[{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"1. Sarah Bradford Hopkins wrote two biographies of this historical figure, who used the profits from Hopkins’ books to establish a retirement home in Auburn, New York. This person guided James Montgomery’s forces in the raid on Combahee Ferry and served Robert Gould Shaw his last meal. In 2016, it was announced that this historical figure will replace Andrew Jackson on the twenty-dollar bill. This activist recruited residents of Chatham, Ontario for John Brown’s raid on Harper’s Ferry, but declined to participate herself. For 10 points, name this abolitionist, nicknamed “Moses,” known for guiding escaped slaves on the Underground Railroad. ","answer":"ANSWER: Harriet Tubman [or Araminta Ross] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"2. A novel by this author ends with the protagonist’s nephew Russell opening the “yellow, unprepossessing door” of the Bethel Independent Mission. The chauffeur Sparser runs over a little girl while the protagonist of that novel by this author is canoodling in the backseat with Hortense Briggs. A character created by this author leaves his job as a bellhop to work at a factory in Lycurgus, New York, where he meets a woman he later kills by smashing a camera on her head. Roberta Alden appears in this author’s novel about Clyde Griffiths. For 10 points, name this author of An American Tragedy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Theodore Dreiser "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"3. The Dirac equation modifies the Schrödinger equation to account for the results of this theory. A prediction of this theory was tested by measuring the relativistic decay of muons in the Rossi–Hall experiment. This theory involves rotations and boosts that make up the Lorentz transformations between inertial reference frames. The foundation of this theory was laid in the year of the Annus Mirabilis by the paper “On the Electrodynamics of Moving Bodies.” This theory, which involves length contraction and time dilation, predicts mass-energy equivalence through “E = mc squared.” For 10 points, name this theory formulated by Einstein, which is contrasted with its “general” counterpart. ","answer":"ANSWER: special theory of relativity [or SR; or time dilation until it is read; prompt on (theory of) relativity; do not accept or prompt on “general relativity”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"4. An opera by this composer begins with Fortune and Virtue arguing about who has more power over mankind. The words “Lasciatemi morire” are repeated over and over again in a lost opera by this composer. This coiner of the term seconda pratica wrote the aria “Possente spirto,” and composed a cantata that features the earliest known orchestral use of string tremolo and pizzicato. This composer of L’Arianna wrote an opera whose title character schemes with Ottone to overthrow Nero. This man composed the earliest surviving opera that is still performed. For 10 points, name this composer of The Coronation of Poppea and L’Orfeo. ","answer":"ANSWER: Claudio (Giovanni Antonio) Monteverdi "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"5. In order to become the morning star, a god from this myth system slept with his sister and burned himself in a fire. After playing a conch-shell trumpet and circling his kingdom four times, a god in this myth system created humanity by mixing bones with blood. This system’s war god uses a turquoise snake as a weapon and is usually depicted as a hummingbird. Child sacrifices were performed to appease this myth system’s rain god Tlaloc. This myth system’s wind god took the form of a plumed serpent and was worshipped in the city of Tlatelolco [“tlah-teh-LOHL-ko”]. For 10 points, name this myth system whose god Quetzalcoatl was worshipped by priests in Tenochtitlan [“ten-OCH-teet-LAHN”]. ","answer":"ANSWER: Aztec mythology "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"6. One of this author’s characters visits San Francisco to see the preserved head of a man she believes to be her former lover, Joaquin [wa-KEEN] Andieta. Another character created by this author is the daughter of a snakebitten gardener and a servant who chokes to death on a chicken bone. This author of Daughter of Fortune wrote about the prostitute Transito Soto, who saves the life of Pedro Tercero. Poisoned brandy accidentally kills the green-haired Rosa in this author’s novel about the Trueba [“troo-AY-bah”] family. For 10 points, name this Chilean author of Eva Luna and The House of the Spirits. ","answer":"ANSWER: Isabel Allende "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"7. A politician with this surname resigned as Conservative Party leader as a result of the Carlton Club Meeting. As Colonial Secretary, a politician with this surname offered to resettle Jews in Uganda. A politician with this surname was told “in the name of God, go!” by Leo Amery during the Norway Debate. The Locarno Pact was negotiated by a diplomat with this surname whose brother succeeded Stanley Baldwin as Prime Minister. That Prime Minister of this surname declared “peace in our time” after allowing the annexation of the Sudetenland at the 1938 Munich Conference. For 10 points, give this surname of the Prime Minister who was replaced by Winston Churchill. ","answer":"ANSWER: Chamberlain family [or Neville Chamberlain; or Austen Chamberlain; or Joseph Chamberlain] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"8. A form of “tribalism” called asabiyyah is discussed in Ibn Khaldun's Muqaddimah, an early text taking a “universal” approach to this discipline. Hegel claimed “the Owl of Minerva” flew only in the aftermath of this concept, which he attributed to the weltgeist, or “world spirit,” in a series of lectures that claim Africa does not possess this concept. Giambattista Vico discussed the cyclical nature of this concept in his The New Science. Thomas Carlyle popularized the “great man” theory of this discipline. Echoing Hegel, Karl Marx claimed this thing “repeats itself, first as tragedy, then as farce.” For 10 points, name this field whose early practitioners included Thucydides and Herodotus. ","answer":"ANSWER: history [accept historiography] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"9. One type of these molecules associates with DGCR8 and the Drosha complex to form a stem-loop structure. This type of molecule is cleaved with the help of the protein Argonaute and the RISC [RISK] complex, which are activated by the enzyme Dicer to modulate gene expression. Another class of these molecules has a cloverleaf-shaped secondary structure and carries specific amino acids to the ribosome during elongation. According to a well-known form of the central dogma of molecular biology, this macromolecule serves as the intermediate. For 10 points, “small interfering” and “transfer” are examples of what type of nucleic acid? ","answer":"ANSWER: RNA [or ribonucleic acid; or mRNA; or miRNA; or tRNA] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"0. Rescorla and Wagner proposed an equation to measure the strength of this process, and described how it can be inhibited through the “blocking effect.” The Garcia effect involves taste aversion produced by this process. Extinction refers to the failure of this process, which can be reverted through spontaneous recovery. To study this process, one man invented the cumulative recorder and a namesake box, inspired by Edward Thorndike. The first experiment studying this process used it to make dogs salivate at the ring of a bell. For 10 points, what form of learning central to behavioral psychology comes in classical and operant varieties? ","answer":"ANSWER: conditioning [accept classical conditioning or operant conditioning; prompt on learning] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"1. During this war, black volunteers joined zouavo [“zoo-AH-vo”] units to escape slavery. In thanks for his arbitration of a lingering border dispute after this war, one countrynamed a province after Rutherford Hayes. Six ironclads snuck past the river fortress Humaitá [“oo-my-TA”] in this war, allowing the Duke of Caxias [“cah-SHEE-us”] to capture a capital. After the Battle of Cerro Cora, the losing side’s president was executed in front of his mistress Eliza Lynch. This war began with the invasion of Mato Grosso, ordered by Francisco Solano López. This war killed half of Paraguay’s population. For 10 points, name this South American war won by a coalition of Argentina, Brazil, and Uruguay. ","answer":"ANSWER: War of the Triple Alliance [or Paraguayan War until “Paraguay” is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"2. How Doth the Little Crocodile was painted by a British artist from this movement who lived most of her life in Mexico named Leonora Carrington. It’s not futurism, but an artist from this movement painted in the pittura metafisica style and often depicted mannequins, empty urban spaces, and trains. A man looks at the back of his head in a mirror in Not to Be Reproduced, a work by a member of this movement who also painted a train emerging from a fireplace. In The Treachery of Images, that artist from this movement depicted a pipe above the statement “this is not a pipe.” For 10 points, name this movement of Giorgio di Chirico and René Magritte, whose works were inspired by dreams. ","answer":"ANSWER: surrealism [or surrealist; accept Leonora Carrington until “this movement” is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"4. ","answer":"ANSWER: Eastern Orthodoxy [or Russian Orthodoxy; or Greek Orthodoxy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"4. The presence of neutral hydrogen in the intergalactic medium may cause the emission spectra of these objects to exhibit Gunn-Peterson troughs rather than the typical Lyman-alpha forests. Maarten Schmidt measured distances to these objects, whose extreme redshift helped refute the “steady state” theory of the universe. These active galactic nuclei are thought to be powered by the accretion of gaseous material into supermassive black holes, leading to massive releases of electromagnetic radiation. For 10 points, name these highly luminous and distant objects whose name is a contraction of “quasi-stellar radio source”. ","answer":"ANSWER: quasars [accept quasi-stellar radio sources before mention; prompt on active galactic nucleic or AGNs until it is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"5. This character blesses some snakes that “coiled” with “a flash of golden light.” While experiencing a vision of two spirit voices, this character learns that he “hath penance done / and penance more will do.” This character, who has a “long grey beard” and “glittering eye,” recounts how Death and Life-in-Death played a game of dice for his soul. In a poem narrated by the Wedding-Guest, this character brings himself bad luck by shooting an albatross, causing him to lament “water, water everywhere / and not a drop to drink.” For 10 points, name this title character of a Rime by Samuel Taylor Coleridge. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Ancient Mariner [accept The Rime of the Ancient Mariner] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"6. Description acceptable. One of these events involved the death of a man who had participated in Operation Balak by sanctioning arms shipments to the Haganah. The first of these events allegedly induced a fatal heart attack in King Wenceslaus IV, leading to the breakout of the Hussite Wars. Count von Thurn led one of these events against a victim who was later granted the title Baron of Highfall. Protestant pamphleteers countered assertions of divine intervention by claiming that the Catholic victims of the second of these events had landed in a dung heap. For 10 points, the Thirty Years’ War was sparked by what act of throwing people from a window in a Czech city? ","answer":"ANSWER: Defenestrations of Prague [or Second Defenestration of Prague; or Third Defenestration of Prague; accept equivalents that including being thrown out of a window in Prague until the giveaway is read; prompt on defenestrations by asking “in what city?”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"7. The Texas Declaration of Independence was signed in a town named for this man located on the Brazos River. A mountain named for this man can be ascended via the Crawford Path, and has the highest recorded wind speed in America. This man is the namesake of a bridge that links Manhattan to Fort Lee, New Jersey, that was closed by Chris Christie during “Bridgegate.” A mountain named for this man is the tallest peak of the White Mountains and the highest point in New Hampshire. His is the leftmost face carved into Mount Rushmore. For 10 points, identify this president, the namesake of a state whose largest city is Seattle. ","answer":"ANSWER: George Washington [or Washington-on-the-Brazos] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"9. An architect from this European country was inspired by Buckminster Fuller to design two giant geodesic biomes housing a variety of plants for his Eden Project. An architect from this country freed up the floor space of a Hong Kong bank by supporting its exterior with eight steel masts. That architect from this country designed the five billion dollar Apple Park and added a glass dome to the Reichstag. Renzo Piano designed an extremely tall tapering building called the Shard in this country, which is also home to a building called “the Gherkin.” For 10 points, name this home country of architects Norman Foster and Christopher Wren. ","answer":"ANSWER: England [or Great Britain; or United Kingdom; or U.K] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"0. A character in this play contrasts his “sole reality” with a “game of art” after a machinist accidentally lets down a curtain. After predicting the end of this play, one man describes how the “Demon of Experiment” hides within him. A woman in this play wishes to be called “Amalia,” although she is primarily referred to as “the Mother.” Father attempts to construct a shop by hanging up the actresses’ hats in this play, which causes Madame Pace to appear. This play begins with actors rehearsing the second act of Mixing It Up. For 10 points, name this play in which the Manager loses “a whole day” of rehearsals because of the title intrusive family, by Luigi Pirandello. ","answer":"ANSWER: Six Characters in Search of an Author [or Sei personaggi in cerca d’autore] Tiebreaker. A common method for designing these devices is a graph with two operating lines, an equilibrium line, and a series of stair-steps from the bottoms to the overheads. The output of a catalytic cracker is usually fed directly into one of these pieces of equipment. These devices are operated at -300 degrees Fahrenheit to do cryogenic separation of oxygen from nitrogen. Refluxing liquid drains downward through these devices to enhance the purity of streams coming out of them. Kerosene is one of the “fractions” coming off these devices when they’re used to refine petroleum. For 10 points, name these columns that separate liquids by their boiling points. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this remnant radiation that provides strong support for the Big Bang theory. It is measured through satellites such as DASI [das-see] and WMAP [“double u MAP”]. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cosmic Microwave Background Radiation [or CMBR] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] The temperature of the CMBR is inversely proportional to this quantity, a measurement of the relative expansion of the universe. This dimensionless quantity is symbolized a and is invoked in the Friedmann equations. ","answer":"ANSWER: cosmic scale factor [or Robertson–Walker scale factor] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] The CMBR was discovered with a telescope sensitive to microwaves in this lowest-energy region of the electromagnetic spectrum. Karl Jansky pioneered the study of radiation in this region of the spectrum. ","answer":"ANSWER: radio waves "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"2. A character named after this author engages in a debate over the theology of laughter with William of Baskerville in Umberto Eco’s The Name of the Rose. For 10 points each: [10 Name this South American author of “The Garden of Forking Paths.” Like the antagonist of Eco’s novel, this real-life author was blind and obsessed with labyrinths. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jorge Luis Borges "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Eco modeled William of Baskerville after this Arthur Conan Doyle-created detective, whose relationship with John Watson resembles the dynamic between William and Adso of Melk in Eco’s novel. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sherlock Holmes [accept either underlined portion] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] A retired beekeeper heavily implied to be Sherlock Holmes helps a Jewish refugee find a lost parrot in this man’s novel The Final Solution. This author won the Pulitzer Prize for a novel in which two Jewish boys create The Escapist. ","answer":"ANSWER: Michael Chabon (Chabon won a Pulitzer for The Amazing Adventures of Kavalier and Clay) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this ballet by Sergei Prokofiev. It includes a “Dance of the Knights” that Prokofiev later used in the Montagues and Capulets section of his Suite No. 2, titled after the feuding families in this ballet’s source material. ","answer":"ANSWER: Romeo and Juliet "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] The work of Shakespeare also inspired a Frederick Ashton ballet titled for one of these events. In musical theatre, atmospheric sections focused on dancing are known as this sort of “ballet,” popularized by Agnes de Mille’s choreography for Oklahoma! ","answer":"ANSWER: dreams [or The Dream; or dream ballet] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Christopher Wheeldon, the choreographer of an adaptation of Shakespeare’s Winter’s Tale, is noted for his collaborations with this Moscow-based ballet company. With the Mariinsky Ballet, this company is considered the most prestigious in Russia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bolshoi Ballet "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this sport played by Aaron Hernandez and Junior Seau, both of whom may have committed suicide due to the symptoms of CTE. ","answer":"ANSWER: American football "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] In 2009, this current commissioner of the NFL issued a rule change forcing teams to bench players who showed signs of head injuries. ","answer":"ANSWER: Roger Goodell "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This current Washington State head coach was fired by Texas Tech after he locked a concussed player in an equipment closet. He popularized the Air Raid offense during his time at Texas Tech. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mike Leach "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this condition that, like castration, was commonly inflicted on political prisoners in the Byzantine court. The Diadochid ruler Antigonus the One-Eyed partially suffered from this condition. ","answer":"ANSWER: blindness [accept equivalents] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] During this campaign, the blind Venetian doge Enrico Dandolo helped Isaac’s son overthrow Alexios. The participants in this crusade never made it to the Holy Land, but ended up sacking the Byzantine capital instead. ","answer":"ANSWER: Fourth Crusade [prompt on the Crusades] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] An army of these people had 199 out of every 200 eyes removed after they were defeated by the Byzantines at the Battle of Kleidion. This ethnic group was subjugated by the Byzantine emperor Basil II. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bulgars [or Bulgarians] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this populist leader of the National Regeneration Movement. He defeated Ricardo Anaya in a July 2018 presidential election. ","answer":"ANSWER: Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador [or AMLO; prompt on partial answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Lopez Obrador is the president-elect of this country. With the United States and Canada, this country is party to the recently renegotiated NAFTA treaty. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mexico "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Obrador campaigned on a promise to reform this state-owned Mexican oil company, which Obrador’s predecessor, Enrique Peña Nieto, attempted to privatize. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pemex [or Petroleos Mexicanos] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name these optically inactive mixtures made of equal amounts of both types of a substance’s enantiomers. ","answer":"ANSWER: racemic mixtures [or racemates] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This scientist discovered the first racemic mixture, named racemic acid, and resolved it into enantiomers of tartaric acid. This Frenchman also names a process of sterilizing milk by heating it. ","answer":"ANSWER: Louis Pasteur "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Resolution of enantiomers from racemic mixtures is commonly done through first converting the enantiomers to these types of isomers. These stereoisomers differ in at least one, but not all, of their stereocenters. ","answer":"ANSWER: diastereomers [or diastereoisomers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this “great” emperor who won the Second Battle of Panipat three decades after his grandfather Babur won a battle at the same location. He founded a new capital for his empire at Fatehpur Sikir ","answer":"ANSWER: Akbar the Great [or Akbar I] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Akbar led this Indian empire, whose emperor Shah Jahan built the Red Fort and the Taj Mahal. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mughal Empire "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] While Akbar combined Islamic beliefs with Hindu practices, this sixth Mughal emperor reinstated the jizya tax on non-Muslims and executed the Sikh Guru Bahadur. He was given the title Alamgir, meaning “world-seizer.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Aurangzeb [or Aurangzeb Alamgir] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This huntress was the first person to wound the boar, for which she was awarded its hide. Later, this woman was forced to marry Hippomenes after he beat her in a footrace with the help of some distracting golden apples. ","answer":"ANSWER: Atalanta "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This lover of Atalanta killed the Calydonian boar. The Fates predicted that this man would only live as long as a piece of wood; this man died when his mother, Althaea, set the piece of wood on fire. ","answer":"ANSWER: Meleager "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Meleager was the son of Althaea and this man. Artemis sent the boar to attack this Calydonian king after he forgot to honor Artemis at his harvest sacrifices. ","answer":"ANSWER: King Oeneus "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this novel about the romances and life of Eatonville resident Janie Crawford. The events of this novel are narrated by Janie to Phoeby Watson as they sit on her back porch. ","answer":"ANSWER: Their Eyes Were Watching God "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] In Their Eyes Were Watching God, the changes undergone by this plant symbolize Janie’s awakening sexuality. This plant’s appearance changes from the “snowy virginity of bloom” to an “ecstatic shiver...creaming in every blossom.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the pear tree [prompt on partial answer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This Floridian wrote Their Eyes Were Watching God. Delia Jones watches her cruel husband Sykes die of a snakebite on his neck in this writer’s short story “Sweat.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Zora Neale Hurston "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this Classical era composer of Night Music of the Streets of Madrid. He wrote a String Quintet in E major that is known for its “Celebrated Minuet.” ","answer":"ANSWER: (Ridolfo) Luigi Boccherini "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Grützmacher wrote the best known arrangement of Boccherini’s concerto for this instrument. Boccherini himself played this instrument, whose historical virtuosos include Jacqueline du Pré and Mstislav Rostropovich. ","answer":"ANSWER: cello "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This other classical composer wrote two cello concertos in C major and D major. This “father of the symphony” wrote 106 symphonies, including ones titled Farewell and Surprise. ","answer":"ANSWER: (Franz) Joseph Haydn "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this country whose feudal lords united under the general Skanderbeg to preserve this country’s independence. Later, this country was proclaimed “the world’s first atheist state” by its dictator Enver Hoxha [en-VAIR HOE-jah]. ","answer":"ANSWER: Albania "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] As a child, Skanderbeg was recruited by the Devshirme [“dev-SHUR-may”], or “blood tax,” to fill the ranks of the Janissaries, the slave soldiers of this Muslim empire from which he defected. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ottoman Empire "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Albanian nationalists revere a flag, first hoisted by Skanderbeg, depicting one of these animals. At the 2018 World Cup, Granit Xhaka and Xherdan Shaqiri [jer-DAN shah-KEE-ree] were fined for making this animal’s symbol with their hands. ","answer":"ANSWER: double-headed eagle "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this Mexican author of Christopher Unborn. A fictionalized version of Ambrose Bierce goes to Mexico to die in this author’s novel The Old Gringo. ","answer":"ANSWER: Carlos Fuentes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Christopher Columbus marvels at “kingdoms naked in the trembling heart” in “Ave Maria,” a poem by an author with this surname. A different author with this last name wrote The Red Badge of Courage. ","answer":"ANSWER: Crane [accept Hart Crane; accept Stephen Crane] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] The title character of this author’s novel Annie John writes on a picture of Christopher Columbus, upsetting Miss Edward. A woman leaves the West Indies to be an au pair in this author’s novel Lucy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jamaica Kincaid "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this taxonomic classification that is more specific than a genus. ","answer":"ANSWER: species [or speciation] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Sympatric speciation is distinguished from this other form of speciation, which occurs when two populations are geographically isolated from each other. ","answer":"ANSWER: allopatric speciation "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This German-born biologist discussed the “biological species concept,” which defines a species in terms of reproductive compatibility, in his 1942 book Systematics and the Origin of Species. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ernst Mayr "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this “accuser” who pressures God into testing Job’s faith. This “prince of darkness” is sometimes conflated with the talking serpent that tempted Eve in the Garden of Eden. ","answer":"ANSWER: Satan [or the Devil] [10] “Greater” and “lesser” forms of magic are practiced by the Church of Satan founded by this person. This author of the largely plagiarized Satanic Bible cultivated Satanism’s public image by shaving his head, wearing capes, and maintaining a black goatee. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This gnostic religion emphasized the struggle between good and evil, sometimes simplified to a struggle between God and Satan. St. Augustine followed this religion as a young man, but later denounced it as a heresy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Manichaeism "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this concept whose “actual” and “potential” forms were distinguished by Aristotle. Many of Zeno’s paradoxes are concerned with this mathematical concept, that Anaximander referred to as apeiron, or “boundless.” ","answer":"ANSWER: infinite [or infinity] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] In his magnum-opus Totality and Infinity, Emmanuel Levinas claimed that ethics arise from our face-to-face encounters with this concept. In The Second Sex, Simone de Beauvoir claimed that women were part of this group, contrasted with the Self. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Other "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] A philosopher with this surname documented our philosophical understanding of infinity in his 1990 book The Infinite. Another British philosopher with this surname suggested “good” cannot be defined as part of his naturalistic fallacy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Moore [or A. W. Moore; or G. E. Moore] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Spheres and polyhedra can be defined as sets of points in this type of metric space named for a Greek mathematician who wrote the Elements. ","answer":"ANSWER: three-dimensional Euclidean space [prompt on Euclid] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] For this type of set, every point has a neighborhood that also lies in the set. For example, a disk that does not contain its boundary points is this type of set. ","answer":"ANSWER: open set "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] According to a theorem that this mathematician co-names with Bernard Bolzano, every bounded infinite set in R n has an accumulation point--in other words, every bounded sequence has a convergent subsequence. ","answer":"ANSWER: Karl Weierstrass [accept Bolzano-Weierstrass theorem] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this legendary outlaw of the American West who was killed by Pat Garrett. This one-time cattle rustler was nicknamed for his youthful appearance. ","answer":"ANSWER: Billy the Kid [or William Bonney] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Billy the Kid died in this state. This state’s city of Santa Fe is one of the oldest continuously inhabited cities in the United States. ","answer":"ANSWER: New Mexico "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Billy the Kid’s killing was ordered by this governor who, as a Union general, infamously marched his division down the wrong road at the Battle of Shiloh. He also wrote Ben-Hur. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lew Wallace "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this sort of creature. In another story by the same author, one of these creatures named Josephine is worshipped for her ability to sing. ","answer":"ANSWER: mouse [or mice] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This author of “A Little Fable” and “Josephine the Singer” often featured non-human protagonists in his works, such as the “horrible vermin” that Gregor Samsa transforms into in his novella The Metamorphosis. ","answer":"ANSWER: Franz Kafka "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] In Kafka’s story “Investigations of a Dog,” the title character faints in his own blood after choosing to do this. In another Kafka story, a panther replaces an “artist” who excels at performing this action after he loses popularity. ","answer":"ANSWER: fasting [or hunger; accept equivalent descriptive answers like not eating] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This artist’s block-shaped sculpture Kiss is a famous example of direct carving. He sculpted the Endless Column and The Table of Silence for a World War I memorial in his hometown, Târgu Jiu. ","answer":"ANSWER: Constantin Brâncuși [bran-COOSH] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] William Zorach, a sculptor known for his use of direct carving, was a member of this artistic movement. Guitar and Bust of a Woman were sculpted by this movement’s founder Pablo Picasso. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cubism [or word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Description acceptable. Barbara Hepworth and Henry Moore, who pioneered direct carving in the United Kingdom, often created smooth, curving sculptures with this sort of feature, to which Hepworth often added string. ","answer":"ANSWER: a hole [or negative space; accept equivalents] Tiebreaker. A poet from this country mourned her love Romelio Ureta in her Sonnets of Death. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this home country of Gabriela Mistral. Another poet from this country observes “the night is shattered and the blue stars shiver in the distance” in a poem that begins “tonight I can write the saddest lines.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Chile "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This Chilean poet wrote “Tonight I Can Write the Saddest Lines.” In his collection Twenty Love Poems and a Song of Despair, this poet laments an impending “hour of departure.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Pablo Neruda "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] In “The Heights of Macchu Picchu,” Neruda asks the land to give him “struggle,” “iron,” and these things. One of these geographical features appears in the title of a novel about the alcoholic British diplomat Geoffrey Firmin set on the Day of the Dead. ","answer":"ANSWER: volcanos [or Under the Volcano] (Under the Volcano was written by Malcolm Lowry) EXTRA Answer the following about functional programming, for 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] To be Turing-complete, functional programming relies on this practice in which something is defined in terms of itself, which is contrasted with iteration. It may involve a function calling itself. ","answer":"ANSWER: recursion [or word forms like recursing or recursive function] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Functional programming implements this formal system of logic invented by Alonzo Church. Encodings of lists in this system influenced John McCarthy to develop the language Lisp. ","answer":"ANSWER: lambda calculus [do not accept or prompt on “calculus” alone] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] This programming feature, in which a function has the same body but has the ability to operate on several different data types, is used extensively in functional programming. ","answer":"ANSWER: polymorphism [or word forms; or parametric polymorphism] Some architects claimed that the choice of this material for one project was “too feminine” and questioned the way it sharply tapered. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Name this material used for a fountain in Montgomery’s Civil Rights Memorial inscribed with the names of 41 activists. Another memorial consists of this material structured in a V shape, inscribed with over fifty-eight thousand names. ","answer":"ANSWER: black granite "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] The Civil Rights Memorial was designed by this architect, who won the commission to design Washington D.C’s Vietnam War Memorial at the age of twenty-one. ","answer":"ANSWER: Maya Lin "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"A","question":"[10] Maya Lin’s sculpture The Women’s Table depicts a spiral of increasing numbers to commemorate the female enrollment at this U.S. university, her alma mater. ","answer":"ANSWER: Yale University"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"1. At the end of Raging Bull, Robert de Niro recites one of this actor’s monologues into a mirror. He’s not James Dean, but this student of Stella Adler was the first notable Hollywood actor to employ Stanislavski’s [stan-uh-SLAWV-skee’s] “method acting.” This actor played a character who overturns a basket of oranges when he is shot by Tattaglia hitmen; that character played by this man advises his son, Michael, to “keep your friends close [and] your enemies closer.” In an Elia Kazan film about corrupt dockworkers, this actor laments “I coulda had class. I coulda been a contender.” For 10 points, what star of On the Waterfront portrayed mob boss Vito Corleone in The Godfather? ","answer":"ANSWER: Marlon Brando "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"2. Abnormal clusters of DNA in these cells called Howell-Jolly bodies may develop during hereditary spherocytosis. Deficiency of these cells is common in a disease whose name is derived from its prevalence among Mediterraneans. Another disease affecting these cells results from a glutamine-to-valine mutation at position 6 of a protein’s beta chain. They take on an abnormal shape in a disease that confers resistance against malaria due to heterozygote advantage. The number of these cells in the body is lowered in thalassemias and sickle-cell anemia. For 10 points, name these cells that deliver oxygen to body tissues with the help of hemoglobin. ","answer":"ANSWER: red blood cells [or erythrocytes; or RBCs] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"3. A sexually explicit example of this literary form describes “dirty farts...spluttering” out of Nora Barnacle’s backside. A work of this type by John Keats compliments Shakespeare’s ability to cope with uncertainty, which Keats dubbed “negative capability.” Sylvia Plath’s suicide is explored in a Ted Hughes collection named for this literary form. In a novella, Wormwood learns how to corrupt the Patient through works of this type. While on an Arctic expedition, Robert Walton writes some of these works in Mary Shelley’s Frankenstein. For 10 points, name these correspondences that are imitated by the narration of epistolary novels. ","answer":"ANSWER: letters [or epistles; accept Birthday Letters or The Screwtape Letters] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"4. This empire authorized Jan Janszoon [“YAWN YAWN-sohn”] and the Salé Rovers to conduct a series of slave raids in Iceland, known as this empire’s namesake “abductions.” Supposed evidence for pre-modern Antarctic exploration exists on a map by one of this empire’s admirals, Piri Reis. This empire’s admiral Dragut died at the Great Siege of Malta and served at the Battle of Preveza, where Andrea Doria retreated from a fleet led by this empire’s admiral Hayreddin Barbarossa. The Age of Sail began after this country’s galley fleet was routed by the combined forces of Venice and Don Juan of Austria at the Battle of Lepanto. For 10 points, name this empire ruled by Suleiman the Magnificent. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ottoman Empire [accept Turkey or Turkish Abductions] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"5. This deity declares that no giant is equal to Vafthrudnir [voff-THRUD-near] and counsels another deity against visiting him. This deity protects certain people from danger by sending them to the servant Hlín. This deity’s messenger has a flying sea-treading horse whose name means “hoof-tosser,” or Hófvarpnir [hoff-VARP-near]. This deity’s servants include Gná [NAH] and Fulla. In the Lokasenna, Loki accuses this deity of sleeping with Vili and Ve. Freya is second only to this goddess, who is known as the highest among the Aesir. This goddess weeps at her hall Fensalir after the death of her son Baldr. For 10 points, name this Norse goddess and wife of Odin. ","answer":"ANSWER: Frigga [or Frija; do not accept or prompt on Freya] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"6. This sculpture inspired the pose of the central figure in Abbott Thayer’s A Virgin. Filippo Marinetti’s Futurist Manifesto declares that “a racing automobile … is more beautiful than [this sculpture].” This sculpture originally overlooked the Temple of the Great Gods, where it was elevated by a marble pedestal representing a ship’s prow. It was found and reassembled under the lead of archaeologist Charles Champoiseau [“shawm-pwah-SOH”]. This statue, located atop the Daru Staircase within the Louvre, features clothing ruffled by wind and is missing its arms and head. For 10 points, name this Hellenistic-era sculpture depicting the goddess Nike. ","answer":"ANSWER: Winged Victory of Samothrace [or Winged Nike of Samothrace or Winged Victory of Samothrace or Winged Nike of Samothrace; prompt on partial answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"7. After a city in this state voted for a 2014 referendum banning fracking within city limits, its legislature passed a law forbidding cities from making such bans. Although T. Boone Pickens’ scheme to build the world’s largest wind farm in this state failed, as of 2018 it produces the most wind power of any US state. This state’s Railroad Commission is unusually powerful because it regulates the energy industry, rather than railroads. The oil-rich Permian Basin is in this state, which is the southern terminus of the Keystone XL pipeline. This state’s oil industry is centered in the Midland-Odessa metropolitan area. For 10 points, name this state where many oil companies are headquartered in Houston. ","answer":"ANSWER: Texas "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"8. This man made a speech nominating Jerry Brown for president at the 1976 Democratic National Convention. Philip Vera Cruz resigned from this man’s organization after he endorsed Ferdinand Marcos. This man’s brother Richard designed a black eagle logo for his organization. Protesting a preferential contract negotiated with the Teamsters, this activist was jailed for violating an antiboycott injunction during the Salad Bowl strike. This activist joined Filipino workers in the Delano grape strike and fought to end the Bracero Program alongside Dolores Huerta. For 10 points, name this Mexican-American labor activist who led the United Farm Workers. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cesar Chavez "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"1. In specular reflection, a line named for this word is at equal angles to both the incident and reflected rays. The force of friction is proportional to the coefficient of friction times a force described by this adjective. For 10 points, name this word which denotes the force perpendicular to a surface. ","answer":"ANSWER: normal [or normalization] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"0. A poem written in this language contrasts the “golden hair” of Margarete [“mar-guh-RET-uh”] with the “ashen hair” of Shulamith, and begins by describing the “black milk of daybreak we drink at nightfall.” A collection written in this language includes a poem inspired by Picasso’s Family of Saltimbanques, and another that declares “beauty is nothing but the beginning of terror.” Paul Celan’s “Death Fugue” was written in this language, as was a poem that ends “You must change your life.” An Italian castle inspired a set of 10 mystical poems in this language that opens “Who, if I cried out, would hear me among the Angelic Orders?” For 10 points, what language was used for the Duino Elegies by Austrian poet Rainer Maria Rilke? ","answer":"ANSWER: German [or Deutsch] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"1. Talcott Parsons’ analysis of the division of labor distinguished between the “instrumental” and “expressive” based on this concept. A 1987 paper by Candace West and Don Zimmerman popularized the phrase “doing [this concept].” The “ritual of subordination” is discussed in an Erving Goffman book analyzing how advertisements affect our view of this concept. A 1990 book considers J. L. Austin’s theory of “performative utterances” to argue for this concept’s “performativity.” That book by Judith Butler is titled for its Trouble. Sociologists often discuss the “binary” this concept is confined to in most Western societies. For 10 points, what social construct is often contrasted with sex? ","answer":"ANSWER: gender [do not accept or prompt on “sex”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"2. Conspiracies theories arose after this nation signed the Tashkent Declaration with a prime minister who died the next day. A leader of this country vowed to “eat grass” until his country acquired nuclear weapons. In 2004, this country’s top nuclear physicist was revealed to have smuggled uranium to Libya and North Korea. This country began enriching uranium in response to a neighboring country’s Smiling Buddha test. Separated from its eastern neighbor by the Line of Control, this country’s nuclear program was started by A. Q. Khan on the orders of prime minister Zulfikar Ali Bhutto. For 10 points, identify this country that contests the rule of Kashmir with the nation it was partitioned from, India. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pakistan "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"3. At the beginning of this novel, Mary Debenham mysteriously tells a colonel “Not now. When it’s all over.” In this book, Cyrus B. Hardman is frustrated that he can’t find a “small, dark man with a womanish voice.” A man in this novel learns that many women’s dressing gowns are “corn coloured” and “blue satin,” but fails to find a “scarlet kimono.” The protagonist of this novel discovers that Samuel Ratchett is actually Cassetti, who fled America after kidnapping Daisy Armstrong; later, the protagonist deduces that Cassetti was stabbed to death by his fellow passengers. For 10 points, Hercule Poirot investigates a crime aboard a train in what Agatha Christie novel? ","answer":"ANSWER: Murder on the Orient Express "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"4. Heinz Hopf conjectured that this figure is homeomorphic to any simply connected manifold with pinched sectional curvature. Grigori Perelman proved a statement concerning the 4-dimensional variant of this figure; that statement is named for Henri Poincaré. The Kepler conjecture gives 0.74 as the maximum density with which this figure can pack a volume. Coordinates symbolized rho, theta, and phi are used in a system named for this solid figure. For 10 points, the solid that gives the largest surface area for a given volume is what shape, whose surface area is “4 pi r squared”? ","answer":"ANSWER: sphere "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"5. This philosopher’s atomism was defended by a later thinker’s idea of the “swerve,” which holds that atoms can divert from their innate downwards path. In a letter to Herodotus, this philosopher argued that death is not to be feared. A trilemma attributed to this man is arguably the first version of the problem of evil. This philosopher believed that the highest form of happiness is the combination of tranquility and the absence of pain, or aponia and ataraxia. Lucretius’ De Rerum Natura defended the beliefs of this man who taught at The Garden. For 10 points, name this Greek philosopher whose namesake school of philosophy is considered to be a form of hedonism. ","answer":"ANSWER: Epicurus [or Epíkouros] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"6. This religion inspired a poem in which a character in “blue work overalls” chants “DROWN THEIR BUTTS/ CRUSH THEIR BUTTS.” That poem titled for Smokey the Bear is by Gary Snyder. In one novel, spiritual experiences like climbing the Matterhorn occur after Japhy Ryder introduces Ray Smith to this religion. A poem inspired by this religion set on “the tincan banana dock” claims that the title object was “never no locomotive!” This religion is central to Beat movement literature like “Sunflower Sutra” and The Dharma Bums. For 10 points, name this religion practiced by Allen Ginsberg and Jack Kerouac in its Mahayana and Zen forms. ","answer":"ANSWER: Buddhism [or Zen Buddhism; or Mahayana Buddhism] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"7. At high pressures, this element could undergo the Wigner-Huntington phase transition to its “metallic” form. Most common solvents in NMR replace nuclei of this element with its rarer isotopes. The kinetic isotope effect is most pronounced in this element, as its isotopes have the largest relative change in mass than do any other element’s. The majority of cosmic rays are nuclei of this element. The predominant isotope of this element is replaced by an uncommon isotope in heavy water. Isotopes of this element, which contain one and two neutrons, respectively, are deuterium and tritium. For 10 points, name this diatomic gas, the lightest element on the periodic table. ","answer":"ANSWER: hydrogen [or H; prompt on deuterium or tritium] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"8. Dorieus, brother of Leonidas, claimed this island’s city of Heraclea Minoa based on his Herculean ancestry. An invasion of this island intended to restore the tyrant Terrilus ended in Hamilcar I’s defeat at the Battle of Himera. This island’s city of Segesta was betrayed by Agathocles, whose son-in-law Pyrrhus of Epirus unsuccessfully besieged Lilybaeum to drive out Carthage. A request by Mamertine mercenaries on this island for an alliance with Rome against Hiero II sparked the First Punic War. Archimedes, who resided on this island, legendarily built a heat ray for its city of Syracuse. For 10 points, name this Mediterranean island, located to the south of mainland Italy ","answer":"ANSWER: Sicily [or Sicilia] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"9. An aria by this composer opens with the notes D and C–sharp, then triplets on C, then B–natural, B–flat, and A. He used a theme based on the carol “March of the Kings” for his incidental music to the play L’Arlesienne [LAHR-less-ee-en]. In an opera by this composer, two characters recall their time together in Kandy in the friendship duet “Au fond du temple saint” [oh fond due TOMP-luh SAHNT”] Another opera by this composer begins outside a cigarette factory, where the title character sings that “love is a rebellious bird” and throws a flower at her love interest. That opera by this composer includes the Toreador Song and the Habanera. For 10 points, name this composer of The Pearl Fishers and Carmen. ","answer":"ANSWER: Georges Bizet "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"0. This country’s Christian church was represented by Dioscorus at the Council of Chalcedon, where this country’s church joined other miaphysite [“MY-uh-fizz-ite”] churches in breaking from the rest of Christianity. A saint from this country is considered the father of Christian monasticism and was tempted by demons while in the wilderness. During a journey back to this country, a Biblical character had his feet touched by his son’s foreskin after it was cut off by his wife, Zipporah. The Israelites are led out of this country to Mount Sinai. For 10 points, name this country where Moses freed the slaves from the Pharaoh. ","answer":"ANSWER: Egypt [or Arab Republic of Egypt] Tiebreaker. It’s not an ethnicity, but the white stripe of the Five Races Under One Union flag signified members of this minority group. The members of the Kansu Braves were part of this minority, as were the leaders of the Ma Clique. A man born into this minority group presented a giraffe to the Yongle Emperor after one of his treasure ship expeditions to the Indian Ocean. The eunuch Zheng He [“ZHUNG HUH”] belonged to this religious minority, and it is the majority religion of Xinjiang [“shin-JYANG”] province. For 10 points, most Uyghurs are members of what religion that was introduced to China by companions of Muhammad? "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this country where, two years later, protests over increased food prices brought Edward Gierek to power. ","answer":"ANSWER: Poland "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Gierek was toppled in 1980, shortly after signing the Gdańsk Agreement, which permitted the creation of this trade union. Under Lech Wałęsa [“LEKH vaw-WES-uh”], this organization led the anti-Communist movement in Poland. ","answer":"ANSWER: Solidarity [or Solidarność] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This Polish Cardinal was elected Pope during Gierek’s rule. John Lewis Gaddis identifies this pontiff’s 1979 visit to Poland as the catalyst for the formation of the Solidarity movement. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pope John Paul II [or Karol Wojtyła [“KEH-rul voy-TAY-wah\"]] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this wind instrument whose players utilize extensive circular breathing. They are often over a meter long, and are traditionally made from wood that has been hollowed out by termites. ","answer":"ANSWER: didgeridoo "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Didgeridoos are often referred to as a “pipe” that produces this sort of sound. Bagpipes also produce this sort of sound sustained for a long period of time. ","answer":"ANSWER: drone [or word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] A long-necked string instrument from this country known as the tanpura is also used to produce a drone. Other instruments invented in this country include the tabla and the sitar. ","answer":"ANSWER: Republic of India "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this man who, in a poem, is said to have “fallen cold and dead” after “the fearful trip is done.” In another poem, he is compared to a “powerful western fallen star” that is “lustrous with silver face in the night.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Abraham Lincoln "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This poet mourned Lincoln’s assassination in the poems “O Captain, my Captain!” and “When Lilacs Last in the Dooryard Bloom’d.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Walt Whitman [or Walter Whitman] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Abraham Lincoln’s son, Willie, lingers in purgatory in this author’s 2017 novel Lincoln in the Bardo. He wrote the short story collections Tenth of December and CivilWarLand in Bad Decline. ","answer":"ANSWER: George Saunders "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this syncretic religion whose name translates to “highest power.” Popes, cardinals, and bishops are ranks in its executive body, and its beliefs are generally a combination of Buddhism, Taoism, and Confucianism. ","answer":"ANSWER: Caodaism [or Đức Cao Đài] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Cao Dai is a religion from this country. This country’s largest basilica was built in Saigon during its time as a French colony. ","answer":"ANSWER: Socialist Republic of Vietnam "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] As in Buddhism, Hinduism, and other Indian religions, a major goal of adherents of Caodaism is freedom from the cyclical pattern of life, death, and suffering referred to by this Sanskrit term. Nirvana is the release from this cycle. ","answer":"ANSWER: saṃsāra [or sansara] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] According to this principle named for a Swiss physicist, an increase in a fluid’s velocity is accompanied by a decrease in its pressure or potential energy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bernoulli’s principle "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] In this low-velocity flow regime, fluids typically do not exhibit chaotic behavior, so parallel fluid layers slide past one another. ","answer":"ANSWER: laminar flow regime "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This “tube” named for a Frenchman is often used to measure the velocity of fluids. It is also used as a speedometer on aircraft. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pitot [pee-TOH] tube [or Pitot probe] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this poet of Amoretti. His most famous work is an allegorical epic poem that represents Queen Elizabeth I as Gloriana. ","answer":"ANSWER: Edmund Spenser (the allegorical epic poem The Faerie Queene) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] The opening of Eliot’s The Waste Land parallels the “General Prologue” of this Geoffrey Chaucer book, which describes April’s “shoures soote” [“showers soot”]. This book’s characters include the Miller, the Franklin, and the Wife of Bath. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Canterbury Tales "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] At the end of The Waste Land, Eliot describes this play’s character Hieronymo becoming “mad againe.” In this Thomas Kyd play, Hieronymo murders Lorenzo and Balthazar to avenge the death of his son. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Spanish Tragedy, or Hieronimo is Mad Again "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this opera based on a Georg Büchner play that opens with the title character shaving his captain. This opera’s protagonist gets revenge on his wife, who is cheating on him with the Drum Major, by stabbing her under a blood moon. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wozzeck "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Wozzeck and the unfinished Lulu are operas by this Austrian composer, a member of the Second Viennese School of composers. This composer’s violin concerto was dedicated “to the memory of an Angel.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Alban Berg [or Alban Maria Johannes Berg] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This other Austrian composer mentored Berg and founded the Second Viennese School. The unfinished opera Moses und Aron was written by this composer of Transfigured Night and Pierrot Lunaire. ","answer":"ANSWER: Arnold Schoenberg [or Arnold Franz Walter Schoenberg] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this political party that was led by the former commandant of Whampoa Academy, Chiang Kai-Shek. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kuomintang [or KMT; or Nationalist Party of China; or Guómíndǎng; or Chinese Nationalists; prompt on “Nationalists” or other partial answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This wife of Chiang Kai-Shek helped negotiate his release after he was captured in the Xi’an [“SHEE-ahn”] Incident. Mao famously quipped that this woman loved power, while her two sisters loved money and China. ","answer":"ANSWER: Soong Mei-Ling "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] After the Kuomintang’s defeat in the Chinese Civil War, Chiang and Soong fled to this island, where they established the Republic of China. ","answer":"ANSWER: Taiwan [or Formosa] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] If you’re predicting a stock’s failure, you can take this position, in which you sell an asset you don’t own and “cover” it later. Michael Lewis described the 2000s housing bubble in a book titled for a Big sale of this sort. ","answer":"ANSWER: short sale "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] One of the most important rules of finance is to always diversify this group of investments or assets you own. ","answer":"ANSWER: your portfolio "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] You might use CAPM, or the Capital Asset Pricing Model, in which this variable is symbolized beta. Harry Markowitz’ modern portfolio theory seeks to find an “efficient frontier” given a certain value for this variable. ","answer":"ANSWER: risk [or volatility] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this French biologist who proposed the theory of inheritance of acquired characteristics. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jean-Baptiste Lamarck "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Lamarck’s theory conflicted with this British scientist’s theory of evolution by natural selection. ","answer":"ANSWER: Charles Robert Darwin "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Lamarck’s views are somewhat consistent with the “transgenerational” form of this phenomenon, in which the traits of one’s offspring are altered without altering any DNA sequences. ","answer":"ANSWER: epigenetics [or transgenerational epigenetics] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this former CEO of CBS who resigned in the wake of a July New Yorker article publicizing the sexual harassment allegations against him. ","answer":"ANSWER: Les Moonves "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] An October 2017 New Yorker exposé revealed the sexual assault allegations against this independent film producer, whose fall from grace initiated the #MeToo movement. ","answer":"ANSWER: Harvey Weinstein "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] The Moonves and Weinstein exposés were written by this journalist, who also wrote about the abuse allegations against New York Attorney General Eric Schneiderman. He has a strained relationship with his father Woody Allen. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ronan Farrow [or Satchel Ronan Farrow] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this novel discussed by Azar Nafisi in a book titled for Reading [it] in Tehran. Nafisi argues that the subject of this book is not the rape of Dolores Haze by “a dirty old man,” but “the confiscation of one individual’s life by another.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Lolita [or Reading Lolita in Tehran] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This other Iranian author described falsely accusing an innocent man of harassment to distract attention from her lipstick in the graphic memoir Persepolis. ","answer":"ANSWER: Marji Satrapi "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Iran’s first female author of the modern era, Simin Daneshvar, wrote about Zari’s fascination with this religion’s martyr Hosein in Savushun. In Persepolis, Satrapi opposes a theocracy guided by this religion’s clerics. ","answer":"ANSWER: Shiite Islam "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this painting whose primary subject stands next to a bowl of oranges. Despite looking directly at the viewer, that subject’s reflection in the mirror behind her is seen to the right as she faces a top-hatted man. ","answer":"ANSWER: A Bar at the Folies-Bergere "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Critics believe the model for the painting, Suzon, also held this profession. T. J. Clark discussed the “Choice” of a scandalous painting in which a person with this profession stares at the viewer as she’s presented a bouquet by a black servant. ","answer":"ANSWER: prostitute [or sex worker; reluctantly accept synonyms like hooker] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This early French Impressionist subverted the male gaze in paintings like A Bar at the Folies-Bergere, the aforementioned Olympia, and Luncheon on the Grass. ","answer":"ANSWER: Édouard Manet "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this technique used in organic chemistry, which starts with a target molecule and breaks it down into precursor materials until simpler molecules are reached. ","answer":"ANSWER: retrosynthetic analysis [or retrosynthesis] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Performing retrosynthesis on this functional group on an aromatic ring can result in carboxylic acids. These functional groups have a C-N triple bond. ","answer":"ANSWER: nitriles [or cyanides] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] One can perform retrosynthesis on amides to yield nitriles, as adding this compound to nitriles results in amides. This compound is removed in a dehydration reaction. ","answer":"ANSWER: water [or H2O] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this country that experienced mostly peaceful relations with the United States until 1941, when its navy attacked Pearl Harbor. ","answer":"ANSWER: Japan "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This American commodore opened Japan to the West by sailing his “Black Ships” to Edo Bay and threatening to fire on the capital. ","answer":"ANSWER: Matthew Perry [prompt on just Perry; do not accept or prompt on Oliver Hazard Perry] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] In 1866, the American steamer General Sherman attempted to emulate Perry’s expedition by visiting this non-Japanese East Asian city; however, the ship was destroyed by this city’s residents. The USS Pueblo was captured off the coast of this capital city, and is still held in this city today. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pyongyang "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this philosopher who attacked Meinong’s conception of a “round square” being both round and not round in a paper that attempted to solve the problem of negative existentials. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bertrand Russell [or Bertrand Arthur William Russell, 3rd Earl Russell] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This Austrian philosopher of language went to Cambridge to study with Russell and, like Russell, discussed the meanings of false propositions in his text Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ludwig Wittgenstein [or Ludwig Josef Johann Wittgenstein] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Russell and Wittgenstein are both associated with this philosophical tradition, which is usually contrasted with the “continental” tradition of mainland European philosophy. ","answer":"ANSWER: analytic philosophy [prompt on Anglo-American philosophy or British philosophy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this process in which cooler water rises to the ocean surface to replace warm water that has been pushed away by wind. ","answer":"ANSWER: upwelling [or coastal upwelling] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] The nutrients in upwelling waters attract large numbers of the “phyto” variety of these ocean-dwelling organisms whose name is Greek for “wanderer.” Most of them are microscopic in size. ","answer":"ANSWER: plankton [or phytoplankton] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] One key driving force of upwelling is this type of fluid transport, in which water moves at right angles to the wind direction due to the Coriolis effect. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ekman transport "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this son of Shaodian and Fubao who defeated the Yan Emperor at the Battle of Banquan. ","answer":"ANSWER: Yellow Emperor [or Huangdi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] The Yellow Emperor is a mythical figure from this country. People from this country are said to be the Yellow Emperor’s descendants. ","answer":"ANSWER: China [or Zhongguo] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] The Yellow Emperor’s court historian, Cang Jie [“tsung JYE”], is known for this invention. Cang Jie, who had four eyes, is said to have invented this thing after observing the footprints of animals on the earth. ","answer":"ANSWER: Chinese writing system [or Written Chinese; or Chinese alphabet; accept word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this profession of Trefon Ivanitch, who lies about his relationship with Alexandra Andreyevna in an Ivan Turgenev story. This is also the profession of a title character who falls in love with Lara after serving in the Russian Civil War. ","answer":"ANSWER: doctors [or A Young Doctor’s Notebook or A Country Doctor’s Notebook or “The District Doctor” or Dr. Zhivago; prompt on poet] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This Russian playwright of Uncle Vanya and The Cherry Orchard was also a practicing physician. ","answer":"ANSWER: Anton Chekhov "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] In this Chekhov story, Anna Sergeyevna visits Moscow on the pretense of seeing a doctor to carry on her affair with Dmitri Gurov, whom she met vacationing in Yalta. ","answer":"ANSWER: “The Lady with the Dog” [or “The Lady with the Lapdog” or “The Lady with the Little Dog”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name these objects in which Viking leaders were often buried. In some instances, these objects were set on fire with corpses inside them in order to help the dead man’s soul reach Valhalla. ","answer":"ANSWER: ships [or boats or longships] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] The most famous archaeological site in Britain is this monument on the Salisbury Plain. This stone circle’s trilithons align with the sunrise and sunset on the solstices. ","answer":"ANSWER: Stonehenge "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] The most famous archaeological site in Ireland, Tara, is located on and named for one of these geographical features. Maiden Castle is a well-preserved example of a type of “fort” named for these geographical features built in Britain during the Iron Age. ","answer":"ANSWER: hills [or Hill of Tara or hillforts] Tiebreaker. This scientist is the director of SNOLAB, which includes a tank of heavy water surrounded by photomultiplier tubes. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this Canadian astrophysicist. He shared the 2015 Nobel Prize in Physics for his discovery of neutrino oscillations. ","answer":"ANSWER: Arthur B. McDonald "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Neutrinos oscillate between this many generations. Both quarks and leptons come in this many generations in the Standard Model. ","answer":"ANSWER: three "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Neutrino oscillations helped to solve a discrepancy in the amount of neutrinos measured coming from this body. Those electron neutrinos are emitted by nuclear fusion that takes place in this star. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Sun [or Sol]"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"1. An artist known as the “Master of the Small” form of this genre was popularized by a series of 44 prints published by Hieronymus Cock. A small Charon crosses the Styx at the center of a work in this genre by Joachim Patinir, who pioneered its “world” variety. Haarlem native Jacob van Ruisdael specialized in these paintings, such as his Jewish Cemetery. 12 works in this genre, one for each month, were created by an artist who also painted one of these works in which a fisherman, a ploughman, and ships ignore a small pair of legs emerging from the water. For 10 points, “the Fall of Icarus” was depicted by Pieter Brueghel in what sort of painting that primarily depicts natural scenery? ","answer":"ANSWER: landscapes [or “Master of the Small Landscapes” or Landscape with the Fall of Icarus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"2. When confronted by robbers, this religious leader declared himself “the herald of the Great King” and was subsequently pushed into a ditch. This man and his first companion opened the Missal three times to seek divine advice; that companion was Bernard of Quintavalle. A church at San Damiano was rebuilt by this man when he misinterpreted divine instructions to “go and repair my church.” A song by this man praises various creations of God, such as Brother Fire and Sister Water, and is titled “Canticle of the Sun.” This man received the stigmata from a six-winged angel and legendarily preached to birds. For 10 points, name this patron saint of animals who lived in Assisi. ","answer":"ANSWER: Saint Francis of Assisi [or Giovanni di Pietro di Bernardone] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"3. This city’s fortress of Sacsayhuamán [“sawk-say-wah-MAHN”] was constructed by the Killke [“KEY-ke”] culture. Conflict over the jurisdiction over this city resulted in the Battle of Las Salinas, after which Diego de Almagro was executed. This city, built in the shape of the sacred puma, had its Coricancha temple stripped of gold in order to pay a ransom for its ruler. After leading resistance from Vilcabamba, Túpac Amaru was executed in this city. During a civil war, Huáscar was captured defending this city from the forces of Atahualpa, who had been imprisoned by Francisco Pizarro. For 10 points, name this capital of the Inca Empire. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cusco [or Cuzco] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"4. At the beginning of one of his books, this author states his desire to invent the path to Galta as he traverses it, to “go to the end.” With Eliot Weinberger, this man analyzed nineteen translations of Tang Dynasty poet Wang Wei. This man wrote a biography of Sor Juana subtitled The Traps of Faith. This author of The Monkey Grammarian wrote about the “poem” and the “poetic revelation” in his Heraclitus-inspired work of criticism, The Bow and the Lyre. In his most famous essay collection, he analyzed the traditions of his home country, including “The Day of the Dead” and “Mexican Masks.” For 10 points, name this Mexican writer of The Labyrinth of Solitude. ","answer":"ANSWER: Octavio Paz "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"5. This scientist's article “Planck’s Law and the Hypothesis of Light Quanta” was translated into German and published in Zeitschrift für Physik. This man is the first namesake of a distribution of indistinguishable particles that is contrasted with Fermi–Dirac statistics. This scientist names particles that are symmetric over particle exchange and only have integer spin. He is the first namesake of a substance that was first produced by Cornell and Wieman by cooling rubidium atoms, in which all the atoms occupy the lowest quantum state. For 10 points, name this Indian theoretical physicist, who, along with Einstein, names a “condensate” phase of matter. ","answer":"ANSWER: Satyendra Nath Bose "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"6. A theorist from this country used the kick-dancing Tiller Girls to illustrate his concept of the “mass ornament.” Two philosophers from this country coined the term “culture industry” and wrote Dialectic of Enlightenment. A philosopher from this country argued that the modern ability to duplicate art causes works to lose their “aura” in an essay on “Art in the Age of Mechanical Reproduction.” A philosopher from this country explained one concept using a term translated as “sublation” and formulated a master-slave dialectic. For 10 points, name this birth country of Theodor Adorno, Walter Benjamin, and G. W. F. Hegel. ","answer":"ANSWER: Federal Republic of Germany [or Bundesrepublik Deutschland] (the “mass ornament” was theorized by Siegfried Kracauer) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"7. In a play set during this holiday, Nora delivers a stillborn baby and her husband Jack Clitheroe is shot. A woman in a poem that takes place during this holiday spent “her nights in argument / until her voice grew shrill,” yet she remains in the same “casual comedy” as a “drunken, vainglorious lout.” The speaker of a poem that occurs during this holiday recounts passing people with “vivid faces” with whom he exchanges “polite meaningless words.” This day, the setting of The Plough and the Stars, names a poem which repeatedly states “a terrible beauty is born.” For 10 points, name this holiday which names a 1916 Irish rebellion immortalized by W.B. Yeats. ","answer":"ANSWER: Easter [accept Easter Rising; or “Easter 1916”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"3. In the second movement of a piece by this composer, a repeated eighth-note quarter-note viola rhythm is marked to be played “always very loud.” This composer of L’estro armonico and two versions of Orlando Furioso wrote a set of pieces that include instructions like “the barking dog” and “the drunkards have fallen asleep;” those concertos are included in The Contest Between Harmony and Invention. For 10 points, name this Italian composer of The Four Seasons. ","answer":"ANSWER: Antonio Vivaldi [or Antonio Lucio Vivaldi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"9. This polity’s air force installed Prince Peter on the throne after his regent, Prince Paul, acceded to the Tripartite Pact. Collaborationist troops attempting to surrender to the British were instead returned to this country in the Bleiburg repatriations. Many war crimes were committed in this country by the pro-Nazi Ustashe [“ooh-STAW-shuh”] militia. The Tehran Conference cut off aid to this country’s royalist Chetniks in favor of the communist Partisans. After this country’s partition by Nazi Germany, Ante Pavelić was installed as the head of a Croatian puppet state. For 10 points, name this Balkan country whose World War II resistance was led by Josip Broz Tito. ","answer":"ANSWER: Yugoslavia [prompt on Independent State of Croatia until “Croatian” is read”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"0. Enhancing this technology was the initial motivation behind the receiver operating characteristic curve, as well as a specialized vacuum tube called the klystron. A cavity magnetron connected to an antenna, which was used in this technology to output energy in the microwave region of the spectrum, was developed by the British Royal Navy during World War II. The presence of a “hook echo” discovered with this technique may indicate the approach of a tornado. Modern uses of this technology include its “Doppler” form, which is used in meteorology. For 10 points, name this technology that locates objects with the help of radio waves. ","answer":"ANSWER: radar [or radio detection and ranging; or Doppler radar; or weather radar; prompt on object detection; prompt on radio wave electronics or RF before “radio”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"1. A poem set in this city describes “philosophers who cry, ‘All is well,’ / And contemplate the ruins of this world.” While traveling to this city, an Anabaptist named Jacques drowns trying to save an ungrateful sailor from a storm. The title character of a novella is captured by the Inquisition in this city and sentenced to be executed in an auto-da-fé, but is able to save Cunegonde after he kills Don Issachar and the Grand Inquisitor. A catastrophe in this city teaches teaches a character to doubt Dr. Pangloss’s belief that we live in “the best of all possible worlds.” Voltaire’s Candide witnesses the 1755 earthquake in, for 10 points, what Portuguese city? ","answer":"ANSWER: Lisbon "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"2. In the Ramayana, Guha uses one of these vehicles to help transport Rama in his journey. The giantess Hringhorni helps move an enormous one of these items during Baldr’s funeral. One of these vehicles made entirely from nails, known as Naglfar, will be set free during Ragnarok. The Norse god Freyr owns one of these vehicles called Skidbladnir that can be folded into his pocket at will. Zeus orders Calypso to help Odysseus build one of these vehicles that allows him to return home to Ithaca. The king Aegeus jumps to his death after his son Theseus forgets to change the black sails on one of these vehicles. For 10 points, name these vehicles that travel over water. ","answer":"ANSWER: boats [or ships; or ferries] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"3. Dioxane and trioxane are both cyclic ethers with this many members in their rings. The Diels–Alder reaction reacts a diene and a dienophile to form a ring with this many members. Piperidine is a heterocyclic ring with this many members. Applying Hückel’s rule where n equals one corresponds to a system with this many pi-electrons. A cyclic compound with this many carbons exists in “half chair” and “twist boat” conformations. August Kekulé deduced the structure of a compound with this many carbons through a dream with a snake eating its own tail. For 10 points, name this number of carbons in benzene and cyclohexane. ","answer":"ANSWER: six "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"4. In his Memoirs Illustrating the History of this group, Augustin Barruel claimed this group was an Illuminati plot to overthrow Christianity. George Canning published a newspaper opposed to this group, whose even purer Black proponents title a history of the Haitian Revolution by C.L.R. James. A journalist who supported this faction was assassinated by Charlotte Cordray. This faction controlled the Committee of Public Safety until their Reign of Terror was ended by the Thermidorian Reaction. The Girondins were opposed by, for 10 points, what radical faction of the French Revolution led by Maximilien Robespierre? ","answer":"ANSWER: Jacobins [or the Jacobin Club; or The Black Jacobins; or Memoirs Illustrating the History of Jacobinism] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"5. The art of comic book artist Charles Burns inspired a 1991 production of this ballet by Mark Morris set in the 1960s. In a scene from this ballet, a character sits on a clock that begins to strike midnight, causing a tree to grow much taller. Divertissements stereotypically representing ethnic foods like Arabian coffee and Chinese tea precede the grand pas de deux [“pah-day-DO”]that bookends this ballet, which consists of a tarantella and a dance accompanied by the celesta. Notable excerpts from this ballet include the “Waltz of the Snowflakes” and the “Dance of the Sugar Plum Fairy.” For 10 points, name this Pyotr Tchaikovsky ballet traditionally performed around Christmas. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Nutcracker "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"6. This character’s girlfriend sarcastically asks “what part of Long Island are you from?” and says “dating you was like dating a stairmaster” while breaking up with him. In the last scene of the film, a lawyer played by Rashida Jones tells this character “you aren’t an asshole. You’re just trying so hard to be.” Erica Albright breaks up with this man because he is obsessed with joining one of Harvard’s final clubs. A David Fincher adaptation of Ben Ezrich’s The Accidental Billionaires ends with this man settling lawsuits with Eduardo Saverin and the Winklevoss twins. Jesse Eisenberg portrayed, for 10 points, what protagonist of The Social Network and CEO of Facebook? ","answer":"ANSWER: Mark Zuckerberg [accept either] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"7. The “sheepskin effect” describes an increase in this quantity, which is calculated using an equation named for Jacob Mincer. Research by Berkeley’s David Card suggests that immigration has little effect on this quantity; Card also studied the effects of increasing this quantity at various locations in New Jersey. Nominal rigidity refers to a situation in which this quantity become “sticky” or doesn’t react to market conditions. This quantity is often equated to the marginal product of labor. This quantity naturally decreases to a lower bound, according to David Ricardo’s “iron law” of this quantity. For 10 points, the federal “minimum” for what quantity is currently set at $7.25 an hour? ","answer":"ANSWER: wages [or incomes; or minimum wage] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"8. These proteins include regions consisting of repeating sequences of asparagine, proline, and alanine, called NPA regions. A lack of these proteins in the distal collecting duct is a hallmark of many forms of diabetes insipidus. The activation of V2 receptors by antidiuretic hormone stimulates the insertion of these proteins into the cells of the kidney. These proteins typically consist of six alpha-helices that span the cell membrane. Peter Agre discovered that these proteins facilitate osmosis across the phospholipid bilayer. For 10 points, name these proteins that selectively allow the transport of water molecules. ","answer":"ANSWER: aquaporins [prompt on water channels] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"9. Settlers in this colony were referred to as “long knives” by the Iroquois. Natives were educated at Brafferton in this colony after it signed the Treaty of Middle Plantation. This colony’s militia fought the Shawnee at the Battle of Point Pleasant; earlier in this colony’s history, frontiersman disgruntled by Doeg [“doog”] raids formed a militia and burned down its capital. Lord Dunmore and William Berkeley once governed this colony, whose earliest settlers alleviated the Starving Time by trading with the Powhatan Confederacy. For 10 points, name this colony where Nathaniel Bacon’s rebellious army marched on Williamsburg and Jamestown. ","answer":"ANSWER: Virginia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"0. In a chapter titled “[this place] Says Goodbye,” a character with “sad brown shoes” describes going away to this place so she can come back for “the ones who cannot.” In order to play in the “Monkey Garden” behind this place, Sally is told she must kiss a group of boys. After Lucy and Rachel are harassed, they hide high heels in a bushel basket behind this place. A tree behind this place is used for the First Annual Tarzan Jumping Contest, which Meme [“MEH-may”] Ortiz wins. Mama and Papa refer to this place as “temporary” when speaking with the young Esperanza Cordero. For 10 points, name this home in Chicago that titles a book by Sandra Cisneros. ","answer":"ANSWER: The House on Mango Street [or 4006 Mango Street; prompt on Chicago until mentioned] Tiebreaker. A victory in battle for these people was commemorated on the Day of the Vow, which has since been renamed the Day of Reconciliation. These people, many of whom died in the Weenen Massacre, formed a republic under the terms of the Sand River Convention. The murder of Piet Retief [“PEET reh-TEEF”] and his followers by Dingane [“DING-uh-nuh”] was avenged at the Battle of Blood River by some of these people under the command of Andries Pretorius. These people embarked on the Great Trek and migrated to the Transvaal, where they were later led by Paul Kruger. For 10 points, name these descendants of Dutch settlers who fought two wars with Britain in South Africa. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Elizabeth Vestris is credited with originating a design of three walls and a proscenium arch named for this shape. Loges, special seating areas in a theatre, are named for this shape, as is the “office” where one buys tickets. ","answer":"ANSWER: boxes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] An influential American stage designer with this surname parted from realism in books like The Dramatic Imagination. An architect with this surname worked on masques with Ben Jonson before planning Covent Garden. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jones [or Robert Edmond Jones; or Inigo Jones] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Stage designer Es Devlin, who has collaborated with artists like Kanye West, designed the closing performance for this event. Danny Boyle designed this event’s Opening Ceremony, which featured the “Chariots of Fire” theme. ","answer":"ANSWER: 2012 Summer Olympics [or Olympics in London; or the Games of the XXX Olympiad] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this author who later responded to Meun in a work that details the accomplishments of over a hundred real and fictional women, titled The Book of the City of Ladies. ","answer":"ANSWER: Christine de Pizan "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Pizan’s Book was inspired by this author’s On Famous Women. Marguerite of Navarre parodied this author in a work about five men and women who escape a flood by hiding and telling stories in an abbey in the Pyrenees. ","answer":"ANSWER: Giovanni Boccaccio (That Marguerite of Navarre work, The Heptameron, is a parody of Boccaccio’s Decameron) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Christine de Pizan’s works heavily critiqued the convention of the “courtly” form of this emotion. Ovid’s didactic treatise Ars Amatoria is typically translated as The Art of [this emotion]. ","answer":"ANSWER: love "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this city. According to Ab Urbe Condita, it was founded by Romulus on April 21, 753 BCE. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rome "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Ab Urbe Condita was written by this Roman historian, who also titles a set of Discourses by Niccolo Machiavelli. ","answer":"ANSWER: Livy [or Titus Livius Patavinus or Discourses on Livy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Livy was a tutor of this stuttering emperor, whose own scholarly pursuits included histories of Carthage and the Etruscans, as well as the introduction of three new letters to the Latin alphabet. ","answer":"ANSWER: Claudius "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name these events whose propagation was studied by Alan Lloyd Hodgkin and Andrew Fielding Huxley in the longfin inshore squid. ","answer":"ANSWER: action potentials [prompt on spikes or spike trains; prompt on impulses] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Action potentials most commonly occur in these cells, which contain a cell body, axon, and dendrites. ","answer":"ANSWER: neurons "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The influx of this ion into neurons provides the depolarization necessary to induce the propagation of action potentials. ","answer":"ANSWER: sodium ion [or Na+] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this school of international relations, typically contrasted with liberalism, whose adherents emphasize the role of power in states’ interactions. Thinkers associated with its “neo” branch include John Mearsheimer and Kenneth Waltz. ","answer":"ANSWER: realism [or neorealism] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] To illustrate the security dilemma, defensive realists often cite the example of this early 20th-century war, which was partially caused by escalating tensions between the Allied Powers and the Central Powers. ","answer":"ANSWER: World War I "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Robert Jervis claimed the security dilemma could only exist under this situation. The Constructivist Alexander Wendt claimed that this situation “is what states make of it.” ","answer":"ANSWER: anarchy "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this King of Mercia who built a namesake dyke on his kingdom’s western border. ","answer":"ANSWER: Offa "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Offa’s Dyke separates Mercia from this constituent country of the United Kingdom. The title “Prince of [this country]” is traditionally granted to the heir apparent to the British throne. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wales "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"0. ","answer":"ANSWER: Edward I [or Edward Longshanks; prompt on partial answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this son of Zal, the hero of the Iranian epic poem Shahnameh. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rostam "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] On Rostam’s first labor, he is completely asleep when Rakhsh, his animal of this sort, kills an attacking lion. Pegasus is a winged example of these animals in Greek mythology. ","answer":"ANSWER: horse "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Rostam’s seventh labor involves killing the Div-e Sepid, known as the “demon” of this color. Zoroastrian priests wear robes of this color. ","answer":"ANSWER: white "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this language. With Mandarin Chinese, this language titles a play about the mistranslation-hindered travels of American businessman David Cavanaugh in Guiyang. ","answer":"ANSWER: English [or Chinglish] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This author wrote the aforementioned works Chinglish and F.O.B. French diplomat Rene Gallimard finds out that his “Perfect Woman” is actually a male Communist spy in this playwright’s M. Butterfly. ","answer":"ANSWER: David Henry Hwang "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] In this Amy Tan novel, Lindo takes English classes at the First Chinese Baptist Church with the other three members of the title mahjong playing organization. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Joy Luck Club "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this ethnic group whose roughly 150,000 members live around the confluence of the Tigris and Euphrates rivers. Saddam Hussein attempted to destroy this ethnic group by draining their homeland. ","answer":"ANSWER: Marsh Arabs [or Arab al-Ahwar; also accept Ma’adan or shroog, even though these terms are considered derogatory] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Marsh Arabs hold religious ceremonies in mudhif houses, which are made out of these things. Many scholars believe that the “Sea of [these things]” crossed by Moses and the Israelites in the Bible is actually the Red Sea. ","answer":"ANSWER: reeds "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The Uru people live on “floating islands” made out of totora reeds on this largest lake in South America, which straddles the border between Peru and Bolivia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lake Titicaca "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this sandwich compound, which contains two cyclopentadienyl rings coordinated with a central iron atom. ","answer":"ANSWER: ferrocene "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The two cyclopentadienyl rings in ferrocene serve this role. These compounds are Lewis bases that are coordinated to the central metal atom of coordination complexes. ","answer":"ANSWER: ligands "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Ferrocene is also used as an antiknocking compound. Antiknocking compounds are generally used in this substance; they also help to increase this substance’s octane rating. ","answer":"ANSWER: fuel [or gasoline; or petroleum; or oil] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this Chinese philosopher who argued for the existence of four innate ethical tendencies that he called “sprouts.” The last book of the Four Classics is this man’s namesake text. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mencius [or Mengzi; or Meng Tzu; or Meng Ke] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Mencius may have been taught by Zisi, the grandson of this other Chinese philosopher whose teachings are found in the Analects. The rectification of names and five key relationships are concepts from this man’s teachings. ","answer":"ANSWER: Confucius [or Kongzi; or Kong Fuzi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This Confucian virtue is central to the Confucian concept of ancestor veneration. This virtue generally entails obedience to parents, and is exemplified by a Guo Jujing text describing 24 paragons of this virtue. ","answer":"ANSWER: filial piety [or xiào; accept hyodo or hiếu or oyakoko] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this piece for piano and voice based on a Goethe poem. In this lied [“LEED”], the singer portrays a narrator, a father, a son, and the title character, all of whose melodies lie in different vocal ranges. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Der Erlkönig” [or “The Erlking” or “The Elf-King”] [10] “Der Erlkönig” is one of more than 600 lieder [“LEE-der”] composed by this German romantic composer. His never-completed Symphony No. 8 in B minor is nicknamed the Unfinished. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This Paul Dukas [“do-KAH”] piece, also adapted from a Goethe poem, uses the bassoon to represent the title character who disobeys his master. In Disney’s Fantasia, this piece plays as Mickey Mouse uses magical brooms to carry water from a well. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Sorcerer’s Apprentice [or L'apprenti sorcier] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this conqueror who founded the Mongol Empire. ","answer":"ANSWER: Genghis Khan [or Chinggis Khan; or Temüjin] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Despite his prohibition on certain ritual practices, Genghis Khan granted freedom of religion to his subjects in this secret law code, which was used to govern the Mongol Empire. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Yassa "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This distant descendant of Genghis Khan commissioned the production of Islamic art in his capital city, Samarkand. This conqueror razed the city of Delhi, and was sometimes called “lame” due to his limp. ","answer":"ANSWER: Timur the Lame [or Tamerlane] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Identify this electronics company named for a large U.S. state. ","answer":"ANSWER: Texas Instruments [or TI] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] While working at Texas Instruments, Jack Kilby invented the first one of these mass-produced semiconductor devices. They may contain billions of transistors in an area the size of a fingernail. ","answer":"ANSWER: integrated circuits [or ICs] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The TI-83 Plus calculator included this type of nonvolatile, reprogrammable memory. “Memory sticks” store data via this form of memory. ","answer":"ANSWER: flash memory [or flash drives] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this crop central to the play Kongi’s Harvest. In Arrow of God, a failed harvest of this crop convinces the people of Umuaru to embrace T.K. Winterbottom’s religion. ","answer":"ANSWER: yams "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This Nigerian author of Kongi’s Harvest claimed “yams do not sprout amulets” in the poem “Abiku.” Olunde kills himself in place of his more wary father Elesin in this author’s play Death and the King’s Horseman. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wole [“WAH-lay”] Soyinka "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The Yoruban word “abiku” refers to a dead one of these people. In Uzodinma Iweala’s novel Beasts of No Nation, Agu fights in the Sierra Leone Civil War despite being one of these people. ","answer":"ANSWER: children [or child soldier; accept clear knowledge equivalents like kid or boy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This President drew on his observations of the Autobahn as Supreme Commander of Allied Forces in Europe during World War II to authorize construction of the Interstate Highway System. ","answer":"ANSWER: Dwight D. “Ike” Eisenhower "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] A funding bill for this road situated entirely within Kentucky was controversially vetoed by Andrew Jackson, who allegedly did so to spite his Kentuckian rival Henry Clay. ","answer":"ANSWER: Maysville Road "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The Camino Real [“rey-AWL”], or “Royal Road,” connects the colonial-era missions in California founded by this Spanish friar. He was canonized as a saint in 2015 despite opposition from Native American groups. ","answer":"ANSWER: Saint Junípero Serra "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this quantity. Measured in amperes per meter, this property is defined as the amount of magnetic moment per unit volume. ","answer":"ANSWER: magnetization "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The relationship between magnetization M and magnetic field H is not linear in materials exhibiting this phenomenon, creating a namesake loop. This phenomenon involves the creation of magnetic “memory.” ","answer":"ANSWER: hysteresis [or word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Hysteresis is observed in these kinds of magnets. This phenomenon, which exists in iron, nickel, and cobalt, involves permanent magnetic alignment and is named after iron. ","answer":"ANSWER: ferromagnetism [or word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this city where Pope Pius IV commissioned a Flemish artist to sculpt the grand Fountain of Neptune for the renovation of this city’s Piazza Maggiore. The fountain’s success led that sculptor to be nicknamed for this city. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bologna [also accept Giambologna] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The aforementioned artist, Giambologna, quickly moved to Florence, where he painted an allegorical sculpture depicting “Florence Triumphant Over” this city. This city is the site of a famed Leaning Tower. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pisa "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] The work of Giambologna presaged this artistic movement in sculpture, employing its characteristic figura serpentinata. Benvenuto Cellini led the sculptural branch of this movement that featured exaggerated expressions and proportions. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mannerism "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this most famous novel by Charlotte Bronte. A derogatory name for its character Bertha Mason titles Gilbert and Gubar’s aforementioned feminist study of Victorian literature, The Madwoman in the Attic. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jane Eyre "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Madwoman in the Attic also discusses the work of a young Jane Austen, which is referred to using this term. This Latin-derived catch-all term for an author’s early works encompasses Austen’s Love and Freindship. ","answer":"ANSWER: juvenilia (yes, “Freindship” is supposed to be misspelled) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] This novel is referred to as the “Bible of hell” in The Madwoman in the Attic. Nelly Dean relays the story of this novel to a disturbed Mr. Lockwood, who sees the ghost of one of its characters try to enter his room. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wuthering Heights (by Emily Bronte) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this Japanese religion whose shrines include the Ise [“EE-say”] Grand Shrine, which is dedicated to Amaterasu. ","answer":"ANSWER: Shintoism [or kami-no-michi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Statues of these animals are commonly found in Shinto shrines dedicated to Inari, the kami of these animals. Many East Asian countries depict these animals with nine tails. ","answer":"ANSWER: foxes [or kitsune] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Shrine maidens called miko engage in a tradition referred to as kagura, which consists of this activity. A form of this activity performed alongside boiling water rituals at Ise Shrine led to a form of this called Ise-ryu kagura. ","answer":"ANSWER: dancing [accept word forms] Tiebreaker. Statins are drugs that lower the concentration of this compound by targeting the mevalonate pathway. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Name this compound whose esterification can trigger the formation of foam cells. ","answer":"ANSWER: cholesterol "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Cholesterol is important in maintaining the fluidity of this structure, which consists of a semipermeable phospholipid bilayer studded with channel and peripheral proteins. ","answer":"ANSWER: cell membrane [or plasma membrane; prompt on membrane] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"C","question":"[10] Cholesterol is an example of this class of compounds that consists of four fused rings, including three cyclohexane rings and one cyclopentane ring. ","answer":"ANSWER: steroids"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"1. A set of lithographs published in 1945 depicts eleven of these animals drawn progressively more abstractly. The artist of that work also depicted the head of one of these animals in a sculpture consisting of a bicycle seat and handlebars. Paint was blown onto walls to render these animals in “twisted perspective” at a “Great Hall” in the Lascaux Caves. Kristen Visbal’s sculpture Fearless Girl was installed to face a sculpture of one of these animals on Wall Street. One of these animals can be seen to the left of a horse in Picasso’s Guernica. For 10 points, name these aggressive male cows. ","answer":"ANSWER: bulls [prompt on cows or cattle until mentioned] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"2. This politician’s senior thesis on Saul Alinsky was suppressed at the request of the White House. This cabinet member wrote the article “America’s Pacific Century” to codify the “Pivot to Asia,” and popularized the phrase “women’s rights are human rights” at a speech in Beijing. This politician presented a giant red “reset” button to Russian Foreign Minister Sergei Lavrov. She can be seen covering her mouth in Pete Souza’s photo of the Situation Room during the raid on Osama bin Laden’s compound. For 10 points, name this Secretary of State who, as First Lady, supported her husband during the Monica Lewinsky scandal. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hillary Clinton [or Hillary Rodham; prompt on Clinton] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"3. Kobayashi and Maskawa predicted how CP violation for this force necessitates the existence of a third generation of quarks. The gauge bosons for this force, which were discovered by the UA1 and UA2 experiments, are given mass by the Higgs mechanism. Salam, Weinberg, and Glashow were awarded a Nobel Prize for unifying this force with electromagnetism. This fundamental force can cause a down quark to transform into an up quark and an electron antineutrino. This force is mediated by the W+, W-, and Z bosons. For 10 points, name this fundamental force that governs radioactive decay, the second least powerful of the four fundamental forces. ","answer":"ANSWER: weak force [prompt on (radioactive) decay before mentioned] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"4. This figure gives birth to and raises Lava [“LUH-vah”] and Kusha while living in the forest away from her husband. A man draws a circle around this figure to protect her, but she steps out to give alms to an ascetic. This figure undergoes a trial of fire after being reunited with her husband, and gives Hanuman a ring while imprisoned in Lanka. This daughter of King Janaka [“JAW-nuh-kuh”] is said to be born from the earth, and she gets married after a figure strings Shiva’s bow at her swayamvara [“swaw-YUM-vuh-ruh”]. This figure’s desire for a golden deer leads her husband to leave her in the forest. For 10 points, name this wife of Rama who is abducted by Ravana in the Ramayana. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sita [“SHEE-tah”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"5. This character reveals his dislike of capital punishment while describing a guillotining he witnessed in France to a house servant. He exclaims “a man's faith might be ruined by looking at that picture!” upon viewing a copy of Hans Holbein’s Body of the Dead Christ in the Tomb. While delivering a speech on aristocracy at a dinner party, this character accidentally destroys a prized Chinese vase. This character, who harbors romantic feelings for Aglaya and Natassya, is eventually sent back to a Swiss sanitorium to seek treatment for his epilepsy. For 10 points, name this simple-minded title character of a Fyodor Dostoyevsky novel. ","answer":"ANSWER: Prince Lev Nikolayevich Myshkin [or the Idiot] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"6. The ratio of two isotopes of this element in ice cores is used as a paleothermometer to determine prehistoric temperatures. One molecule that contains this element appeared about 2.45 billion years ago in a namesake “great event” that was correlated with the emergence of cyanobacteria. This element can become depleted in lakes through the process of eutrophication. This element, which is found along with silica in all feldspars, is the most abundant element in the Earth’s crust. An allotrope of this element is removed by CFCs in a layer of the stratosphere. For 10 points, name this element found in ozone. ","answer":"ANSWER: oxygen [or O] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"7. Linguistic syncretism is the phenomenon in which one of these units performs multiple grammatical functions, such as the word “bet” being both a past and present tense form. The “zero” form of this unit does not have any phonetic realisation, as in the plural of “sheep.” The ratio of these things to words determines whether a language is more analytic or synthetic. Agglutinative languages express grammatical functions by stringing a large number of these units together. These units are “bound” if they cannot stand alone, such as the affix “un-.” Unlike phonemes, they possess a meaning. For 10 points, name these smallest grammatical units of language. ","answer":"ANSWER: morphemes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"8. A woman in this collection is surprised to receive a sword in place of flowers, causing her to exclaim “No more doll’s decorations for me!” At the end of this collection, the speaker compares his life reaching “its eternal Home” to “a flock of homesick cranes.” The speaker of this collection describes himself as a “frail vessel” that has been “emptiest again and again.” This collection begins by telling God “thou hast made me endless, such is thy Pleasure.” The introduction to this collection was written by William Butler Yeats. For 10 points, name this collection of “Song Offerings” by Bengali poet Rabindranath Tagore. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gitanjali [or Song Of erings before mentioned] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"9. A siege of this city was aided by Imre Thököly and his army of Kuruc [“koo-ROOTZ”] rebels. Nicholas of Salm commanded the defense of this city atop walls that were partially financed by the ransom of Richard the Lionheart. Cannons captured during a siege of this city were later cast into bells for St. Stephen’s Cathedral. Eugene of Savoy entered the service of this city’s ruler during a failed siege led by Kara Mustafa Pasha. This city was rescued from that 1683 siege by the cavalry of Polish King Jan Sobieski. For 10 points, name this city that twice withstood Ottoman sieges, the capital of Austria. ","answer":"ANSWER: Vienna [or Wien] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"1. Another composer from this country featured 840 repetitions of a theme in his Vexations, and wrote a set of three piano pieces named for a dance performed by naked Spartan boys. A group of experimental composers from this country known as “The Six” were influenced by a man from this country who composed the Gymnopédies. For 10 points, name this home country of Arthur Honegger and Erik Satie. ","answer":"ANSWER: France [or French Republic] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"1. Debye’s law predicts that a solid’s specific heat is proportional to the third power of this quantity. The root-mean-squared speed of a gas represented by the Maxwell–Boltzmann distribution is proportional to the square root of the ideal gas constant times this quantity, over the molar mass. Thermodynamic beta is defined as one over the product of Boltzmann’s constant and this quantity. The zeroth law of thermodynamics considers two systems with the same value of this quantity as a third system. The smallest possible value of this quantity is absolute zero. For 10 points, name this quantity that measures the average kinetic energy of a system, whose SI unit is the Kelvin. ","answer":"ANSWER: temperature [prompt on T] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"2. This religion’s orthodox sect was founded by a follower of Mason Remey, who is considered a “covenant breaker” under this religion’s Lesser Covenant. This religion’s short obligatory prayer ends by calling God “the Help in Peril, the Self-Subsisting.” This religion’s governing body issues an annual worldwide message during this religion’s twelve-day festival of Riḍván, which commemorates a speech its founder gave in a garden. This religion’s central text is the Kitáb-i-Aqdas. A Ten Year Crusade by this religion’s first Guardian, Shoghi Effendi, ended with the creation of this religion’s Universal House of Justice. For 10 points, name this religion founded by Bahá'u'lláh. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bahá'í Faith [or Baha'iyyah] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"3. This crop was brought to Chikmagalur, India by the Sufi saint Baba Budan. The dying indigo industry was replaced with this crop by the oligarchy of the Fourteen Families in El Salvador. Fazendas producing this crop dominated the São Paulo economy during a period named for “[this crop] with milk” in Brazil. With his mule Conchita, Juan Valdez is an iconic representative of this crop in Colombia, where it is grown in a namesake triangle. Cultivation of this crop in Java began after the Dutch obtained some plants from the Yemeni port of Mocha. For 10 points, name this crop whose arabica beans are used to make cappuccinos. ","answer":"ANSWER: coffee "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"4. At the 2018 FIFA World Cup, this national soccer team used the basketball-inspired “love train” strategy of attacking corner kicks. Members of this team were photographed frolicking on inflatable unicorn pool toys a day after they defeated Tunisia on a last-minute header. The coach of this team became a surprise fashion icon after online sales of his trademark navy waistcoat skyrocketed. The phrase “it’s coming home” became a meme after this team defeated Colombia and Sweden to reach the World Cup semi-finals, where they lost to Croatia. For 10 points, name this Gareth Southgate-coached national soccer team that plays home matches at Wembley Stadium. ","answer":"ANSWER: England national soccer team [prompt on The Three Lions; do not accept or prompt on “United Kingdom” or “Great Britain”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"5. Eighteen of these objects symbolize eighteen stories in a 1951 collection partially named for some possessed by a Wisconsin carnival worker. Sarah Ruth believes one of these objects is sacrilegious in Flannery O’Connor’s story “Parker’s Back.” Alvaro drops a condom while discussing one of these objects with Serafina in a Tennessee Williams play titled for a Rose one of them. According to Ishmael, these “purplish yellow” objects can result from a white man falling among cannibals; Ishmael makes this observation after seeing that Queequeg’s body is covered in these objects. For 10 points, name these artworks that cover the body of Ray Bradbury’s Illustrated Man. ","answer":"ANSWER: tattoos [accept illustrations before “Sarah Ruth” is read, prompt afterwards; accept specific descriptions of tattoos like The Rose Tattoo and tattoos of Jesus] 16.This philosopher quoted another man’s “first principles of demonstration” in a passage that states that “no one can mentally admit the opposite of what is self-evident.” A text by this philosopher takes an argument from “the governance of the world.” That text by this philosopher borrows from another thinker by defining “motion” as reducing something from potentiality to actuality, and includes sets of objections followed by contradicting statements introduced with the Latin phrase “sed contra.” This philosopher argued that God is the first efficient cause in his five proofs for God’s existence. For 10 points, name this author of the Summa Theologica. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"7. This musician improvised a jazz break to open his solo during a 1946 recording of “A Night in Tunisia” with Miles Davis. Charles Mingus’ Mingus Revisited was originally released under the title Pre-[this musician’s name]. After pawning his instrument for heroin, this musician used a Grafton plastic instrument to perform in a famous quintet at Massey Hall. This musician reworked a theme from Ray Noble’s “Cherokee” for his composition “Ko-Ko.” He quoted “How High the Moon” in a song that references his nickname, “Ornithology.” For 10 points, name this bebop saxophonist who was nicknamed “Bird.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Charlie “Bird” Parker Jr. [prompt on Yardbird or Bird] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"8. At the end of one of this author’s novels, the title character watches a goose jump over the head of his lover Marmaduke Bonthrop Shelmerdine. In another novel by this author, the title character decides to “buy the flowers herself,” and is compared to a lily by her former lovers Peter Walsh and Sally Seton. This lover of Vita Sackville-West wrote a satirical “biography” of an Elizabethan genderfluid poet, Orlando. In her best-known novel, World War I veteran Septimus Smith jumps out a window as the title character, Clarissa, prepares to throw a party in London. For 10 points, name this author of Mrs. Dalloway. ","answer":"ANSWER: Virginia Woolf "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"9. This process is controlled by the bZIP [“BEE-zip”] class of proteins, which contain leucine zipper motifs and include the protein MafK [“MAFF-KAY”]. It can be terminated prematurely by attenuators, which are an example of cis-regulatory elements. David Hogness and Michael Goldberg identified a sequence critical to the initiation of this process called the TATA [“TAH-TAH”] box. “Factors” that control the rate of this process may bind to activators or promoters. After this process occurs, introns are removed during the process of splicing. For 10 points, name this process in which an mRNA strand is created from DNA, and which occurs before translation. ","answer":"ANSWER: transcription [accept transcription factors] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"0. An ivory statuette of the goddess Lakshmi discovered at this non-Asian location is thought to have come from northern India. A monarch who visited this site was so alarmed by its erotic artwork that he had it confined to a Secret Museum. Giuseppe Fiorelli developed the process of making plaster casts of corpses at this site. Frescoes depicting the initiation rites of a mystery cult were unearthed in this site’s Villa of Mysteries, and a mosaic of Alexander the Great was displayed in this site’s House of the Faun. Pliny the Elder died trying to rescue victims near this place at Herculaneum. For 10 points, name this Roman town that was destroyed by the eruption of Mount Vesuvius. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pompeii Tiebreaker. This taxonomic class includes the family Reduviidae, which has earned the nickname “assassin” due to their nature as ambush predators. Another animal in this class native to the Americas produces carminic acid, from which the dye carmine is made. Animals in this class include the cochineal and an organism that stays underground during a 13- or 17-year long life cycle. Hemiptera is an order in this class, whose members may enter the imago stage after emerging from the pupa. For 10 points, name this class that includes aphids and cicadas. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this city. Two neighbors discover that their spouses are having an affair with one another in In the Mood for Love, a 2000 film set in this city that introduced its Second Wave of filmmakers to global audiences. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hong Kong "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Hong Kong cinema initially gained international fame through films in this genre, exemplified by the work of Wong Fei-hung and the Shaw Brothers. Later, it was popularized by actors like Bruce Lee and Jackie Chan. ","answer":"ANSWER: martial arts films [or kung fu films or karate films; prompt on action films] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] The director of In the Mood for Love, Wong Kar-wai, often collaborates with Christopher Doyle, who has this profession. This member of a film crew controls the film’s lighting, lensing, and overall visual aesthetic. ","answer":"ANSWER: cinematographer [or director of photography; or DP; or DOP] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This Oxford scholar used the word “hwæt” so much his students thought it meant “quiet.” He argued that scholars should appreciate Beowulf as a literary work, not a historical one, in “The Monsters and the Critics.” ","answer":"ANSWER: J.R.R. Tolkien [or John Ronald Reuel Tolkien] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This Irish poet translated “hwæt” as a casual “so” in his “New Verse Translation” of Beowulf. His collection Death of a Naturalist includes a poem about an “old man” who “could handle a spade,” “Digging.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Seamus Heaney "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] C.K. Scott Moncrieff, who translated “hwæt” as “what” in his version of Beowulf, is better known for his English translations of literature in this language, including books by Proust and The Song of Roland. ","answer":"ANSWER: French "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Wife-carrying races are inexplicably popular in this Scandinavian country, which hosts many Nordic walking races in and around its capital city of Helsinki. ","answer":"ANSWER: Republic of Finland [or Suomi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"5. ","answer":"ANSWER: Iditarod Trail Sled Race "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Christopher McDougall's Born to Run brought attention to the Tarahumara people of this country, who are renowned for their abilities to run long distance races barefoot. The rodeo-like sport of charreada was invented in this country. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mexico 4.This country experienced the Killing Time after rebels issued the Sanquhar Declaration in response to a monarch’s renunciation of the Treaty of Breda. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this country where Covenanters led by the Earl of Argyll fought off the imposition of episcopacy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Scotland [prompt on United Kingdom or Great Britain] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] While king of Scotland, this monarch attempted to integrate the Church of Scotland with Anglican episcopacy in his Five Articles of Perth. This first Stuart king of England also authorized an English translation of the Bible. ","answer":"ANSWER: James I of England [or James VI of Scotland] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This theologian ushered in the Scottish Reformation by writing the Scots Confession. He attacked female rulers in his pamphlet The First Blast of the Trumpet Against the Monstrous Regiment of Women. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Knox "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this conic section, which consists of points that are equidistant to a single point called the focus and a line called the directrix. ","answer":"ANSWER: parabola "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Simpson’s rule is a method of performing this task using parabolas. The trapezoidal rule is another technique for doing this task. ","answer":"ANSWER: numerical integration [or approximating a (definite) integral; or approximating the area under a curve; prompt on area] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This function of x generates a catenary in the xy-plane. It equals the average of the functions “e to the x” and “e to the negative x.” ","answer":"ANSWER: hyperbolic cosine of x [or cosh of x] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] In an essay, Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie claimed that “we should all be” these people. Roxane Gay considers herself a “bad” one of these people because she likes rap music and the color pink. ","answer":"ANSWER: feminists "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Essayist Jill Lepore wrote about this historical figure’s sister Jane in her Book of Ages. In Ann Petry’s novel The Street, Lutie Johnson follows the ideals presented in this man’s essay “The Way to Wealth.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Benjamin Franklin "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] In The Empathy Exams, Leslie Jamison describes performing this job for medical students. Jennifer Lawrence asked why she made less in this profession than her male counterparts in a piece for Lena Dunham’s newsletter. ","answer":"ANSWER: acting [or being an actor or actress] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this modern-day country where an 1830 performance of The Mute Girl of Portici inspired this country’s Walloon and Flemish ethnic groups to secede from the United Provinces. ","answer":"ANSWER: Belgium "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] The Mute Girl of Portici was a patriotic work of this type. Italian nationalists supported unification under King Victor Emmanuel II with their slogan “Viva Verdi,” which referenced the name of a composer of these works. ","answer":"ANSWER: operas "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This French diplomat’s plan to partition Belgium and annex Wallonia was rejected at the London Conference. This notoriously duplicitous minister represented France at the Congress of Vienna. ","answer":"ANSWER: Charles Maurice de Talleyrand-Périgord "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this American scientist. He also formulated a phase rule that gives the number of degrees of freedom of certain multi-component systems. ","answer":"ANSWER: Josiah (Willard) Gibbs "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Gibbs also names a type of “free energy” which is equal to this quantity minus the product of entropy and temperature. This quantity, equal to the internal energy plus PV, is symbolized H. ","answer":"ANSWER: enthalpy "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Enthalpy is considered one of these types of functions. These types of functions do not depend on the path between two positions of a system. ","answer":"ANSWER: state functions "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this process that comes in contagious, hierarchical, and stimulus varieties. In the study of geography, this term refers to the spread of a phenomenon. ","answer":"ANSWER: diffusion "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Leo Frobenius coined a form of diffusion involving this concept. Carl Sauer founded a branch of geography focusing on this concept, which encompasses the beliefs, customs, and values of a people. ","answer":"ANSWER: culture [or cultural diffusion; or cultural geography] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This 1997 book partially examines the role of diffusion in explaining why Eurasian civilizations became the dominant world powers, a process largely aided by the title entities. ","answer":"ANSWER: Guns, Germs, and Steel: The Fates of Human Societies (by Jared Diamond) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name these creatures from Greek myth who attempted to abduct Hippodamia on her wedding day, thus inciting a war with the Lapiths. The bodies of these creatures are half-man, half-horse. ","answer":"ANSWER: centaurs "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This wise centaur didn’t join his more rowdy brethren in their attempted abduction of Hippodamia. He tutored Jason and Achilles. ","answer":"ANSWER: Chiron "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] The centaurs were produced by this Lapith king’s union with the cloud nymph Nephele. Hermes punished this king by strapping him to a fiery wheel, which spins in Hades for all eternity. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ixion "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this Romantic era pianist who popularized performing from memory. This composer of the Soirées musicales and a piano trio in G minor is depicted in the 11th section of another composer’s Carnaval. ","answer":"ANSWER: Clara Schumann [or Clara Wieck; prompt on Schumann] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Clara Schumann and Joseph Joachim were both musicians from this country, as was Clara’s husband Robert Schumann. ","answer":"ANSWER: Federal Republic of Germany [or Bundesrepublik Deutschland] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Clara premiered this close friend’s piece Variations and Fugue on a Theme by Handel. Clara also premiered this composer’s Opus 49, which contains a famous “lullaby” dedicated to this composer’s friend Bertha Faber. ","answer":"ANSWER: Johannes Brahms "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"8. ","answer":"ANSWER: organesson [or Or] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Organesson is the heaviest-known element in this group on the periodic table. Elements in this group, whose lightest element is helium, are relatively unreactive due to their completely filled valence shells. ","answer":"ANSWER: noble gases [or inert gases; or Group 18] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This noble gas element is produced in stars from the fusion of oxygen and helium, making it the fifth most abundant element in the universe by mass. This gas is commonly used in gas-discharge tubes for lighting. ","answer":"ANSWER: neon [or Ne] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this type of place. These places are often the setting of works by Native American writers, such as Louise Erdrich's Love Medicine. ","answer":"ANSWER: Native American reservations "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"8. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sherman Alexie "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] The contemporary Mojave poet of When my Brother was an Aztec has this last name. Another author of this surname wrote This is How You Lose Her and a novel about an overweight Dominican nerd. ","answer":"ANSWER: Diaz [accept Natalie Diaz; accept Junot Diaz] (the novel alluded to in the second sentence is The Brief Wondrous Life of Oscar Wao) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name these two concepts, which one philosopher argued were a priori notions that grounded all comprehension of sense experience. That philosopher structured human experience using cause and effect and these two concepts. ","answer":"ANSWER: space and time [accept in either order] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This philosopher argued that space and time were integral to the structure of human experience. This man wrote Groundwork of the Metaphysics of Morals and defined categorical imperatives in another of his works. ","answer":"ANSWER: Immanuel Kant "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This Kant text argues for transcendental idealism of space and time and discusses the analytic-synthetic dichotomy. This text is the first in a series of three Kant texts including ones about “Practical Reason” and “Judgment.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Critique of Pure Reason "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"1. ","answer":"ANSWER: Democratic Republic of the Congo [or Congo-Kinshasa; or Congo-Léopoldville; do not accept or prompt on “Zaire”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This motorcycle-riding revolutionary arrived in the Congo to instruct the Simbas in his foco theory of guerilla warfare. This Argentine-born comrade of Fidel Castro is immortalized in the Guerrillero Heroico photograph, ","answer":"ANSWER: Ernesto “Che” Guevara [prompt on El Che] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Che Guevara initially joined up with a Congolese rebel with this surname, but broke off on his own because that rebel was too lazy. Another former guerilla with this surname is the D.R. Congo’s current president. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kabila [Laurent-Désiré Kabila or Joseph Kabila] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this filtration system possessed by animals in Mysticeti, a subgroup of Cetacea. ","answer":"ANSWER: baleen [accept whalebone] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] The baleen system is used by this heaviest living species of whale, which is widely believed to be the largest animal that has ever existed. ","answer":"ANSWER: blue whale [or Balaenoptera musculus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Blue whales belong to this family of baleen whales that also includes the fin and minke whales. Lunge feeding in this family is believed to be the largest biomechanical event on Earth. ","answer":"ANSWER: rorquals [or Balaenopteridae] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this character who mentions “the public works of Puncher and Wattmann” in the aforementioned monologue, which he delivers after another character commands him to “Think!” ","answer":"ANSWER: Lucky "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Lucky appears in a play titled for this character. Because this character never actually appears during the play, some critics argue that he symbolizes God. ","answer":"ANSWER: Godot [or Waiting for Godot] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This Irish playwright, who wrote Waiting for Godot, rejected that analysis, claiming, “If by Godot I had meant God I would have said God, and not Godot.” He also wrote Endgame and Happy Days. ","answer":"ANSWER: Samuel Beckett "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this syncretic Caribbean religion that worships orishas like Olodumare. The Supreme Court case Lukumi Babalu v. City of Hialeah concerned this religion’s practice of animal sacrifice. ","answer":"ANSWER: Santería [or Regla de Ocha] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This other syncretic Caribbean religion originates from Haiti. Namesake dolls, zombies, and other witchcraftrelated practices are commonly associated with this religion, which worships spirits called loas. ","answer":"ANSWER: Vodou [or Voodoo] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Elekes, things that consist of these objects, are received in the first stage of the Santería initiation process. Practitioners of Islam use misbahas, which consist of these objects, during dhikr. ","answer":"ANSWER: beads [or prayer beads] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this Swiss Neoclassical painter best known for her history paintings, such as Cornelia Presenting Her Children as Her Treasures. ","answer":"ANSWER: Angelica Kauffmann "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Kaufmann was one of two women who helped found this English institution, led initially by Joshua Reynolds. Because the two weren’t allowed in its 1772 group portrait, Johann Zoffany included portraits of them on this institution’s wall. ","answer":"ANSWER: Royal Academy of Arts "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] The other female founder, Mary Moser, gained prominence through her paintings of these plants. Many critics have emphasized the sexual nature of Georgia O’Keefe’s paintings of these plants. ","answer":"ANSWER: flowers [accept more specific answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this city infiltrated by the Culper Ring during its occupation by William Howe’s British forces. This city’s Great Fire of 1776 may have been set by arsonists loyal to the American cause. ","answer":"ANSWER: New York City "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] After the British spy John André was captured, Tallmadge acted to stop him from being sent to this American general at West Point, whom Tallmadge correctly suspected of being a traitor. ","answer":"ANSWER: Benedict Arnold "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Tallmadge was a Yale classmate of this other spy who was captured in New York City. Before being hanged, this spy exclaimed “I only regret that I have but one life to lose for my country.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Nathan Hale Tiebreaker. The Annals of one of this empire’s rulers are inscribed in the British Museum’s Taylor Prism. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Name this empire whose ruler Sennacherib razed Babylon to the ground. Sennacherib ruled from this empire’s capital city of Nineveh. ","answer":"ANSWER: Assyrian Empire "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] Sennacherib’s Annals mentions his unsuccessful 701 BCE siege of this city, which was ruled by King Hezekiah. The Tanakh records that Hezekiah stripped the gold from this city’s Temple of Solomon to pay tribute to Sennacherib. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jerusalem "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"D","question":"[10] This ruler sacked Jerusalem and destroyed its Temple in 597 BCE, ushering in the Babylonian Captivity. According to Josephus, this king built the Hanging Gardens of Babylon. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nebuchadnezzar II [prompt on partial answers]"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"1. During this battle, Ameinias failed to capture an enemy commander who held a ten-thousand drachma bounty for the insolence of being a woman. At this battle, the victorious leader had his slave Sicinnus feign defection in order to lure the enemy into position. The losing commander built a throne on Mount Aigaleo to observe this battle, which was fought after a stalemate at Artemisium. Queen Artemisia of Halicarnassus escaped this battle by ramming her ship into friendly forces. For 10 points, name this 480 B.C. defeat of Xerxes’ Persian navy by an allied Greek fleet under the command of Themistocles. ","answer":"ANSWER: Battle of Salamis "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"2. In a play by this author, the sudden withering of some roses represents the demise of the title spinster, who waits over twenty years for her fiance to return. This author wrote a play in which a mother is reminded of her husband’s death by her son’s request for a knife; in that play, Death takes the form of an old beggar woman while the Moon is represented by a young woodcutter. Near the end of that work by this playwright, Leonardo Felix and the Groom kill each other. This author’s best known play features an all-female cast, and concerns a matriarch who institutes a lengthy mourning period for her second husband. For 10 points, name this Spanish playwright of Blood Wedding and The House of Bernarda Alba. ","answer":"ANSWER: Federico Garcia Lorca "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"3. People of this profession are depicted in the best-known portraits of photographer Barbara Morgan. It’s not acting, but a woman of this profession named Moira Shearer plays Vicky Page in Powell and Pressburger’s film The Red Shoes. Marie van Goethem, a 14-year old girl of this profession, is depicted in an 1880 wax sculpture by an artist who also painted one of these people in Fin d'Arabesque. People of this profession like Misty Copeland often practice Pierre Beauchamp’s five positions. Edgar Degas painted two young girls of this profession Practicing at the Barre. For 10 points, name this artistic profession whose female practitioners traditionally wear tutus. ","answer":"ANSWER: ballet dancers [or ballerinas; prompt on dancers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"4. This religion’s prophets preached at halls called samavasaranas after achieving a state called kevala jnana [“KAY-vuh-luhj NAW-nuh”]. Five auspicious events known as Panch Kalyanaka are associated with the lives of this religion’s prophets. This religion’s last major historical figure preached the principle of anekantavada, or many-sided reality, and had his teachings compiled into the Agamas. A broom, a gourd, and a book of scripture are the only possessions held by the naked monks of this religion’s Digambara sect. This religion’s last tirthankara, Mahavira, preached observance of the five vows. For 10 points, name this Indian religion that emphasizes a form of nonviolence called ahimsa. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jainism [or Jain Dharma] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"5. It’s not scattering, but this phenomenon can cause anti-Stokes lines when the starting molecule is already in an excited state. The decay of this process can be accomplished through Dexter electron transfer or Förster resonance energy transfer. The intensity of this process can be reduced by quenching. The quantum yield of this process is equal to the ratio of the number of photons emitted and the number of photons absorbed. This process names lamps that use mercury vapor to emit light. This process names a form of microscopy that often makes use of GFP. For 10 points, name this form of luminescence in which photons are absorbed and then emitted at a lower energy. ","answer":"ANSWER: fluorescence [accept word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"6. Particularly violent examples of these groups, such as the Cossacks and the Comancheros, are often referred to as “one-percenters.” Alexander Zaldostanov leads a Vladimir Putin-backed group of this type, The Night Wolves, that participated in the annexation of Crimea. One of these groups was allegedly paid in beer to provide security at the Altamont Free Concert, where they caused a riot during The Rolling Stones’ performance. Mayans MC is a spin-off of an FX Network show about a fictional one of these groups, the Sons of Anarchy. The Bandidos and the Hell’s Angels are examples of, for 10 points, what criminal groups whose members often ride Harley Davidsons? ","answer":"ANSWER: outlaw motorcycle gangs [accept outlaw motorcycle clubs or biker gangs or other reasonable descriptive answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"7. The plot of one of this author’s novels is compared to the allegations of the Casement Report in an Adam Hochschild book. Tayeb Salih’s Season of Migration to the North is often interpreted as a rebuttal to this author. In Dreams from My Father, Barack Obama says that this author’s most famous novel is “not about black people” but this man’s perspective. This author is called a “thoroughgoing racist” in an essay that claims his depiction of Africa “is to Europe as the picture is to Dorian Gray.” Chinua Achebe’s “An Image of Africa” attacks this author’s use of racist tropes in a novel that ends with Kurtz’s death. For 10 points, name this author of Heart of Darkness. ","answer":"ANSWER: Joseph Conrad [or Jozef Teodor Konrad Korzeniowski] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"8. After arming followers of this movement in Wales, William Price fled to France and became an archdruid. Thomas Carlyle raised the “Condition of England” question in a pamphlet titled for this movement. A march on the Westgate Hotel led by John Frost to free supporters of this movement culminated in the Newport Rising. Feargus O’Connor propagated this movement in his newspaper, The Northern Star. William Lovett helped draft this movement’s namesake document, which included calls for compensating MPs and secret ballots among its six demands. For 10 points, name this working-class movement that sought universal male suffrage in Britain. ","answer":"ANSWER: Chartists [or Chartism] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"9. Xenon monochloride can be used to create the excimer type of these devices. These devices were used by Arthur Ashkin to manipulate small particles, winning him the 2018 Nobel Prize in Physics for the development of optical tweezers. Theodore Maiman developed the first of these devices, which used ruby as a gain medium. Arthur Kastler invented the technique of optical pumping, which is used in these devices to achieve a population inversion. The Einstein A and B coefficients describe processes that occur in these devices, including spontaneous and stimulated emission. For 10 points, name these devices that emit a beam of coherent light. ","answer":"ANSWER: lasers [accept lamps before “Arthur” is read; prompt on optical tweezers before read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"0. Galen Strawson asserts that this concept leads to an infinite regression in his “Basic Argument” against this concept. Alvin Plantinga’s defense against the argument from evil is named for this concept. Daniel Dennett’s Elbow Room uses intuition pumps to explain this concept. Duration is defined as “the immediate data of consciousness” in a Henri Bergson book titled for Time and this concept. Compatibilist philosophers argue that this concept and determinism are not mutually exclusive. For 10 points, name this philosophical concept, the ability to choose between possible actions. ","answer":"ANSWER: free will "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"1. Court cases involving this practice often use a test coined by Earl Warren’s majority opinion in Tropp v. Dulles, the “evolving standards of decency” test. When given a scenario about his wife Kitty, Michael Dukakis defended his opposition to this practice during a presidential debate. Roper v. Simmons established that this practice cannot be imposed on juveniles. A notoriously faulty device nicknamed “Old Sparky” was used to perform this practice in Florida. The majority opinion to Furman v. Georgia, which briefly suspended this practice in the United States, concluded that this practice is always “cruel and unusual punishment.” For 10 points, name this practice of executing criminals. ","answer":"ANSWER: capital punishment [or the death penalty; or execution until it is read; accept more specific types of capital punishment like the electric chair or lethal injection; prompt on cruel and unusual punishment until read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"2. Samuel Butler argued that this book was written by a Sicilian woman. Emily Wilson’s 2018 translation of this book emphasizes its protagonist’s role as a “complicated man” by describing him as a “wily lord of lies.” Poems from the perspective of twelve hanged maids are interspersed throughout Margaret Atwood’s modern interpretation of this book. The last chapter of a novel inspired by this book is a soliloquy in which a woman exclaims “yes I said yes I will Yes;” that woman is Molly Bloom and that chapter is entitled “Penelope.” James Joyce’s Ulysses is a retelling of, for 10 points, what Homeric epic?. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Odyssey "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"3. A Trojan hero who is invulnerable to spear and sword turned into one of these animals after he was strangled to death by Achilles. The son of Sthenelus turned into one of these animals out of grief after the death of his lover Phaethon. Ares turned Alectryon into one of these animals because he fell asleep guarding Ares and Aphrodite. Heracles shoots many these animals with arrows from the Hydra as part of his sixth labor; those are the Stymphalian types of these animals. Castor and Pollux were born after Leda was impregnated by Zeus in the form of one of these animals. For 10 points, cygnus and apus are what kind of flying animal? ","answer":"ANSWER: birds [accept swans; accept roosters] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"4. Natural toxicants produced in this plant include chaconine and other glycoalkaloids. In the 1950s many Warsaw Pact countries attempted to eradicate a yellow-striped beetle from Colorado that damaged this plant. A disease that affects this plant is caused by the water mold Phytophthora infestans, Possible ancestors of this crop include Solanum brevicaule, which is native to the Andes Mountains. At 300 million more tons per year than the eggplant and tomato, this crop is the highest produced nightshade plant. For 10 points, late blight affects what plant whose tuber is harvested for use in foods such as French fries? ","answer":"ANSWER: potato plant [or Solanum tuberosum; prompt on spud or tater or other informal terms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"5. An artist who visited this city was influenced by Raphael Mengs and Johann Winckelmann’s studies of its artworks. A painting contrasts a resident of this city, who broods in the shadows on the left, with his wife and daughters, who mourn as men “bring [him] the bodies of his sons.” In a painting set in this city, the central figure is framed in the center of three arches as his three sons salute the swords he is holding. Students at this city’s French Academy vied for its namesake “Prix” and made sketches of sculptures like The Dying Gladiator and Laocoön. For 10 points, French Neoclassicists like Jacques-Louis David were inspired by the art of Greece and what Italian city, the setting of David’s Oath of the Horatii? ","answer":"ANSWER: Rome "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"6. One of this man’s books caused a scandal in Germany when it was advertised on the jerseys of the ECD Iserlohn hockey team. The Lebanese Shia leader Musa al-Sadr is believed to have died at the hands of this leader, who developed the Third International Theory and the Jamahiriya political system. This leader’s adopted daughter Hana may have died during Operation El Dorado Canyon, which Ronald Reagan ordered in response to his 1986 bombing of a West Berlin discotheque. This author of The Green Book died in 2011 after his regime was overthrown during the Arab Spring. For 10 points, name this longtime dictator of Libya. ","answer":"ANSWER: Muammar Al-Gaddafi [also accept Moammar Gadhafi or Muanmar Khadaf] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"7. A low frequency response exhibited by these devices known as the “proximity effect” may be common if they employ a directional or cardioid polar pattern. Small examples of these devices known as lavaliers can be mounted using clips. Gerhard Sessler of Bell Labs invented the common “electret” type of these devices, which uses a permanently charged material to record changes in air pressure. The “dynamic” type of these devices, which contains an induction coil connected to a diaphragm, uses an operating principle similar to that of loudspeakers. For 10 points, sound waves are converted to electrical signals by what devices that increase a speaker’s volume? ","answer":"ANSWER: microphones [or mics; accept electret microphones; accept dynamic microphones] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"7. Much of this country’s crude oil deposits are located in a 5,100 square mile tidal bay that has a notable duckweed infestation. Angel Falls is in this country, and its central llanos region is irrigated by the Orinoco River. Lake Maracaibo is located in, for 10 points, what country whose capital is Caracas? ","answer":"ANSWER: Venezuela "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"9. A symphony by this composer uses a motif in which the winds play A major and A minor triads over a marchlike timpani rhythm. The word “ewig” [“EE-vig”] is repeatedly sung at the end of this composer’s setting of Hans Bethge’s translations of Chinese poetry. A solo trumpet plays a C-sharp minor fanfare in the opening funeral march of a symphony by this composer whose fourth movement is titled “Urlicht.” Another symphony by this composer includes three “hammer blows of fate” and a theme named for his wife, Alma. For 10 points, name this composer of symphonies nicknamed “Titan” and “Resurrection,” as well as the “Symphony of a Thousand.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Gustav Mahler "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"0. A Henry Louis Gates book titled for the Trials of this poet discusses how Thomas Jefferson tried to undermine this poet’s reputation. This poet, who argued that anyone “may be refin’d, and join th’angelic train,” describes “a celestial choir enthron’d in realms of light” in a poem that praises “Columbia’s scenes of glorious toil.” This writer claimed that “Twas mercy brought me from my pagan land” in a poem that preceded a work dedicated to “His Excellency” George Washington. For 10 points, name this poet who wrote about her experience being taken to the United States as a slave in “On Being Brought from Africa to America.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Phillis Wheatley Tiebreaker. During this war, Thomas Egenton Hogg was arrested for plotting to seize the Panama Railroad Company’s Salvador steamer. A commerce raider fired the last shots of this war off the coast of Alaska five months before surrendering on the River Mersey. John Ericsson designed a ship with a rotating turret at the behest of Gideon Welles during this war, whose captured shipping led Charles Francis Adams to negotiate settlement of the Alabama Claims. One admiral during this war ordered his ships to “damn the torpedoes!” at the Battle of Mobile Bay; that man was David Farragut. For 10 points, name this war in which the ironclads Monitor and Merrimack clashed off Hampton Roads. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"1. John O’Keeffe received a 2014 Nobel for identifying cells in this structure that activate when a certain environment is encountered. For 10 points each: [10]Name this structure that contains the dentate gyrus. Long-term potentiation was first discovered in this structure. ","answer":"ANSWER: hippocampus [10]Damage to the dentate gyrus has been shown to induce the “anterograde” form of this condition of excessive memory loss. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this Dutch Golden Age painter of the aforementioned masterpiece, Girl with a Pearl Earring. ","answer":"ANSWER: Johannes Vermeer "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] This artist’s Portrait of Adele Bloch-Bauer is nicknamed “Vienna’s Mona Lisa.” This foremost member of the Vienna Secession made heavy use of gold leaf in paintings like The Kiss. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gustav Klimt "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"0. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Sea of Galilee [or The Storm on the Sea of Galilee] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name these Occitan heretics, based in Southern France, who were massacred at Béziers during an early 13 th -century crusade led by Simon de Montfort the Elder. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cathars [or Albigensians] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Known as gitanos in Spain, these speakers of the Caló language were persecuted in a Great Round-Up ordered by Ferdinand VI. Centuries later, these people were rounded up and massacred during the Porajmos ","answer":"ANSWER: Romani [or Roma; or Gypsies; or Kalé] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] This minority group, whose Sephardic communities populated Iberia, was expelled from Spain by Ferdinand and Isabella’s Alhambra Decree. In Medieval Europe, these people were often accused of using Christian children’s blood to make matzah. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jews [or Jewish people; or Judaism] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this concept that was also divided into multiple categories by Howard Gardner. The Stanford-Binet scale measures its “quotient.” ","answer":"ANSWER: intelligence "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] The self, the world, and the future comprise a “cognitive triad” Aaron Beck proposed to understand beliefs associated with this condition. Dysthymia is a less-severe form of this condition that is often treated with SSRIs. ","answer":"ANSWER: clinical depression "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Mary Ainsworth’s “Strange Situation” experiment helped establish three primary forms of this concept: secure, insecure, and ambivalent. These relationships are key to a theory pioneered by John Bowlby. ","answer":"ANSWER: attachments [or attachment theory] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Timothy Findley coined the name for an “Ontario” version of this genre which, in America, was exemplified in by the work of Carson McCullers and the short story “A Good Man is Hard to Find.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Southern Gothic [accept Southern Ontario Gothic] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Naomi Nakane reconstructs her memory of the Canadian rendition of this historical event in Joy Kogawa’s Obasan. American characters named “Mother”and “Father” are separated during this event in a Julie Otsuka novel. ","answer":"ANSWER: Japanese internment during World War II [prompt on World War II] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] This author couldn’t drive into Canada because his poodle, Charley, didn’t have the right shots. He wrote The Grapes of Wrath. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Steinbeck "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name these figures that are known as malak in Islam. Two of these figures named Munkar and Nakir ask three questions during barzakh. ","answer":"ANSWER: angels [prompt on mala’ikah] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Munkar and Nakir’s questions can only be answered correctly if one truly believes in this Islamic creed, which is one of the Five Pillars of Islam. It states that there is no God but God, and that Muhammad is God’s prophet. ","answer":"ANSWER: shahada [or aš-šahādah] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Reciting the shahada is one of the Five Pillars of Islam along with salat, which requires adherents to pray five times a day facing this holiest city of Islam. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mecca [or Makkah] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this King of Norway who died fighting for the throne of England against Harold Godwinson at the Battle of Stamford Bridge. ","answer":"ANSWER: Harald Hardrada [or Harald III; prompt on Harald] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] As a young man, Harald served with the Varangian Guard in this city as a personal bodyguard to Emperor Michael IV. This city was the capital of the Byzantine Empire. ","answer":"ANSWER: Constantinople "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Having amassed significant wealth from his Varangian loot, Harald stored it in this city, which was ruled by his ally Yaroslav the Wise. A polity based in this city was ruled by the Rurik dynasty. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kiev [or Kievan Rus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this country where Bo Bardi designed the Sao Paulo Museum of Art. Lucio Costa and Oscar Niemeyer designed this country’s capital city. ","answer":"ANSWER: Brazil "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Bo Bardi published an influential architectural magazine of this name during the 1950s. For Montreal’s Expo 67, Moshe Safdie tried to “reinvent the apartment” with a prefabricated modular housing complex of this name. ","answer":"ANSWER: Habitat [or Habitat 67] [10] 4 blue pilotis support a residence of this name Bo Bardi designed for herself. Ludwig Mies van der Rohe’s Farnsworth House inspired the choice of material used for Philip Johnson’s personal residence, which has this name. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name these events that are often accompanied by coronal mass ejections. Unlike coronal mass ejections, they emit electromagnetic radiation rather than mass. ","answer":"ANSWER: solar flares [or sun flares; prompt on flares] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Solar flares may interact with the Earth’s magnetosphere to produce these colorful displays of light in the sky, which are termed “borealis” if they occur near the North Pole. ","answer":"ANSWER: auroras [or aurorae; accept aurora borealis] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Independently of Richard Hodgson, this British amateur astronomer made the first observation of a solar flare in 1859 by studying a massive geomagnetic storm that bears his name. ","answer":"ANSWER: Richard Christopher Carrington [or Carrington event; or Carrington storm] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this substance that also titles a novel by Patrick Süskind in which Jean-Baptiste Grenouille, an orphan in 18th-century France, begins murdering pubescent girls to create a perfect variety of it. ","answer":"ANSWER: perfume [or Jitterbug Perfume or Perfume: The Story of a Murderer or Das Parfum] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] The narrator remarks “the smell and taste of things remain poised a long time, like souls” after one of these food items triggers involuntary memories at the opening of Marcel Proust’s In Search of Lost Time. ","answer":"ANSWER: a madeleine [prompt on “cake” or “cookie”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Gustav von Aschenbach detects the strong smell of disinfectant and learns of the cholera epidemic plaguing this Italian city in a Thomas Mann novel. ","answer":"ANSWER: Venice [or Death in Venice or Der Tod in Venedig] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this sitcom that won a GLAAD Award for an episode in which characters shout “not that there’s anything wrong with that!” to deny being gay. This show spawned the catchphrases “no soup for you” and “Serenity Now!” ","answer":"ANSWER: Seinfeld "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Michael Scott vows to end “100,000 years of being weirded out by gays” in “Gay Witch Hunt,” an episode of this sitcom that ends with Michael kissing Oscar Martinez in Dunder Mifflin Scranton’s conference room. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Of ice "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] In the “Puppy Episode” of her namesake sitcom, Ellen DeGeneres realizes that she is gay while speaking to a therapist played by this woman. In 30 Rock, Liz Lemon mistakes a teenage girl for this woman after mixing white wine with anti-anxiety pills. ","answer":"ANSWER: Oprah Winfrey [accept either] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this World War I campaign, in which bloody landings at ANZAC Cove forged a sense of national identity for Australians and New Zealanders. Mustafa Kemal commanded Turkish forces during this campaign. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gallipoli Campaign [or the Dardanelles Campaign; or the Battle of Çanakkale] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] This country memorializes the Battle of Vimy Ridge, the first time all four divisions of its WWI corps fought side-by-side. On its home front, Robert Borden dealt with a conscription crisis among Francophones in Quebec. ","answer":"ANSWER: Canada "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] During World War I, this South African field marshal occupied German South West Africa and chased Paul von Lettow-Vorbeck around East Africa. This United Party prime minister’s 1948 electoral defeat ushered in the apartheid era. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jan Smuts "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this American scientist. He names a butterfly-shaped attractor that came from his work in modeling atmospheric convection. ","answer":"ANSWER: Edward Lorenz [do not accept or prompt on “Lorentz”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] The Lorenz equations are known for having solutions that exhibit this phenomenon. This phenomenon, the extreme sensitivity of a system to initial conditions, is exhibited by the butterfly effect. ","answer":"ANSWER: chaos theory "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] One of these systems attached to another’s end is also known for exhibiting chaotic behavior. These systems, which are made of a weight suspended from a pivot, are examples of simple harmonic oscillators. ","answer":"ANSWER: (double) pendulums "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this Haitian author who included “Between the Pool and the Gardenias” in her collection Krik? Krak!. She chronicled Sophie Caco’s journey from Haiti to New York and back again in Breath, Eyes, Memory. ","answer":"ANSWER: Edwidge Danticat "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Alejo Carpentier wrote about a Haitian one of these people named Ti Noel in The Kingdom of this World. Harriet Jacobs and Olaudah Equiano both wrote narratives about their time as these people. ","answer":"ANSWER: slaves "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Aime Cesaire set his adaptation of this Shakespeare play in Haiti. Cesaire emphasized this play’s racial subtext by casting Prospero as white and Caliban as black. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Tempest "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this French pianist and music teacher whose students included Philip Glass, Quincy Jones, and Eliot Carter. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nadia Boulanger "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] During her tour of the United States, Boulanger premiered a Symphony for Organ and Orchestra composed by this former student of hers. He composed the ballets Rodeo and Appalachian Spring. ","answer":"ANSWER: Aaron Copland "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Boulanger encouraged her student Astor Piazzolla to compose music for this dance genre instead of classical music. This partner dance form originated in Argentina and Uruguay. ","answer":"ANSWER: tango "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"9. Earlier in its history, this island housed men like Whitey Bulger and Robert Stroud, who was known as its “birdman.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Alcatraz Island "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Dee Brown, who participated in the occupation of Alcatraz, wrote a history of the American West titled Bury My Heart at this location. Over 300 Lakota Sioux were killed in a 1890 massacre at this South Dakota location. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wounded Knee [or Bury My Heart at Wounded Knee] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] This activist chronicled America’s history of broken treaties and forced Indian removals in A Century of Dishonor. Her novel Ramona is often credited with reigniting interest in California’s Spanish missions. ","answer":"ANSWER: Helen Hunt Jackson "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this queen of Connacht from the Ulster Cycle. In some accounts, this woman’s lover Fergus protects her with a shield as she fills a moat with urine. ","answer":"ANSWER: Queen Medb [mave] [or Queen Maeve; or Queen Medba] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Queen Medb was jealous of one of these animals, which she attacked in a “raid” at Cooley. In Greek mythology, Io turns into a white type of this animal after being courted by Zeus. ","answer":"ANSWER: cows [or cattle; accept synonyms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] This warrior single-handedly opposed Medb’s army in the Cattle Raid of Cooley. This son of Lugh wields a barbed spear known as Gae Bulg. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cuchulainn [cuh-HOO-linn] [or Setanta] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this title character of Yann Martel’s most famous novel. This adherent of Christianity, Islam, and Hinduism spends 227 days adrift in the Pacific Ocean with a tiger named Richard Parker. ","answer":"ANSWER: Piscine Patel [accept either underlined name; or Life of Pi] [10] “One: A Poem” are the first words of this poem when it is translated into Pilish [“PILE-ish”], a language in which the number of letters in each word of a poem spell out the digits of pi. This Edgar Allan Poe poem features a bird that croaks “nevermore.” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] A poet from this country wrote an ode to the “admirable number pi,” but is better known for “Love at First Sight.”Another of its writers analyzed the effect of Stalinism on this country in The Captive Mind. ","answer":"ANSWER: Poland (the first sentence refers to Wislawa Szymborska, while the second refers to Czesław Miłosz) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this process, in which molecules of a liquid or gas adhere to a solid surface and form a thin film on it. ","answer":"ANSWER: adsorption [do not accept or prompt on “absorption”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] The degree of adsorption can depend on this property, which quantifies how easily a surface can maintain contact with a liquid. Surfaces with a large value of this property usually form a very small contact angle with water. ","answer":"ANSWER: wettability [accept word forms; accept hydrophilicity and word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Liquids with a high wettability often have a low value for this cohesive property. This property, which is reduced by surfactants, is what allows insects to walk on water. ","answer":"ANSWER: surface tension [or surface energy; prompt on gamma] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name this scholastic philosopher who expressed his disdain for lazily contradictory theology in Sic et Non. ","answer":"ANSWER: Peter Abelard [or Pierre Abélard] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Peter Abelard was a philosopher from this modern-day country, where another scholastic philosopher, Peter Lombard, taught at the cathedral school of Notre Dame. ","answer":"ANSWER: France "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Abelard’s infamous quarrels with other theologians include one with a man of this name from Laon. Another philosopher of this name was the archbishop of Canterbury and made an ontological proof of God’s existence. ","answer":"ANSWER: Anselm [or Saint Anselm of Canterbury or Anselm of Laon] Tiebreaker. The “Arctic” type of these animals is the most prominent predator of the lemming. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Name these animals whose “true” genus also includes a long-eared species called the fennec. ","answer":"ANSWER: foxes [or Vulpes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] Like wolves, foxes are in the family Canidae, which comes from the Latin for these animals. ","answer":"ANSWER: dogs "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"E","question":"[10] The red fox has been labeled as a highly damaging invasive species in this country, whose other invasive species include the cane toad. ","answer":"ANSWER: Australia"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"1. Speakers of this city’s Cheli dialect participated in a 1970s counterculture movement known as this city’s “Movida.” This city’s Carabanchel Prison was used to house political prisoners during the rule of a dictator who erected the Valley of the Fallen in one of this city’s suburbs. A set of Accords signed in this European capital city handed over control of Western Sahara to Morocco and Mauritania. The 1975 coronation of Juan Carlos I in this city marked the end of a dictatorship ruled by the Falange Party. For 10 points, name this capital city that served as the base of Francisco Franco’s regime. ","answer":"ANSWER: Madrid "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"2. Description acceptable. In a play set during this historical event, Ned Weeks pressures Felix Turner to write an article about this event for the New York Times. The nurse Belize treats people impacted by this historical event in a play that ends with the characters gathering around the Bethesda Fountain. Randy Shilts’ And The Band Played On is about this event, which, in another play, leads to the death of a man who is visited by Ethel Rosenberg’s ghost in his hospital room. In that play, Roy Cohn fears that his death during this disease outbreak will reveal his homosexuality. For 10 points, name this epidemic central to Tony Kushner’s Angels in America. ","answer":"ANSWER: the AIDS epidemic [or acquired immunodeficiency syndrome; accept the AIDS crisis; accept HIV in the place of AIDS; accept any answer that mentions AIDS or HIV] (the play described in the first line is Larry Kramer’s The Normal Heart) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"3. Sir James Edward Smith founded a society named for this man, where papers by Alfred Wallace were read at the first public exposition on the theory of evolution. The 17 “apostles” of this man travelled with explorers like James Cook to help him gather plant specimens from around the world to study at Uppsala. Cladistics is an extension of a system developed by this man, which splits the biological world into plants, animals and minerals. This man’s book Systema Naturae helped found the modern field of taxonomy. For 10 points, name this Swedish naturalist who popularized binomial nomenclature. ","answer":"ANSWER: Carolus Linnaeus [or Carl Linnaeus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"4. In 2017, Ai Weiwei protested U.S border control by placing a giant Gilded Cage in this place. A memorial in this location was designed by Bruce Kelly, who fought to preserve this place. A controversial photo taken here depicts an exasperated child holding a toy hand grenade, and was shot by Diane Arbus. Bright orange structures were installed throughout this location for Jean-Claude and Christo’s 2005 installation The Gates. This place, home to one of three of Cleopatra’s Needles, was designed by landscape architects Calvert Vaux and Frederick Law Olmsted. For 10 points, name this public space bordering the Met and Guggenheim, a large park in New York City. ","answer":"ANSWER: Central Park [prompt on New York City; prompt on NYC; prompt on Manhattan] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"5. A text by this philosopher distinguishes between two forms of self-love by tracing one back to village music contests. That text by this philosopher defines the distinction between man and animal as “perfectibility,” or the ability of man to learn by observing others. This philosopher argued that private property was created when the first man fenced in a piece of land to declare it his. This author of Discourse on Inequality distinguished between the government and the “sovereign of the general will” in a book that declares that “man is born free, and everywhere he is in chains.” For 10 points, name this philosopher of The Social Contract. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jean-Jacques Rousseau "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"6. The narrator of this short story observes “the Rubicon passed, one lends himself to the occasion” after a man requests a glass of wine for his passed-out wife. This story, which is the second entry in Evenings at Medan, begins with a stagecoach journey to Tôtes, during which the protagonist surprises her fellow passengers by sharing a picnic basket. Cornudet [“cor-noo-DAY”] whistles “La Marseillaise” [“mar-say-AZE”] at the end of this story, whose title character weeps after a group of nobles shame her into sleeping with a Prussian officer. For 10 points, name this story about the prostitute Elisabeth Rousset [“roo-SAY”], written by Guy de Maupassant. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Ball of Fat” [or “Boule de Suif”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"7. In one religious tradition, this ceremony is assisted by a ragyapa, who helps a priest burn juniper incense. Timothy Leary wrote a “manual” based on a Nyingma text usually read at these ceremonies, which describes six transitory states of consciousness called bardos. In one tradition, these ceremonies are performed on a raised structure divided into three concentric circles, known as Towers of Silence. The traditional “sky” form of this ceremony practiced in Tibet originated when priests could not find enough firewood to perform cremation. For 10 points, name this type of ceremony at which Buddhists might read The Tibetan Book of the Dead to console a deceased person’s family. ","answer":"ANSWER: funerals [or burials; accept sky burials; prompt on descriptive answers that mention death or the treatment of dead bodies] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"8. Jones and Mueller matrices can be used to calculate how this property changes as light propagates through a system. As light passes through a magnetic field, it undergoes a rotational change in this property in the Faraday effect. Birefringent materials are used to make half-wave plates, which can reverse the sign of this property. A light ray not having this property will gain this property when approaching a surface at Brewster’s angle. This property, whose varieties include linear and circular, is used by some sunglasses to reduce glare. For 10 points, name this property which can describes the orientation of a light wave’s oscillations. ","answer":"ANSWER: polarization [accept word forms, but do not accept “polarizability”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"9. One person with this title names an “Assurance” given to Patriarch Sophronius of Jerusalem. Another person of this title rejected a woman’s claim to inheriting Fadak. The first holder of this title launched the Ridda Wars to unify his domain. A holder of this title defeated a Byzantine army commanded by Vahan the Armenian in a battle fought near the Yarmouk River. While praying, one holder of this title was killed with a poison-tipped sword wielded by a Kharijite. The First Fitna began after the assassination of one holder of this title, Uthman, who was succeeded by Ali. For 10 points, give this title of four “Rightly-Guided” leaders of Islam. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rashidun Caliph [or Rightly-Guided Caliph] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"0. This material is traditionally used by the artisan sculptors of Dongyang, China. In Greek acrolithic sculptures, body parts were sculpted from marble, while the torso and drapery were made from this material. Mary holds a particularly emaciated Christ in a Pieta sculpted from this material found in Röttgen, Germany. A technique utilizing this material was used to print the ukiyo-e of Hiroshige and Hokusai. Thunderbird is often depicted in tall sculptures of this material created by the Haida and Tlingit tribes of the Pacific Northwest. For 10 points, name this material used for the majority of African sculpture, as well as totem poles. ","answer":"ANSWER: wood "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"1. Lapis lazuli owes its color to an anion made of three atoms of this element. This element can be extracted from salt domes through a process that uses superheated water and three concentric tubes. The most common allotrope of this element has eight atoms in a puckered ring. The Claus process recovers this element from natural gas production. This element, which is found with lead in galena, can be industrially extracted using the Frasch process. Mercaptans and thiols are so named because they contain atoms of this element, which lies under oxygen on the periodic table. For 10 points, name this nonmetal that often forms compounds that smell like rotten eggs. ","answer":"ANSWER: sulfur [or S before mentioned] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"2. A boy in this novel uses his grandmother’s cane to kill a rattlesnake, impressing Otto Fuchs. Though he lives with his conservative grandparents, the narrator of this novel parties at the Owl Club with Lena Lingard. The violin-playing father of this novel’s protagonist kills himself in a barn after a difficult winter; later in this novel, the protagonist is impregnated by Larry Donovan, who abandons her. Twenty years after the main events of the novel, its narrator visits Anton Cuzak’s family in Black Hawk, Nebraska. For 10 points, name this novel about Jim Burden’s experiences growing up with the title Czech immigrant, written by Willa Cather. ","answer":"ANSWER: My Ántonia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"3. The term “American exceptionalism” was first used to attack a leader of this organization named Jay Lovestone. Harry Hay split off from this organization to found the pro-LGBT Mattachine Society. Members of this organization were denied passports under the McCarran Act and prosecuted for violating the Smith Act. At a speech in Wheeling, West Virginia, a politician claimed to possess a list of 205 State Department employees associated with this political party. Alleged members of this organization were forced to testify before the House Un-American Activities Committee. For 10 points, name this American political party targeted by Joseph McCarthy during the Second Red Scare. ","answer":"ANSWER: Communist Party of the United States of America [or CPUSA] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"4. In the early 20th century, perennialists like Robert Maynard Hutchins advocated a normative approach to this field, in contrast to the “progressive” theories of this discipline favored by thinkers like Rudolf Steiner. The “banking model” was critiqued by a Brazilian theorist in this field named Paulo Freire. John Dewey emphasized the role of experience in a book whose title pairs this field with Democracy. Horace Mann’s reforms in Massachusetts were inspired by innovations made in this field by Maria Montessori. For 10 points, pedagogy is the study of what process by which students acquire knowledge? ","answer":"ANSWER: education [or learning; or teaching; or pedagogy until it is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"5. A June New Yorker article by Jelani Cobb uses this company’s buildings to illustrate Elijah Anderson’s concept of “white space.” In 2015, this company was widely mocked for its “#RaceTogether” [“hashtag race together”] campaign, which encouraged its employees to start conversations with customers about civil rights This company instituted mandatory racial bias training for all of its US employees after two black men were mistakenly arrested for trespassing at one of its stores in Philadelphia. This company pledged to hire 10,000 refugees under the leadership of its former CEO Howard Schultz. For 10 points, name Seattle-based coffee shop chain. ","answer":"ANSWER: Starbucks Coffee "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"6. One poem in this collection asks the reader to “choose” between “a shade, in which to sing” and “a grave, on which to rest from singing.” Another poem from this collection tells the reader to “gather the north flowers to complete the south.” A “mystic shape” holds the speaker of one poem in this collection before revealing itself to be “not Death, but Love;” the speaker of that poem from this collection reflects how “Theocritus had sung / of the sweet years.” The writer of this collection entreats the reader to “call me by my pet name” and pledges to “count the ways” she “loves thee.” For 10 points, name this poetry collection by Elizabeth Barrett Browning. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sonnets from the Portuguese "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"7. This city’s general Pagondus capitalized on the enemy army’s friendly fire to win the Battle of Delium. A statue of a lion commemorates this city’s defeat in a battle at which a general remarked that this city’s soldiers “never did or suffered anything unseemly.” As a youth, Philip II lived in this city as a hostage of its ruler Pelopidas. This capital of the Boeotian [“BEE-ocean”] League freed the Messenian helots from Sparta under its king Epaminondas. A battalion of gay lovers known as this city’s “Sacred Band” died at the Battle of Chaeronea [“kay-roh-NEE-uh”]. For 10 points, name this “seven-gated” city legendarily ruled by Cadmus and Oedipus. ","answer":"ANSWER: Thebes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"8. This structure is the defining characteristic separating the fish in subclass Dipnoi [“dip-NOH-eye”] from all other extant species of Sarcopterygii [“sar-cop-TARE-uh-jee”]. Although it is evolutionarily unrelated to this structure, arachnids possess stacks of hemolymph-filled tissue known as the “book” form of this organ. This organ in terrestrial mammals is homologous to the swim bladders used by many species of fish to control buoyancy. In humans, its parenchymal [“pah-REN-kuh-mull”] tissue contains hollow cavities called alveoli, which are connected to bronchioles. For 10 points, name this vital organ that conducts the function of gas exchange within land-dwelling vertebrates. ","answer":"ANSWER: lungs [or book lungs; or lungfish] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"9. These people had a pantheon composed of the seventy sons of Bull El, known to them as King Father of Years. These people shared a group of stories named for the “Cycle” of one of their gods, which is written in the Ugaritic language. This group of people is said to be descended from a man who was cursed after seeing his father Noah naked. This group of people originated worship of Baal, Dagon, and Asherah and believed in an underworld known as Sheol. For 10 points, name this group of people, who are wiped out by the Israelites in the Book of Joshua. ","answer":"ANSWER: Canaanites [accept Phoenicians until stated] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"0. In an opera by this composer, a man sings “Come away, fellow sailors” to lead a short dance before a character plots to cause a sea storm in the aria “Our next motion.” A chorus sings “With drooping wings, ye cupids come” at the end of a scene in an opera by this composer set in a grove. A character in an opera by this composer tells her servant she is “prest with torment” in the aria “Ah, Belinda.” This composer worked with the librettist Nahum Tate on an opera that includes the aria “When I am laid in earth.” For 10 points, name this Baroque composer of the first major English-language opera, Dido and Aeneas. ","answer":"ANSWER: Henry Purcell Tiebreaker. On the advice of a monk, a holder of this office screamed “victory!” to overcome his cowardice while defending his country against an invasion. One holder of this office reconciled the rival claims of the Northern and Southern Courts. Holders of this office required nobles to live in the capital every other year with the alternate attendance policy. Douglas MacArthur informally held this title in recognition of his time as military governor of a certain occupied country. This office was dissolved in the Boshin War following the victory of Emperor Meiji’s forces. For 10 points, name this military office that governed Japan on behalf of the nominal emperor. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this country that experienced extreme hyperinflation under a leader who was overthrown in 2017, Robert Mugabe. This country was formerly known as Rhodesia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Republic of Zimbabwe "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] This man lead Rhodesia’s white minority government during the Rhodesian Bush War. He consented to hand power over to Abel Muzorewa in the Lancaster House Agreement. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ian Smith "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] In Operation Murambatsvina, or “Operation Move the Rubbish,” Mugabe ordered the Zimbabwean government to destroy these locations. These places are known as favelas in Brazil ","answer":"ANSWER: slums [or shanty towns; prompt on neighborhoods or towns] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this sun deity. This son of Viracocha had his cult expanded by Pachacuti and was married to the Moon goddess Mama Killa. ","answer":"ANSWER: Inti "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Inti was the major god of this civilization, which also worshipped spirits known as Apu. The Andean Condor was considered sacred by this large South American civilization. ","answer":"ANSWER: Inca Empire [or Incan Empire] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] The Inca creator god Viracocha created humanity from these objects. In Greek mythology, Pyrrha and Deucalion threw some of these objects over their shoulders to create humanity after the Great Flood. ","answer":"ANSWER: stones [or rocks] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this dimensionless quantity, which can quantify the strength of a bond. It is equal to 2 for a double bond. ","answer":"ANSWER: bond order [prompt on “BO”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] The aforementioned formula to calculate bond order comes from this theory, which describes chemical bonding and electron positions in molecules using bonding, nonbonding, and antibonding interactions. ","answer":"ANSWER: molecular orbital theory [or MO theory; or Hund-Mulliken theory) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Molecular orbital theory is commonly used to model these bonds. Unlike ionic bonds, these bonds involve the sharing of electron pairs between atoms. ","answer":"ANSWER: covalent bonds [accept dative bonds; accept coordinate (covalent) bonds] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this religious figure. In an another chiaroscuro painting by the same artist, a beam of light emerging from the upper-right shines on this bearded figure, who points at himself. ","answer":"ANSWER: St. Matthew "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] This Italian Baroque master and notoriously aggressive street brawler painted The Calling of St. Matthew. ","answer":"ANSWER: Michelangelo Merisi da Caravaggio "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Caravaggio modeled Christ’s hand in The Calling of St. Matthew after the pose of an arm in this painting. Gynecologist Frank Meshberger is among those who argue that the right portion of this painting depicts a human brain. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Creation of Adam [prompt on the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this author who defended Romanticism in the preface to his play Cromwell. This playwright of Hernani was inspired by Guernsey’s fisherman to write Toilers of the Sea. ","answer":"ANSWER: Victor Hugo "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] William Wordsworth gave his own defense of Romanticism in his preface to this poetry collection, which contains Wordsworth’s “Lines written above Tintern Abbey.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Lyrical Ballads "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Wordsworth and Hugo’s prefaces are collected in a Book of Prefaces by Alasdair Gray, a contemporary author from this country. This country’s greatest poet Robert Burns wrote an ode to a “lassie” from this country’s Highlands region. ","answer":"ANSWER: Scotland [prompt on United Kingdom or U.K] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this number of major political parties in America. Each individual state is granted this number of seats in the United States Senate. ","answer":"ANSWER: two [or two-party system] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] According to Robert Michels, a democracy inevitably devolves into of these systems, in which power is held by a small number of people. Michels’ theory is known as the “iron law” of these systems. ","answer":"ANSWER: oligarchy "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Michels belonged to an Italian sociological school devoted to the study of these people. A 1956 C. Wright Mills book posits that these people are the answer to the question “Who, after all, runs America?” ","answer":"ANSWER: elites [or The Power Elite; prompt on descriptive answers like rich people] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name these rules that determine which electronic transitions between orbitals are allowed in a molecule. ","answer":"ANSWER: selection rules "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] The Laporte selection rule only applies to centrosymmetric molecules, which means that they have a “center” of this process. This process involves taking a point at (x,y,z) [“x y z”] and moving it to (-x,-y,-z) [“negative x negative y negative z”]. ","answer":"ANSWER: inversion center "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Selection rules are relevant to this spectroscopic technique, which analyzes bond vibration. This technique is named after a region of the electromagnetic spectrum with wavelength longer than visible light. ","answer":"ANSWER: infrared spectroscopy [or IR; accept infrared radiation] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this field of study practiced by Colin McPhee. A pioneer of this field named Alan Lomax used the Cantometrics system and visited Angola Prison to make recordings of Huddie “Leadbelly” Ledbetter. ","answer":"ANSWER ethnomusicology [prompt on musicology; prompt on ethnography; prompt on anthropology; prompt on folklore] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Both Jaap Kunst and Colin McPhee studied the gamelan percussion ensembles of this country. Wayang shadow puppets often perform to gamelan music on this country’s islands of Java and Bali. ","answer":"ANSWER: Republic of Indonesia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Lomax made recordings of Leadbelly at Angola Prison in this state, which is the birthplace of zydeco music. The Preservation Hall brass band hails from this state, as did the members of the Original Dixieland Jass Band. ","answer":"ANSWER: Louisiana "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this monologue performed by the sad fool Jaques. In this speech, Jacques claims that life ends “sans teeth, sans eyes, sans taste, sans everything” in “second childishness and mere oblivion.” You can provide either the common name or the first few words of it. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Seven Ages of Man speech [or the “All the world’s a stage” speech] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] The “Seven Ages of Man” monologue is delivered in this play set in the Forest of Arden. Rosalind disguises herself as a shepherd to woo Orlando in this Shakespeare play. ","answer":"ANSWER: As You Like It "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] As You Like It is an example of this Shakespearean genre. Usually contrasted with tragedies and histories, plays in this genre tend to end with weddings. ","answer":"ANSWER: comedy [or comedies] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this first president of the French Fifth Republic. This general became a national hero for his leadership of the Free French during World War II. ","answer":"ANSWER: Charles de Gaulle "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Student protests and a general workers’ strike in May of this year nearly brought down De Gaulle’s government. During the crisis of this year, de Gaulle briefly fled France to hide in Baden-Baden, Germany. ","answer":"ANSWER: 1968 [prompt on 68] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] De Gaulle’s flight to Baden-Baden soured his relationship with this prime minister, who negotiated the Grenelle Agreements to try and end the crisis. ","answer":"ANSWER: Georges Pompidou "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this piece that uses the melody from the song “La Mantovana” as its main theme. This movement of a larger work depicts a moonlight “dance of the nymphs” and shares its melody with the Israeli national anthem. ","answer":"ANSWER: Die Moldau [or Vltava; or The Moldau; prompt on Ma vlast] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Die Moldau appears alongside pieces depicting Sarka and Blanik in Ma vlast, a set of nationalistic symphonic poems by this composer. He also composed The Bartered Bride. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bedřich Smetana "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Má vlast pays tribute to the Bohemian folklore of this modern-day country, Smetana's homeland. Smetana composed patriotic marches to celebrate an uprising in this country’s city of Prague. ","answer":"ANSWER: Czech Republic [or Czechia] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name these chargeless, nearly massless leptons that rarely interact with matter. About 65 billion of them pass through each square centimeter of Earth per second. ","answer":"ANSWER: neutrinos "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Like neutrino detection, the detection of these ripples in spacetime by observatories such as LIGO are advancements in “multi-messenger” astronomy. ","answer":"ANSWER: gravitational waves [or gravity waves or gravitational radiation; prompt on waves] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Neutrinos emitted from a supernova were first directly recorded with the occurrence of SN 1987A in this Local Group system. After the Andromeda Galaxy, it is one of the closest galaxies to the Milky Way. ","answer":"ANSWER: Large Magellanic Cloud [prompt on Magellanic Cloud] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this novel about Newland Archer’s affair with Countess Ellen Olenska. In this novel, Newland’s plan to run away with the Countess is foiled when his wife May Welland becomes pregnant. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Age of Innocence "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] This author of The Age of Innocence wrote about the title Starkfield resident’s affection for Mattie Silver in Ethan Frome. ","answer":"ANSWER: Edith Wharton "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] In Ethan Frome, Ethan and Mattie attempt to commit suicide in this manner. Ethan repeats “I know we can fetch it” while carrying out this action before seeing his wife Zenobia’s face. ","answer":"ANSWER: sledding into a tree [accept any answer mentioning sledding] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this indigenous people that resides in the northern regions of Norway, Sweden and Finland. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sami [accept Lapps or Laplanders, but inform the player that these terms are considered derogatory] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Traditionally, the Sami people reside in saavu huts which are made from the hides of this animal. The poem “A Visit from St. Nicholas” spread the legend that these animals pull Santa Claus’ sleigh. ","answer":"ANSWER: reindeer [or caribou] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] The majority of Russia’s Sami population live on this peninsula, which separates the White Sea from the Barents Sea. Its largest city is Murmansk. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kola Peninsula "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this body of water named for a marooned explorer who captained the Half Moon. The drainage basin of this body of water was awarded to its namesake company as Rupert’s Land. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hudson Bay [or Hudson’s Bay Company] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] The Hudson’s Bay Company primarily traded for this commodity, which it harvested from beavers. ","answer":"ANSWER: fur [or pelts; or equivalents] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] These mixed-race Canadian people descend from the union of fur traders and First Nations women. After Canada purchased Rupert’s Land, Louis Riel led a revolt of these people. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Métis [prompt on descriptive answers, such as mixed-race Canadians or half-Indian Canadians] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this contemporary American philosopher who used a thought experiment involving an “unconscious violinist” to critique the “right to life” argument in her paper “A Defense of Abortion.”. ","answer":"ANSWER: Judith (Jarvis) Thomson "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Thomson added a “fat man” to this popular thought experiment, in which a person can save five people from an out-of-control vehicle if they redirect the vehicle to hit someone else. ","answer":"ANSWER: the trolley problem [accept any equivalents that include trolley] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Judith Thomson is a prominent thinker within the “virtue” field of this branch of philosophy, which attempts to determine right from wrong. ","answer":"ANSWER: ethics [or moral philosophy; accept virtue ethics] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this Christian holy day that derives its most common name from its commemoration of the foot washing of Jesus and his apostles. ","answer":"ANSWER: Maundy Thursday [or Holy Thursday; or Covenant Thursday; or Great and Holy Thursday; or Sheer Thursday; or Thursday of Mysteries] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Maundy Thursday occurs on the Thursday before this major Christian holiday whose date was historically set by the Computus. This holiday celebrates Jesus’ resurrection from the dead. ","answer":"ANSWER: Easter [or Pascha; or Resurrection Sunday] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] A large, white one of these objects is typically blessed and used every year at Easter. A cross, the letters alpha and omega, and the current year are typically displayed on that object of this kind. ","answer":"ANSWER: a candle "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this night. It is the night after Dunyazade attends her sister’s wedding to King Shahryar and the book those characters appear in ends. ","answer":"ANSWER: the 1002nd night [prompt on descriptive answers like “the last night of the Arabian Nights” that do not specifically mention the number 1002; do not accept or prompt on the 1001st night] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] In the 1001 Nights, this woman puts off her marriage to King Shahryar by telling him a story each night. ","answer":"ANSWER: Scheherazade [10] 1,001 children are born at midnight on Indian Indepence Day in this author’s novel Midnight’s Children. This author was forced to go into hiding after he received a fatwa for his novel The Satanic Verses. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this molecule which tags proteins in the Golgi apparatus that are destined for lysosomes. ","answer":"ANSWER: mannose-6-phosphate [or M6P; or man-6-P] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] This other lysosomal storage disease is caused by a mutation in HEXA [“HECK-sah”] genes and results in the buildup of GM2 gangliosides in neurons. It is prevalent among Cajuns and Ashkenazi Jews. ","answer":"ANSWER: Tay-Sachs disease "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Enzymes responsible for lysosomal function are synthesized by this organelle’s “rough” variety, which is studded by numerous ribosomes. ","answer":"ANSWER: rough endoplasmic reticulum [or the ER] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"5. An iconic photograph depicts a line of evacuees attempting to board a small helicopter on the roof of this city’s American embassy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Saigon [or Ho Chi Minh City] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] While US troops began withdrawing from South Vietnam during Nixon’s presidency, this president was in office during the fall of Saigon. He became president after Nixon resigned during the Watergate scandal. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gerald Ford [or Leslie Lynch King] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] This politician allowed the CIA to operate out of Saigon’s US embassy during his time as President Kennedy’s Ambassador to South Vietnam. He was Richard Nixon’s running mate in the 1960 presidential election. ","answer":"ANSWER: Henry Cabot Lodge Jr. [or Henry Cabot Lodge II; prompt on Henry Cabot Lodge; do not accept or prompt on Henry Cabot Lodge Sr.] Tiebreaker. To prove that these numbers exist, Joseph Liouville constructed a decimal consisting of ones in digit places that correspond to factorials, and zeros otherwise. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name these numbers that are not the solution to any polynomial with rational coefficients. In addition to being irrational, pi and e are examples of these numbers. ","answer":"ANSWER: transcendental numbers "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] The “common” form of this operation yields a transcendental number if it is not applied to a power of 10. [Read slowly] Given a base b and a number x, this operation gives a such that b to the a equals x. ","answer":"ANSWER: common logarithm [or base-10 logarithm] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] The seventh member of this set of mathematical problems asks whether a to the b will be transcendental if a is not 0 or 1 and b is irrational. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hilbert’s problems EXTRA One of this man’s films, loosely adapted from Dostoevsky’s The Possessed, centers on a group of Maoist university students who attempt to assassinate the Soviet Minister of Culture. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Name this founder of the Dziga Vertov Group. This frequent collaborator of Anna Karina featured an intertitle about “The Children of Marx and Coca-Cola” in a film whose title translates to Masculine Feminine. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jean-Luc Godard "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Godard was a pioneer in a radical French film movement of the 60s that rejected the “Tradition of Quality” and was described by this two-word name. It was championed by André Bazin’s Cahiers du Cinéma magazine. ","answer":"ANSWER: French New Wave [or La Nouvelle Vague] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"F","question":"[10] Michel, the protagonist of Godard’s Breathless, loves to mimic the style of this American actor. He starred in films like The Big Sleep, The Maltese Falcon, and Casablanca. ","answer":"ANSWER: Humphrey Bogart"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"1. This location’s “Fence of Shame” was torn down by high schoolers during a 1964 riot that is now commemorated on Martyrs’ Day. Georges Clemenceau and Gustave Eiffel were implicated in a late 19th-century scandal involving Ferdinand de Lesseps’ [“less-SAY’S”] attempt to build a project at this location. Walter Reed’s research on yellow fever was used to lower death rates at this location during an undertaking that was enabled by the Hay-Bunau-Varilla treaty. This location was released from American control in 1999 under the terms of the Carter-Torrijos [“tor-REE-hos”] treaty. For 10 points, name this waterway that bisects North America and South America. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Panama Canal [or the Panama Canal Zone or the Isthmus of Panama] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"2. A group of realist artists from this country refused to take an exam in the “revolt of the fourteen.” Clement Greenberg’s most famous essay contrasts Picasso’s “avant-garde” Woman with a Fan with the “kitsch” of an artist from this country, who painted They Did Not Expect Him. In another painting by that artist, a group of soldiers from this country laugh as they write a letter to Sultan Mehmed IV. Black Square and Red Square were painted by an artist from this country who used the term “New Realism” to describe his art movement, Suprematism. Barge Haulers on the Volga was painted in, for 10 points, what country where Ilya Repin painted Ivan the Terrible clutching his dead son? ","answer":"ANSWER: Russia [or the USSR; or the Soviet Union] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"3. The night before one of these events, a man writes a poem asking “whither have ye winged your way, ye golden days of my young spring?” Vladimir Nabokov’s translation of a work describes a man “secretly laughing” at one of these events as he approaches “the moment of revenge.” A man earlier compared to Childe Harold arrives late at one of these events that is described in alternating masculine and feminine rhymes. Zaretsky tries to dissuade the title character from participating in one of these events that was caused by his flirting with Olga. Eugene Onegin kills Lensky in, for 10 points, what kind of honorable gunfight? ","answer":"ANSWER: duels [accept word forms; prompt on fight] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"4. Replacing a hydrogen in levodopa with a radioactive isotope of this element helps localize adrenal gland tumors in PET [“pet”] scans. Six atoms of this element are found in a compound that is used as a flux for the refining of bauxite called cryolite. Carbon forms its strongest single covalent bond with this element. Non-stick coatings often have a polymer with carbon and this element known as PTFE. Compounds of carbon, chlorine, and this element were banned by the Montreal Protocol due to contributing to ozone depletion. With a value of 3.94 on the Pauling scale, this element has the greatest electronegativity. For 10 points, name this lightest halogen. ","answer":"ANSWER: fluorine [or F] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"5. One of these creatures lives in a “cottage cheese cottage” in the Marmalade Forest, where he befriends an Albanian boy and learns not to be racist. King John the Presbyter sits on a throne made out of these creatures’ bones in Tad Williams’ Memory, Sorrow and Thorn trilogy. In another series, three of these creatures are kidnapped by Pyat Pree and imprisoned in the House of the Undying. Fighting alongside a Dothraki horde, one of these creatures decimates the combined Tarly and Lannister armies at the Battle of the Goldroad. For 10 points, name these flying creatures that are ridden by Daenerys Targaryen in Game of Thrones. ","answer":"ANSWER: dragons [the first clue refers to “Albi the Racist Dragon” by Flight of the Conchords] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"6. This opera’s overture opens with two foreboding D-minor chords played by every instrument except the trombones. The 22nd of Beethoven’s Diabelli Variations parodies this opera’s opening aria, in which a character complains how “night and day [he slaves] away” for his master. The protagonist of this opera serenades Zerlina in the aria ““Là ci darem la mano.\" In its last scene, the ghost of Il Commendatore shows up at the protagonist’s house to accept his dinner invitation. During this opera’s “Catalogue Aria,” Leporello tells Donna Elvira that his master has seduced 1003 women in Spain alone. For 10 points, name this Mozart opera about a womanizer who is dragged to hell. ","answer":"ANSWER: Don Giovanni "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"7. The genome of this species has been studied extensively by the Swedish biologist Svante Pääbo, who coined the term “leaky replacement” to explain its disappearance. The mother of an individual nicknamed “Denny” belonged to this species, which interbred with the closely-related Denisovan group. A 2013 biomechanical analysis of this species’s anatomy suggested that, contrary to previous belief, its hyoid bones did not preclude spoken language. The early modern Cro-Magnons eventually superseded these hominids. For 10 points, a German valley lends its name to what prominent-browed archaic humans? ","answer":"ANSWER: Neanderthals [or Homo sapiens neanderthalensis; prompt on Homo sapiens] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"8. The protagonist of this novel is told to “ask for Wild Bob” if he’s ever in Cody, Wyoming. When a man in this novel asks “Why me?” his guard responds “Vy anybody?” This novel contains a drawing of a tombstone with the inscription “Everything was beautiful and nothing hurt.” Recurring motifs in this novel include a bird singing “poo-tee-weet” and the statement “so it goes.” The protagonist of this novel is imprisoned with Montana Wildhack in a Tralfamadorian zoo after surviving the firebombing of Dresden. For 10 points, Billy Pilgrim becomes “unstuck in time” in what Kurt Vonnegut novel? ","answer":"ANSWER: Slaughterhouse-Five or The Children's Crusade: A Duty-Dance with Death "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"3. The chorus of another song associated with this holiday repeats a word that means “it would have been enough,” “Dayenu.” A child asks “why is this night different from all other nights?” in the first of this holiday’s Four Questions. Because chametz foods are forbidden during this holiday, worshippers usually eat an unleavened bread called matzah. For 10 points, name this Jewish holiday that commemorates the Exodus from Egypt. ","answer":"ANSWER: Passover [or Pesach; or Pesah; prompt on seder by asking, “What holiday is that a part of?”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"0. This man had his cousin Tiberius Gemellus executed on the pretense of a conspiracy involving cough medicine. Jealousy of a purple cloak may have prompted this ruler to assassinate Ptolemy of Mauretania and annex his state. To spite the late soothsayer Thrasyllus of Mendes, this man constructed a three-mile pontoon bridge to ride his horse across the Bay of Baiae [“BYE-ay”]. After this man was assassinated, the Praetorian Guard supposedly looked behind a curtain for his successor, Claudius. This son of the popular general Germanicus allegedly attempted to appoint his horse Incitatus as consul. For 10 points, name this Roman emperor known by a nickname meaning “little boot.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Caligula "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"1. In quantum mechanics, the reflection and transmission coefficients are computed by taking the ratios of instances of the “probability” type of this quantity. This quantity is largest near the surface of a conductor due to the skin effect. According to a continuity equation, the rate of change of the charge density is proportional to the divergence of this quantity’s density, which is symbolized J. The magnetic field generated by this quantity is given by the Biot–Savart Law. This quantity, which multiplies voltage to get power, is equal to voltage divided by resistance according to Ohm’s Law. For 10 points, name this quantity equal to the rate of flow of electric charge and measured in amperes. ","answer":"ANSWER: current [or I; accept “flux” before conductor is read, but do not accept or prompt on it afterwards] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"2. A text by this philosopher states that belief in the Absolute Mind permits a “moral holiday,” and offers contrasting “pluralistic” and “monistic” interpretations of Walt Whitman’s “To You.”Another work by this thinker presents the title concept as a “mediating philosophy” between tough-minded and tender-minded philosophers. This philosopher used the term “cash value” to describe practical reasons for holding certain beliefs. With Charles Peirce [“PURSE”], this man developed a branch of philosophy he called “A New Name for Some Old Ways of Thinking.” For 10 points, name this American philosopher of “The Will to Believe” and Pragmatism. ","answer":"ANSWER: William James "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"3. A 2017 novel by an author from this country contrasts the architect Tilo with the transgender woman Anjum, who is forced to move into a graveyard. In a short story, two immigrants from this country “weep for the things they now knew” after a power outage forces them to discuss their stillborn child. This home of the author of The Ministry of Utmost Happiness is the setting of a novel in which the Orangedrink Lemondrink man abuses a boy during a showing of The Sound of Music. The incestuous twins Estha and Rahel live in this country in The God of Small Things. For 10 points, name this home country of Kiran Desai and Arundhati Roy. ","answer":"ANSWER: India [the short story described in the second line is Jhumpa Lahiri’s “A Temporary Matter”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"4. It didn’t occur in Russia, but this event was the subject of an international relief effort led by Fridtjof Nansen and Vidkun Quisling. The planners of this event were assassinated by Dashnak in Operation Nemesis. During this event, the inhabitants of Musa Dagh withstood a fifty-three-day siege. This event was authorized by the Tehcir Law and began on Red Sunday. The victims of this event were forced to march through the Syrian Desert to Deis-ez-Zor. Discussion of this event is a prosecutable offense under Article 301 of the Turkish Penal Code. For 10 points, name this event in which a Christian minority was systematically exterminated by the Ottomans. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Armenian Genocide [or the Armenian Holocaust; prompt on World War I] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"5. This thinker’s concept of a psychosocial moratorium, in which adolescents freely experiment to find their place, influenced psychologist James Marcia. Virtues are contrasted with maladaptations and malignancies in his best-known theory, which he described as the epigenetic principle. This thinker is credited with pioneering the field of psychohistory in books like Gandhi’s Truth and Young Man Luther. He theorized that geriatrics either find integrity or despair, whereas adolescents struggle between identity and role confusion. The term “identity crisis” was introduced by, for 10 points, what psychologist who developed an eight-stage model of psychosocial development? ","answer":"ANSWER: Erik Erikson "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"6. A.C. Bradley’s assertion that this character has a dead son was mocked by L.C. Knights in an essay titled for this character. One of this character’s monologues is the source of the expression “milk of human kindness.” This character urges a man to “screw [his] courage to the sticking place,” and admits that she would have “dash’d the brains out” of an infant in order to keep a promise. While sleepwalking, this character tries to wash her hands and mutters “out, damned spot!” She encourages the Thane of Cawdor to murder and overthrow King Duncan. For 10 points, name this woman who becomes Queen of Scotland in a William Shakespeare play. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lady Macbeth [accept Macbeth until the end of the first sentence, do not accept or prompt afterward] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"7. During the festival of Toxcatl, a human sacrifice would play one of these musical instruments while dressed as Tezcatlipoca. This instrument is associated with a hunchbacked trickster god who uses his detachable phallus to impregnate women. Kokopelli is usually depicted holding one of these instruments, as is Marsyas, who was flayed for claiming he could play this instrument better than Apollo played his lyre. This instrument is associated with a god who chased Syrinx until she turned into a reed, which he then used to build one of these instruments. For 10 points, name this wind instrument played by the satyr Pan. ","answer":"ANSWER: flutes [or reed flutes or pan flutes or pan pipes or aulos] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"8. Jamb statues depicting kings and queens are carved into the entrance of one of these buildings. Two of these buildings are contrasted in a Henry Adams book subtitled A Study of Thirteenth-Century Unity. The name of the Rayonnant style derives from the use of stone tracery to construct “radiating” windows for these buildings. These buildings were divided into sections like the ambulatory, the transept, and the nave. Flying buttresses allowed these buildings to accommodate large, intricate stained-glass windows. For 10 points, tall spires and pointed arches are characteristic of the Gothic style used to construct what buildings, such as Chartres and Notre-Dame? ","answer":"ANSWER: Gothic cathedrals [or chapels; or churches] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"9. The order of a finite field is always one of these numbers raised to a positive integer. The Green-Tao theorem states that arbitrarily long arithmetic sequences can be found in the sequence containing these numbers. For any integer a and one of these numbers n, a to the n is congruent to a modulo n by Fermat’s little theorem. The Goldbach conjecture claims that any even number greater than two can be expressed as the sum of two of these numbers. According to the fundamental theorem of arithmetic, any integer greater than 1 can be expressed as a product of these numbers. For 10 points, name these numbers whose only divisors are one and themselves. ","answer":"ANSWER: prime numbers [or primes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"0. According to legend, the leader of a Native American tribe from this state rejected a treaty proposal by stabbing it with a knife. Two British citizens, Robert Ambrister and James Arbuthnot, were executed for arming this state’s Indians. Billy Bowlegs was shot under a flag of truce in this state after he refused to sign the Treaty of Payne’s Landing. The territory that became this state was ceded to the United States in the Adams-Onis Treaty. Under Osceola, a tribe waged a guerilla war by hiding out in this state’s swampy Everglades region. For 10 points, name this state where the US fought three wars with the Seminoles. ","answer":"ANSWER: Florida Tiebreaker. This country’s top general resigned after a housewife named Alejandrina Cox goaded him into shooting her car. This country built a national network of telex machines to manage its economy under Project Cybersyn. This country, which received a shipment of weapons in the Cuban Packages scandal, angered American mining companies by nationalizing the El Teniente copper mine. The “Caravan of Death” murdered dissidents in this country after the head of the Popular Unity Party shot himself in La Moneda Palace. For 10 points, name this country where Salvador Allende was overthrown by Augusto Pinochet. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this genre of over ninety works collected in the Exeter Book. A work in this genre named for Leiden begins with the line: “The wet ground, incredibly cold, first produced me from its innards.” ","answer":"ANSWER: riddles "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] The Exeter Book riddles were written in this medieval language. Other works written in this language include the Dream of the Rood and Beowulf. ","answer":"ANSWER: Old English [prompt on English; do not accept or prompt on Middle English] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Most Old English poems, including Beowulf and the Exeter riddles, use this poetic device in lieu of rhyme. Like sibilance, this literary technique is a special form of consonance. ","answer":"ANSWER: alliteration "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this prophet who abridged the Book of Ether [EE-ther]. This prophet shares his name with a captain of the Nephites who raised a banner called the “title of liberty” to rally his people. ","answer":"ANSWER: Moroni [or Captain Moroni] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Moroni’s writings are found in this religious text that includes writings from Enos and Nephi. Moroni supposedly buried the first version of this religious text on Cumorah Hill in New York. ","answer":"ANSWER: Book of Mormon "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This founder of Mormonism used “seer stones” to translate the Book of Mormon into English. Brigham Young took over leadership of the Mormon Church after this man’s death. ","answer":"ANSWER: Joseph Smith Jr. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this quantum number proposed by Gell-Mann and Keiss. This property, which is conserved by the strong and electromagnetic interactions but not the weak interaction, is symbolized S. ","answer":"ANSWER: strangeness "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Strangeness also names a flavor of one of these elementary particles, three of which make up hadrons. These particles have fractional charges and come in flavors such as up, down, and charm. ","answer":"ANSWER: quarks "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Strangeness production is a common technique for identifying certain forms of a plasma formed by quarks and these other particles. These particles mediate the strong force between quarks. ","answer":"ANSWER: gluons "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this language that David Lloyd George spoke at home as a child. Plaid Cymru (“PLIED CUM-ree”) advocates preserving this language by teaching it in schools. ","answer":"ANSWER: Welsh "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Wales underwent this process after a 1997 referendum, which enabled the creation of a Welsh Assembly separate from Parliament. Through this process, Scotland and Northern Ireland have been granted independent legislatures while still retaining their seats in Parliament. ","answer":"ANSWER: devolution [accept word forms like devolving; accept devo max; accept maximum devolution; do not accept or prompt on “federalism”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] In 2016, 52% of Welsh voters supported the Brexit campaign, which has initiated Great Britain’s departure from this continental organization. ","answer":"ANSWER: European Union [or EU] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this “Painter of Light” whose landscapes were championed by John Ruskin. He lends his name to the U.K’s foremost contemporary art prize, which has controversially been awarded to Tracey Emin and Damien Hirst. ","answer":"ANSWER: Joseph Mallord William Turner "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] A Turner painting depicts The Fighting Temeraire about to be “broken up” after this battle. Edwin Landseer sculpted 4 lions surrounding a monument in the center of a square named for this battle in London. ","answer":"ANSWER: Battle of Trafalgar "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] In his will, Turner gifted the National Gallery two paintings on the condition they were hung next to two landscapes by this French Baroque artist. This man’s Embarkation of the Queen of Sheba inspired Turner’s Dido Building Carthage. ","answer":"ANSWER: Claude Lorrain "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this Restoration-era female author of Oroonoko. In her play The Rover, Willmore falls in love with the convent-bound Hellena. ","answer":"ANSWER: Aphra Behn "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Aphra Behn’s translation of the Heroides was included in this writer’s collection of Ovid’s epistles. This author of Absalom and Achitophel mocked the “true blue Protestant poet” Thomas Shadwell in Mac Flecknoe. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Dryden "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Some scholars contend that Behn’s novel Oroonoko: A Royal Slave argues for this social cause. Harriet Beecher Stowe argued for this cause in her Civil War era novel Uncle Tom’s Cabin. ","answer":"ANSWER: abolition of slavery [or abolitionism; accept descriptive answers like ending slavery or ending the slave trade] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this work of political philosophy that critiques hedonism and utilitarianism with the experience machine thought experiment. This book uses the Wilt Chamberlain argument to refute the difference principle. ","answer":"ANSWER: Anarchy, State, and Utopia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Robert Nozick’s Anarchy, State, and Utopia was written as a rebuttal to a John Rawls book titled A Theory of this concept. Rawls used a social contract argument to create a theory equating this concept with fairness. ","answer":"ANSWER: justice [or A Theory of Justice] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Another Nozick work, Philosophical Explanations, argues for a four-part “tracking” theory of this concept. Plato defined this concept as “justified true belief.” ","answer":"ANSWER: knowledge "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name these biological catalysts, examples of which include lactase and helicase. ","answer":"ANSWER: enzymes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] The lock and key model competes with this other model of enzyme-substrate activity, which posits that the active site of an enzyme will change shape to accommodate the correct substrate. ","answer":"ANSWER: induced-fit model "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] An enzyme subject to competitive inhibition will have the same maximum rate of catalysis as an uninhibited enzyme according to this model of kinetics, which can be visualized with a Lineweaver-Burk plot. ","answer":"ANSWER: Michaelis-Menten kinetics [or Michaelis-Menten model] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this ethnic group whose Golden Horde extracted tribute from Russia for over two hundred years. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mongols [or Tatars] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Ivan III, a Grand Prince of this city, freed Russians from the “Tatar Yoke” of the Golden Horde at the Great Stand on the Ugra River. Ivan invited Italian architects to renovate Russia’s most famous kremlin in this city, its capital. ","answer":"ANSWER: Moscow [or Muscovy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Ivan the Terrible constructed St. Basil’s Cathedral in Moscow to commemorate the capture of this city, the capital of a splinter khanate of the Golden Horde. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kazan "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this composer of Les préludes and inventor of the “symphonic poem” genre. This composer’s travels through Switzerland and Italy were depicted in his piece Années de pèlerinage [“ah-NEE deh peh-luh-ree-nagh”] ","answer":"ANSWER: Franz Liszt "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Liszt was born in this country and wrote a set of 19 piano pieces called this country’s Rhapsodies. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hungary [or Magyarország; accept Hungarian] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This collection of three piano pieces by Liszt adapts poems by Ludwig Uhland and Ferdinand Freiligrath. The third piece in this set opens with right hand arpeggios over the melody [READ SLOWLY]: C–C–C [pause], short-C–C, short-C–D-flat, short-C–C, low-F. ","answer":"ANSWER: Liebesträume [or Love Dream or Dreams of Love] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this location where the protagonist travels through nine spheres to reach Empyrean, where he encounters a giant rose and witnesses St. Bernard make a prayer to Mary. ","answer":"ANSWER: paradise [or heaven; or Paradiso] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Beatrice leads Dante Alighieri through paradise because this man, his previous guide, was a “virtuous pagan” and cannot enter heaven. He wrote the Aeneid. ","answer":"ANSWER: Virgil [or Publius Vergilius Maro] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] In Canto III of the Inferno, Virgil leads Dante through this structure, which is inscribed with the message “abandon all hope, ye who enter here.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the Gates of Hell [prompt on descriptive answers like “the entrance to Hell”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this large Asian desert, located in northern China and southern Mongolia, where paleontologists have discovered many fossilized dinosaur eggs. According to legend, it is the home of an intestine-shaped “death worm.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Gobi Desert "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] While the Mongolian death worm is, sadly, fictional, the endangered wild Bactrian species of this animal is in fact native to the Gobi. ","answer":"ANSWER: camel [or wild Bactrian camel] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This Russian explorer became the first westerner to observe the wild Bactrian camel on one of his many Central Asian expeditions. He also discovered horse and gazelle species native to Central Asia, both of which are now named for him. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nikolay Przhevalsky [preh-shah-VAL-skee] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this Scottish-American whose advocacy in The Century Magazine helped lead to the creation of Yosemite National Park. This naturalist founded the Sierra Club. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Muir "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"2. ","answer":"ANSWER: Theodore Roosevelt [or TR; or Teddy Roosevelt; prompt on Roosevelt "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] One cause of the Roosevelt’s split from the Republican Party was Taft’s firing of this U.S. Forest Service Chief. John Muir feuded with this conservationist over the damming of the Hetch Hetchy Valley. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gifford Pinchot "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this ancient Greek hero who slew the Nemean Lion and captured Cerberus. ","answer":"ANSWER: Heracles [or Hercules] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] During Heracles’ fifth labor, he cleaned the stables of Augeas by diverting two of these things named Alpheus and Peneus. Achelous, the father of the Sirens, was a god of these geographical features. ","answer":"ANSWER: rivers [or streams; prompt on bodies of water] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Heracles defeated the river god Achelous in a wrestling contest for the hand of this woman. This wife of Heracles accidentally kills him by giving him Nessus’ poisoned tunic. ","answer":"ANSWER: Deianira "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] The Milky Way is a “barred” example of what type of galaxy? ","answer":"ANSWER: spiral galaxy [or barred spiral galaxy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This quantity is the power radiated by a galaxy or other astronomical object. The “solar” value of this quantity equals 3.828 times 10 28 watts. ","answer":"ANSWER: luminosity [or solar luminosity] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This relation named for two astronomers gives the angular velocity of a spiral galaxy in terms of its luminosity, and can therefore be used to calculate distances to astronomical bodies. ","answer":"ANSWER: Tully-Fisher relation [prompt on TFR] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this long time companion of Spiros Antonopoulos. After Antonopoulos is confined to an asylum, this man, who is both deaf and mute, visits him until he dies. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Singer [accept either underlined part] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] John Singer appears in The Heart is a Lonely Hunter, a novel by this author of The Ballad of the Sad Cafe. ","answer":"ANSWER: Carson McCullers "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"6. ","answer":"ANSWER: Harper Lee 17. [Moderator note: Make sure to read the lead-in to the following bonus (“Answer the following questions!”) forcefully, exaggerating the exclamation point.] Answer the following questions! For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] A sentence like “Answer the following questions!” has the imperative form of this grammatical feature, which also can be declarative or interrogative. It is often paired with tense and aspect. ","answer":"ANSWER: mood "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This other mood is often used to express hypotheticals or wishes, as seen in the use of the verb “were” in the statement “I wish this question were over.” ","answer":"ANSWER: subjunctive mood "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This family of languages, once merged with Baltic languages, largely lacks a subjunctive mood. It underwent a series of three “palatalizations,” and is divided into West, East, and South branches. ","answer":"ANSWER: Slavic languages "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this year in which an eruption of Eyjafjallajökull [“AY-ah-FEE-ut-la-YEH-kee-tull”] volcano created a giant ash cloud over Europe, grounding all flights on the continent from late April to early May. ","answer":"ANSWER: 2010 "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Eyjafjallajokull is located in the Suðurland region of this country. During the 2010 flight disruptions, many tourists were unable to fly out of Keflavik International Airport, which serves this country’s capital city, Reykjavik. ","answer":"ANSWER: Iceland "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Due to the flight cancellations, many world leaders were unable to attend the 2010 funeral of Lech Kaczynski [“LEKH kuh-CHIN-skee”], the president of this country, who had died in a plane crash unrelated to the volcanic ash cloud. ","answer":"ANSWER: Poland "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this double-reed instrument. Classical orchestras tune to a middle A played by this instrument. ","answer":"ANSWER: oboe "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Marshall Allen played oboe in “The Arkestra” of experimental artist Sun Ra, who played this instrument. Jazz fusion bandleader Herbie Hancock played the electric Rhodes variety of this instrument on his album Head Hunters. ","answer":"ANSWER: piano "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Romeo Penque and Harold Feldman played oboe on this album, which features the Gil Evans-written tracks “Saeta” and “Solea,” as well as a jazz rendition of the Adagio movement of the Concierto de Aranjuez. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sketches of Spain (by Miles Davis) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this transition metal. In the Sabatier reaction, this element catalyzes the conversion of carbon dioxide to form methane. ","answer":"ANSWER: nickel [or Ni] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] The nickel-catalyzed Sabatier reaction is an example of these kinds of reactions, which involve adding a namesake element. This kind of reaction can also be facilitated by a palladium-on-carbon catalyst. ","answer":"ANSWER: hydrogenations [prompt on, but do not reveal, “reduction(s)”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] The Mond process reacts impure nickel with this compound to create nickel carbonyl. This colorless, odorless gas contains two triply-bonded atoms and can be deadly to humans. ","answer":"ANSWER: carbon monoxide [or CO] Tiebreaker. A poem in this collection describes how a “Moving Finger writes, and, having writ, moves on.” For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Name this set of Persian quatrains by Omar Khayyam. It was translated into English by Edward Fitzgerald. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] This Persian poet of the Masnavi, or Spiritual Couplets, frequently wrote about his love for his spiritual teacher, Shams-e-Tabrizi. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jalaluddin Rumi "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] In the best-known work of the Persian poet Farid ud-Din Attar, a Conference of these animals crosses seven valleys to visit the Simorgh. They aren’t snakes, but Sinbad the Sailor encounters a mythical one of these animals in a valley that is covered in diamonds. ","answer":"ANSWER: birds [or Roc; accept more specific types of bird like eagles] EXTRA In 1843, William Rowan Hamilton carved the formula “i squared equals j squared equals k squared equals ijk equals -1” onto Brougham Bridge. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] That formula represents the relationships between what four-dimensional complex numbers? ","answer":"ANSWER: quaternions "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] In the multiplication of quaternions, the order of the multiplicands matters; thus, quaternion multiplication lacks this property. ","answer":"ANSWER: commutative property [or commutativity] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"G","question":"[10] Because quaternion multiplication is not commutative, the multiplication group of the quaternions lacks this property named after a Norwegian mathematician. ","answer":"ANSWER: abelian [or abelian group] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"1. These particles are both fired and ejected in a spectroscopy technique named after the Auger effect. The Drude model gives the equation of motion of these particles in a particular material. In beta minus decay, a neutron is converted to a proton while emitting an antineutrino and this particle. Carl D. Anderson discovered the antimatter counterpart of this particle, the positron. The position of these particles is described by the “building up”, or Aufbau, principle. These particles travelled in circular orbits around the nucleus according to the Bohr model. For 10 points, name these negatively charged particles found in atomic orbitals. ","answer":"ANSWER: electrons "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"2. In a novel set in this country, the mute boy Simon kicks and destroys Kerewin’s guitar, which his abusive father uses as an excuse to beat him. A short story by an author from this country ends with a woman placing her fur in its case and listening to it “cry.” This setting of The Bone People is also the setting of a short story in which a woman supervises the placement of a marquee before taking some cream puffs to her recently widowed neighbor, Mrs. Smith. “Miss Brill” and “The Garden Party” were written by Katherine Mansfield, who was from this country. For 10 points, name this home country of the author Keri Hulme, who is of Maori descent. ","answer":"ANSWER: New Zealand "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"3. Members of this empire’s Dyula merchant caste were influential members of its Gbara assembly. A leader of this empire is depicted holding a scepter in Abraham Cresques’ Catalan Atlas. This empire, which trained scholars at a university in Sankore, used bundles of rodier palm and mud to build the Great Mosque of Djenné. According to legend, the founder of this empire used the spur of a white rooster to kill Sumarungu at the Battle of Kirina. Another ruler of this empire is said to have depressed the value of gold in Cairo by handing out money during his pilgrimage to Mecca. For 10 points, name this African empire ruled by Sundiata and Mansa Musa. ","answer":"ANSWER: Malian Empire "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"4. This mythological figure healed the King of Mysia, Telephus, by stabbing Telephus’ wound with his spear. As a child, this figure was disguised as a girl and hidden on the island of Skyros. Hephaestus forged an object for this figure that depicts a city at peace and a city at war. This “fleet-footed” hero refuses to continue fighting after a ruler abducts his lover Briseis. Ajax the Greater and Odysseus fight over this figure’s armor after he dies. When he was an infant, this hero’s mother Thetis dipped him in the water of the river Styx. For 10 points, name this Greek hero with a vulnerable heel. ","answer":"ANSWER: Achilles "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"5. This country’s first prima ballerina became famous for performing the title role in a 1949 production of The Firebird. In 1987, a dance company in this country emulated Nijinsky’s original choreography for a production of The Rite of Spring. A choreographer from this country developed a technique involving breathing effectively to achieve “contraction and release,” and was nicknamed “the picasso of dance” for her modernist style. The Russian-born choreographer George Balanchine directed this country’s most prominent ballet company. For 10 points, name this home country of ballerina Maria Tallchief and choreographer Martha Graham. ","answer":"ANSWER: United States of America [or U.S.A; or America] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"6. A modern type of these devices developed by John Milne contained a spring attached to a pivoting knife that was free to move horizontally. The inability of these devices to function in so-called “shadow zones” was used by Richard Oldham as evidence that the Earth’s core is a liquid. Primitive versions of these devices used a pen and a rotating drum to record the relative motion between a weight and a frame. The velocity of P-waves and S-waves is registered on these devices, which can be used to calculate the distance to the epicenter. For 10 points, name these devices that measure the intensity of earthquakes. ","answer":"ANSWER: seismometers [or seismographs] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"7. A song named for this company mentions a woman who needs “a ring like Carmelo” because she “must be on that white like Othello.” Citing the Trump administration’s sanctions, this company forbade the Iranian national soccer team from using its products at the World Cup. This company, whose slogan was inspired by the dying words of serial killer Gary Gilmore, was founded by Bill Bowerman and Phil Knight. A controversial 2018 ad by this company features the words “Believe in something. Even if it means sacrificing everything,” over the face of Colin Kaepernick. “Just do it” is the slogan of, for 10 points, what athletic apparel company that has a “swoosh” logo? ","answer":"ANSWER: Nike [the song mentioned in the first line is “Nikes” by Frank Ocean] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"8. The speaker of a poem remembers these objects when “in a vacant or pensive mood” while enjoying the “bliss of solitude” on a couch. These objects “out-did the sparkling waves in glee” in the presence of a man to whom they provide “jocund company.” These objects, which are as “continuous as the stars that shine and twinkle on the Milky Way,” toss “their heads in a sprightly dance.” The speaker sees these objects “fluttering and dancing in the breeze” in a poem by the author of The Prelude. For 10 points, name these yellow flowers that serve as the primary subject of William Wordsworth’s “I Wandered Lonely as a Cloud.” ","answer":"ANSWER: daffodils [prompt on flowers until mention] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"9. The Age of this politician titles a Pulitzer Prize-winning book by Arthur Schlesinger. He’s not Thomas Jefferson, but this president invited 10,000 ordinary people into the White House to eat a giant piece of cheese. This president’s enemies distributed the Coffin Handbills and spread rumors that his wife, Rachel, was a bigamist. All but one of this president’s cabinet members resigned after he supported Peggy Eaton during the Petticoat affair. This president relied on the advice of his informal “Kitchen Cabinet” and ordered the Trail of Tears. For 10 points, name this president who succeeded John Quincy Adams, nicknamed “Old Hickory.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Andrew Jackson "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"0. Before the 1960s, patients with this disease were often treated through insulin-induced comas. The drug Clozapine is often prescribed to patients with severe cases of this disease. The “first rank” symptoms of this disease were first identified by Kurt Schneider. Researchers faked this disease’s symptoms in order to be admitted to mental hospitals in the Rosenhan experiment. This disease, which is often conflated with dissociative personality disorder, was once separated into catatonic and paranoid subtypes. For 10 points, name this mental disorder whose symptoms include delusions and auditory hallucinations. ","answer":"ANSWER: schizophrenia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"1. One protein found in these cells has a Schiff base linkage between its lysine residue and aldehyde group. The increased sensitivity to these cells compared to their counterpart is responsible for the Purkinje effect. Ganglion cells typically receive input from roughly 100 of these cells, which are particularly concentrated away from the fovea and absorb radiation using a reddish-purple protein called rhodopsin. Unlike their much less abundant counterpart, these cells allow for night vision and cannot detect color. For 10 points, what photoreceptor cells are present in the retina along with cones? ","answer":"ANSWER: rods [or rod cells] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"2. According to some accounts, this historical figure shouted “I am not!” after falling to the floor of a choir loft. This man was venerated by Nazi Germany on a holiday in November, on which speakers would read passages from this man’s tract On the Jews and Their Lies. Under questioning from Johann Eck, this man replied “here I stand, I can do no other” at a meeting where he was excommunicated in the bull Exsurge Domine. Historians debate whether this opponent of Johann Tetzel actually nailed a document to the door of the Wittenberg Cathedral. For 10 points, name this leader of the Protestant Reformation who wrote the Ninety-five Theses. ","answer":"ANSWER: Martin Luther "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"3. A member of this art movement named Maurice de Vlaminck formed the so-called “School of Chatou.” One of the first works associated with this movement was painted by a student of Gustave Moreau and depicts bathers on the French Riviera. The leader of this movement painted his wife Amélie in the portrait Woman with a Hat, a work that inspired critic Louis Vauxcelles to coin this movement’s name at the 1905 Salon d’Automne. Works associated with this movement, such as The Dance and The Joy of Life, tend to feature aggressively vibrant colors. For 10 points, name this art movement led by Andre Derain and Henri Matisse, whose name means “Wild Beasts.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Fauvism [or word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"4. Chaitanya Mahaprabhu helped popularize a text recited to honor this figure. On a holiday dedicated to this figure, young boys form human pyramids to try and break hanging pots. A “dance of divine love” known as rasa lila is performed in devotion to this figure. This figure’s birth is celebrated on Janmashtami [“jun-MAWSH-tum-ee”]. He is the speaker of a 700-verse text that emphasizes “selfless action.” This figure is considered the Svayam Bhagavan, or “Supreme Lord,” by the ISKCON organization. This figure advises Arjuna in the Bhagavad Gita, and, as a child, he would often steal butter and play the flute. For 10 points, name this blue-skinned deity, the eighth avatar of Vishnu. ","answer":"ANSWER: Krishna [prompt on Vishnu] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"5. After the protagonist of this play tells his wife he punched a man who called him a “walrus,” his wife calls him “the handsomest man in the world.” The protagonist of this play is told that “the jungle is dark, but full of diamonds” by a vision of his deceased brother, who the protagonist chose not to accompany to Alaska. A character in this play drops out of summer school after learning of his father’s affair with “The Woman,” and steals a pen from Bill Oliver during a job interview. Despite the efforts of his wife Linda, the protagonist of this play commits suicide to procure a $20,000 insurance payment for his son Biff. For 10 points, name this Arthur Miller play about Willy Loman. ","answer":"ANSWER: Death of a Salesman "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"6. Standard Oil of Ohio names a process that reacts propylene with this compound and water to form acrylonitrile. An atom in this compound undergoes a quantum-tunneling inversion in a “maser” named for this compound that was invented by Charles Townes. A process for creating this compound most commonly utilizes an iron-based catalyst and high temperatures and pressures. This substance, which is oxidized to produce nitric acid in the Ostwald process, is industrially produced from atmospheric nitrogen by the Haber–Bosch process. For 10 points, name this compound, commonly used in cleaning products, with formula NH3 . ","answer":"ANSWER: ammonia [or NH3 before mentioned] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"7. This composer orchestrated the opening stream of sixteenth notes of a piano suite into rapid, galloping chords for strings in a long-short-short rhythm that starts on a G-major second inversion chord for three beats before ascending the G-major scale. A piano suite by this composer reuses the melody from its opening “Arietta” in waltz form for the final piece, “Remembrances.” This composer’s piano concerto opens with a timpani roll that crescendos into the soloist’s forceful A minor chord. This composer of the Lyric Pieces wrote a suite that includes the pieces “Anitra’s Dance” and “In the Hall of the Mountain King.” For 10 points, name this Norwegian composer of the Peer Gynt Suite. ","answer":"ANSWER: Edvard (Hagerup) Grieg "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"8. The epigraph of this novel specifies that it is to be read as “neither an accusation nor a confession, and least of all an adventure.” Lewis Milestone’s film adaptation of this novel changed its ending to one in which the protagonist is shot while reaching for a butterfly. The protagonist of this novel joins Kropp and Leer to cross a river to meet some French girls, but later feels guilty over killing the printer Gerard Duval. The protagonist receives Kemmerich’s boots after Müller is killed, and gives up hope after “Kat” Katczinsky [“kah-CHIN-skee”] dies in the trenches. For 10 points, name this novel about Paul Baumer’s experiences during World War I, written by Erich Maria Remarque. ","answer":"ANSWER: All Quiet on the Western Front [or Im Westen nichts Neues] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"9. For 10 points, name this Eastern European country ruled by the dictator Nicolae Ceausescu [“chow-SHES-koo”]. ","answer":"ANSWER: Romania "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"0. An essay associated with this school of philosophy foresees an era in which men will “hunt in the morning, fish in the afternoon, and criticize after dinner.”A philosopher from this school of thought postulated an “epistemological break” in its central thinker’s ideas and coined the term “ideological state apparatus.” Philosophers from this school like Louis Althusser and György Lukács [“loo-KASH”] follow a thinker who stated in a letter, “from each according to his ability, to each according to his needs.” That thinker central to this school used a philosophy of dialectical materialism to analyze class struggle. For 10 points, name this school of philosophy named after the author of Das Kapital and The Communist Manifesto. ","answer":"ANSWER: Marxism [accept Orthodox Marxism or Structural Marxism; prompt on Communism] (the essay mentioned in the first line is Marx and Engels’ The German Ideology] Tiebreaker. This man had his friend Henry Albert Harper commemorated with a statue of Sir Galahad on Parliament Hill. On the advice of Ernest LaPointe, this politician created “zombies” by pledging not to deploy conscripts overseas. This politician refused to follow David Lloyd George’s lead into a war with Turkey during the Chanak Crisis. This leader’s grandfather served as the first mayor of Toronto and led the Upper Canada Rebellion of "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"7. He faced a constitutional crisis when his request for a dissolution of Parliament was denied by Governor General Julian Byng. For 10 points, name this longest-serving Canadian prime minister. ","answer":"ANSWER: William Lyon Mackenzie King Bonuses "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this sequence of numbers that begins “0, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Fibonacci numbers [or Fibonacci sequence] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"2. ","answer":"ANSWER: square root of 5 [or radical 5] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"1. ","answer":"ANSWER: Eugène Charles Catalan [or Catalan numbers; or Catalan’s identity] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this ancient Buddhist philosopher who created a logical method referred to as fourfold negation and founded the “middle way,” or Madhyamaka [“MAD-hee-am-ah”], school of Buddhist philosophy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nagarjuna "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Nagarjuna is generally believed to have been a philosopher from this modern day country. Ancient schools of philosophy from this country are classified as orthodox or heterodox partly based on whether they use the Vedas as sources of knowledge. ","answer":"ANSWER: India "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] The ancient Buddhist philosopher Dharmakirti [“DHUR-maw-KEER-thee”] is known for his version of this branch of philosophy involving real particulars. This branch of philosophy takes its name from an Aristotle text that considers “being qua being.” ","answer":"ANSWER: metaphysics "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this Aramaic declaration recited before the beginning of one High Holy Day. Its name translates to “all vows.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Kol Nidre "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] The Kol Nidre is recited before the beginning of this Jewish day of atonement that ends with Ne’ila, during which the gates of heaven are said to close. Adherents fast during this 25-hour holiday that falls on the 10th of Tishrei. ","answer":"ANSWER: Yom Kippur "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] During the Ne’ila Amida prayer, this object is kept open. This object, which is where a synagogue’s Torah scrolls are kept, is traditionally placed on the wall of the sanctuary that faces Jerusalem. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Torah ark [or the holy ark; or Aron kodesh] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this type of poem, exemplified by George Herbert’s “The Altar.” Another Herbert poem, “Easter Wings,” uses the preconditions of this form of poetry to show a man’s faith becoming “thinne” and “poore.” ","answer":"ANSWER: concrete poems [accept shaped poems; prompt on answers mentioning that they resemble their subject] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] George Herbert belonged to this seventeenth century British literary movement. A more famous member of this movement imagined his blood mingled with that of his lover in “The Flea.” ","answer":"ANSWER: metaphysical poets "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Herbert described this entity as “an uncouth hideous thing.” Fellow metaphysical poet John Donne agreed with Herbert’s characterization, telling this entity to “be not proud” in his most famous Holy Sonnet. ","answer":"ANSWER: death [accept “Death, be not proud”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this Prussian theorist who declared “war is the continuation of politics by other means” in his influential tract On War. ","answer":"ANSWER: Carl von Clausewitz "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Clausewitz was captured by Napoleon’s army at this 1806 battle, a decisive defeat for Prussia. Georg Hegel, who witnessed this battle, argued that it constituted the “end of history” ","answer":"ANSWER: Battle of Jena-Auerstedt [accept either] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] After Prussia capitulated to the French via the Treaty of Tilsit, Clausewitz served in this non-British country’s German Legion. Clausewitz aided this country’s general Mikhail Kutuzov at the Battle of Borodino. ","answer":"ANSWER: Russia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this German scientist who proposed that energy is radiated in discrete packets called quanta. His namesake constant is symbolized “h.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Max Planck "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] In order to develop his blackbody formula, Planck modeled atoms of a blackbody as these systems. These systems, which exhibit a restoring force proportional to the displacement, can be damped or driven. ","answer":"ANSWER: simple harmonic oscillators [or SHOs; or springs; or pendulums; or pendula; prompt on oscillators; do not accept or prompt on “quantum harmonic oscillator”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Planck’s blackbody formula helped to solve this problem of classical physics. This problem refers to classical physics’ prediction of radiating infinite energy as frequencies reach a certain region of the electromagnetic spectrum. ","answer":"ANSWER: ultraviolet catastrophe [or UV catastrophe; or Rayleigh–Jeans catastrophe] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this profession of Mabuse in a series of Fritz Lang films. In a 1921 film directed by Robert Wiene, a man with this profession named Caligari hires the sleepwalker Cesare to commit murders for him. ","answer":"ANSWER: doctors [or The Testament of Dr. Mabuse or The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari; prompt on criminal or similar answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari revolutionized the design of these items, one of which displays the slanted word “Moloch!” during a factory explosion in Lang’s Metropolis. Joseph Farnham won the first and only Academy Award for the design of these things, which were made obsolete by the advent of “talkies.” ","answer":"ANSWER: intertitles [or title cards; prompt on titles; do not accept or prompt on “subtitles”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] F. W. Murnau used black Gothic lettering for the intertitles of his film Nosferatu, which is an adaptation of this novel. Bela Lugosi played the title vampire of this Bram Stoker novel in a 1931 Tod Browning film. ","answer":"ANSWER: Dracula "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] The well-traveled Tappan Zee Bridge and its successor, the Mario Cuomo Bridge, both cross this New York river. Its namesake was an English explorer who sailed for the Netherlands. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hudson River "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"0. The Strait of Juan de Fuca connects this body of water to the Pacific Ocean. ","answer":"ANSWER: Puget Sound [also accept Salish Sea] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] The New River Gorge Bridge, the longest steel span in the Western Hemisphere, is a popular destination for BASE jumpers in this state. Some conspiracy theorists believe that the Mothman, a cryptid associated with this state’s town of Point Pleasant, caused the 1967 Silver Bridge disaster. ","answer":"ANSWER: West Virginia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this European who describes 55 fantastical locations, all of which are thinly veiled versions of Venice, in the novel Invisible Cities. This historical figure wrote an account of his life while imprisoned in Genoa. ","answer":"ANSWER: Marco Polo "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Marco Polo converses with Kublai Khan in this Italian novelist’s Invisible Cities. You, the reader, encounter Ludmilla in this author’s novel If on a winter’s night a traveler. ","answer":"ANSWER: Italo Calvino "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Invisible Cities is interspersed with scenes in which Kublai and Marco Polo perform this activity in a magnolia garden. Aleksandr Luzhin is obsessed with this activity in a Vladimir Nabokov novel ","answer":"ANSWER: playing chess [accept any descriptive answer that mentions chess] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this country whose Prince Henry the Navigator commissioned many maritime expeditions. This country came to dominate the Indian Ocean through the exploits of its admiral Afonso de Albuquerque. ","answer":"ANSWER: Portugal "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] In 1511, Albuquerque captured this city in present-day Malaysia from Sultan Mahmud Shah. The Portuguese used their control of this city’s namesake strait to dominate the global spice trade. ","answer":"ANSWER: Malacca [or Melaka; accept Strait of Malacca] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Before capturing Malacca for Portugal, Albuquerque led a successful 1510 siege of this city. This city was forcibly annexed by a different country in 1961’s Operation Vijay. ","answer":"ANSWER: Goa "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this reaction, which reacts a ketone or aldehyde with a triphenyl phosphonium ylide [“YILL-id”] to form another functional group. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wittig reaction "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] The triphenyl phosphonium ylide used in the Wittig reaction is known as this type of anion [“an-EYE-on”]. These ions have a net charge of zero, but exhibit regions of both positive and negative charge. ","answer":"ANSWER: zwitterions [or dipolar ion] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] The Wittig reaction almost exclusively forms the “Z” type of these molecules, not their “E” type. These molecules contain carbon-carbon double bonds. ","answer":"ANSWER: alkenes [or Z-alkenes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this bird who serves as a trickster figure in the mythology of the Pacific Northwest. According to the Haida people, this bird found the first humans in a clam shell. ","answer":"ANSWER: Raven "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Another Haida story tells how Raven stole the sun, the moon, the stars, and fresh water from a grey one of these animals. Zeus is said to have taken the form of one of these animals to abduct Ganymede. ","answer":"ANSWER: eagles "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] This Greek god was said to have turned ravens’ feathers black in his fury. He’s not Helios, but this god of the sun was the patron god of Delphi. ","answer":"ANSWER: Apollo "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Give this term for the common people of Rome, who, despite being citizens, did not gain significant rights until the Conflict of the Orders. They often clashed with Rome’s upper-class patricians. ","answer":"ANSWER: plebs [or plebeians] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] During the Conflict of the Orders, the plebs would often employ this strategy of abandoning their jobs and shutting down Roman commerce. The plebs left Rome for Mons Sacer during one of these events in 494 BCE. ","answer":"ANSWER: Secession of the Plebs [or Secessio Plebis] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] This office, which represented the plebs in the Roman Senate, was created after the 494 Secession of the Plebs. It isn’t legatus or prefectus, but this office shares its name with the Roman military position of officers ranked above centurions. ","answer":"ANSWER: Tribune of the Plebs [or tribunus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this composer of sacred music who was depicted as Aloysius in Johann Fux’s composition text Gradus ad Parnassum. The Agnus Dei of a mass by this composer is unusually split into two parts. ","answer":"ANSWER: Giovanni Pierluigi da Palestrina "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Palestrina is known for his distinct method of writing in this style, which consists of two or more melodies that interact with each other. Palestrina’s Pope Marcellus Mass is known for its use of this style. ","answer":"ANSWER: polyphony [or polyphonic music] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Palestrina is considered a composer from this era of music that followed the Medieval era and preceded the Baroque era. This era shares its name with an Italian humanist movement from the same time period that resulted in a “rebirth” of the arts. ","answer":"ANSWER: Renaissance era [prompt on early modern period] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this “deathless child of Zeus.” The speaker of the poem this figure appears in asks her to “abate [her] torment” and “fight as [her] comrade.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Aphrodite [accept “Hymn to Aphrodite”; accept “Ode to Aphrodite”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] This writer of the “Hymn to Aphrodite” and an “Ode to Anactoria” compared a woman to a “sweet apple” and “wild hyacinth flower” in the poem “One Girl.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Sappho "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] In a poem found in 2014, Sappho waits for her brother Charaxos to return from this conflict. Odysseus fights in this war in Homer’s Iliad. ","answer":"ANSWER: Trojan War "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this compound, an excess of which can lead to Crigler-Najjar syndrome and other forms of jaundice. ","answer":"ANSWER: bilirubin [prompt on hematoidin; do not accept or prompt on “bile”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] This organ, which is damaged in cirrhosis, breaks down bilirubin via the process of glucuronidation and excretes it in bile. ","answer":"ANSWER: liver "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Most of the bile acids that help to break down bilirubin are absorbed into this final section of the small intestine, which releases digested food into the cecum [“SEE-cum”]. ","answer":"ANSWER: ileum [prompt on posterior intestine or distal intestine] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this metal whose “standard” dictated the 19th-century money supply. William Jennings Bryan, who gave a speech titled for a “cross of” this metal, sought to supplement it with “free silver.” ","answer":"ANSWER: gold [or Au] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Members of this faction defected from the Democratic Party in 1896 out of opposition to Bryan’s bimetallist ideas. Grover Cleveland was a member of this faction, which supported low tariffs and the gold standard. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bourbon Democrats "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] The Bourbon Democrats opposed an 1890 Silver Purchase Act sponsored by a senator with this surname who also wrote a namesake Antitrust Act. Another man with this surname stated “if nominated, I will not accept; if elected, I will not serve” when asked to run for president. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sherman [accept John Sherman or William Tecumseh Sherman] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this painting, whose other symbols include a chandelier with a single lit candle, a carved wooden figure of St. Margaret triumphing over a dragon, and a convex mirror bordered by roundels depicting the Passion of Christ. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Arnolfini Portrait [or The Arnolfini Wedding; or The Arnolfini Marriage] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] The Arnolfini Portrait is the best-known work of this Early Netherlandish painter, whose other works include the Madonna of Chancellor Rolin and a possible self-portrait of a man wearing a red turban. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jan van Eyck "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Van Eyck utilized grisaille for a diptych of this Biblical scene. The masterpiece of Robert Campin depicts this scene in skewed perspective, flanked by depictions of St. Joseph carving a mousetrap and donors praying. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Annunciation "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this woman, whose wish for her daughter to be a “beautiful little fool” was quoted by her husband in one novel. She inspired the character of Nicole Diver in her husband’s novel Tender is the Night. ","answer":"ANSWER: Zelda Fitzgerald [or Zelda Sayre] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Zelda’s husband F. Scott Fitzgerald is most famous for writing this Jazz Age novel, in which Nick Carraway attends the title character’s parties in West Egg. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Great Gatsby "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] In this other Fitzgerald novel, Princeton student and World War I veteran Amory Blaine laments “I know myself, but that is all” after his failed romance with Rosalind Connage, another character based on Zelda. ","answer":"ANSWER: This Side of Paradise "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name these mental “shortcuts” utilized in decision-making and problem-solving, which are often contrasted with algorithms. Research by Kahneman and Tversky demonstrated how these things can lead to cognitive biases. ","answer":"ANSWER: heuristics "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Heuristics are often studied in this subfield of psychology, which examines how human behavior is influenced by interactions with other humans. ","answer":"ANSWER: social psychology "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] This pioneering social psychologist from Yale asked volunteers to administer electric shocks to confederate “learners” in an experiment testing subjects’ obedience to authority. ","answer":"ANSWER: Stanley Milgram Tiebreaker. AZT can be used to treat infection caused by this virus. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] Name this virus that causes AIDS. ","answer":"ANSWER: HIV [or human immunodeficiency virus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] HIV can be classified as this type of virus, which uses the enzyme reverse transcriptase to convert RNA into DNA that is then incorporated into a host cell. ","answer":"ANSWER: retrovirus "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"H","question":"[10] The envelope glycoprotein gp120 of HIV often interacts with this receptor protein. Helper T cells are distinguished from cytotoxic T cells by expressing this protein on their surfaces. ","answer":"ANSWER: CD4"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"1. It’s not the saxophone, but David Shire’s score for The Conversation primarily utilizes this instrument. Michael Nyman composed “The Heart Asks Pleasure First” as part of his celebrated minimalist score for a Jane Campion film titled for this instrument. Michael Riesman played this instrument on scores for films like Mishima and The Hours in collaboration with Philip Glass. The score of the 1973 heist film The Sting featured a number of pieces for this instrument that revitalized interest in the ragtime music of Scott Joplin. For 10 points, an iconic scene from Big depicts Tom Hanks and Robert Loggia playing “Heart and Soul” by jumping on the white keys of what instrument? ","answer":"ANSWER: piano "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"2. This organization employed public relations experts Elizabeth Tyler and Edward Young Clarke to publish its newspaper, Searchlight. This organization lost popularity in Indiana after Madge Oberholtzer was raped by this group’s regional leader D.C. Stephenson. Members of this organization loudly booed Al Smith at the 1924 Democratic National Convention, which was nicknamed this group’s “bake.” This organization was revived at Stone Mountain in 1915 after it was positively portrayed in D. W. Griffith’s film Birth of a Nation. For 10 points, Nathan Bedford Forrest was the first Grand Wizard of what cross-burning, hood-wearing white supremacist organization? ","answer":"ANSWER: Knights of the Ku Klux Klan "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"3. A character with this profession witnesses a blackface performance at a party at Chuffnell Hall. A different character with this profession overhears Lord Halifax and Herr Ribbentrop complimenting some silver. That character with this profession is employed by Mr. Faraday, who enjoys engaging in “banter.” A character with this profession is told Carry On and Right Ho in the titles of novels about his adventures with Bertie Wooster. Stevens works in this profession at Darling Hall in Kazuo Ishiguro’s The Remains of the Day. For 10 points, name this type of household servant exemplified by P.G. Wodehouse’s Jeeves. ","answer":"ANSWER: butlers [prompt on manservants] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"4. Post-translational fucosylation is most commonly studied for its impact on these proteins’ efficacy. These proteins are chemically linked to chemotherapeutics in ADCs. The term “biologics” almost exclusively refers to the use of these proteins as drugs when they are synthesized with high specificity by hybridoma cells. These proteins agglutinate into clumps when they bind to specific targets called epitopes. These proteins come in five isotypes and have an incredible array of diversity afforded by class switching and somatic hypermutation. For 10 points, name these Y-shaped proteins essential to the function of the immune system because they bind antigens. ","answer":"ANSWER: antibodies [or antibody or immunoglobulins] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"5. An offshoot of this religion is known for its practice of making and selling brooms. Adherents of this religion often insert the pronoun “I” into words, such as “I-men” for “Amen,” to symbolize the divine nature of the self. This religion refers to the life-force of the self as “livity,” which can be maintained and increased by adhering to this religion’s Ital [“EYE-tall”] diet. The Nyahbinghi and Bobo Ashanti are “mansions” of this religion, which regards the Kebra Nagast as a holy text. Members of this religion worship Haile Selassie [“HIGH-luh suh-LASS-ee”] as the messiah. For 10 points, name this Jamaican religion whose adherents typically wear dreadlocks and smoke ganja. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rastafarianism [or the Rastafari movement; prompt on Nyabinghi; prompt on Bobo Ashanti] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"6. This man served as the first Lord President of the Council of the North. The marriage of this man’s brother to Elizabeth Woodville was declared invalid in the Titulus Regius statute, allowing this man to become king. This monarch’s wife Anne Neville was the daughter of an Earl of Warwick nicknamed “Kingmaker.” In 2013, archaeologists associated with the University of Leicester [“lester”] discovered this king’s skeleton under a parking lot. This regent for Edward V likely murdered the Princes in the Tower before his death at the Battle of Bosworth Field. For 10 points, name this hunchbacked king of England who cries “my kingdom for a horse” in a Shakespeare play. ","answer":"ANSWER: Richard III [prompt on Richard] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"7. This artist’s wife, who published the memoir Burning Lights, is depicted wearing a white collar in one of this artist’s portraits. This artist depicted himself flying with his wife Bella Rosenfeld in paintings titled The Birthday and Over the Town. The story of Elijah may have inspired this artist’s portrait of a man in a purple coat playing a violin. A Lithuanian flag and a burning synagogue appear in this artist’s White Crucifixion. This artist drew from his boyhood memories of Belarus to paint a work in which a row of houses and a man with a scythe appear behind a man staring at a goat. For 10 points, name this Russian-French artist of I and the Village. ","answer":"ANSWER: Marc Chagall "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"8. Bengt Edlen discovered that this body’s outermost region contained highly ionized iron rather than an exotic element. A probe designed to study this body was launched in August 2018 and will use multiple Venus gravity-assists to reach it; that probe is named after Eugene Parker. A class of visual features on this body were rare during the Maunder Minimum and follow an 11-year cycle of appearance. Those features of this body are formed when strong magnetic fields inhibit convection, thus creating cooler areas on its photosphere. For 10 points, name this “yellow dwarf” that is the closest star to Earth. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Sun "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"9. In a novel set in this country, a band of cavaliers makes a deal with the evil ironworker Sintram to seize the Mistress of Ekeby’s property. The first female recipient of the Nobel Prize in Literature was an author from this country who created the disgraced minister Gösta Berling. A novelist from this country wrote about Arvid Falk’s transformation into a bohemian journalist in the novel The Red Room. In a play from this country, the daughter of a Count tries to run away with the valet Jean before walking offstage to kill herself with a razor. For 10 points, name this home country of Selma Lagerlöf and the author of Miss Julie, August Strindberg. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sweden "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"0. According to Simon Kuznets, this statistic increases and then decreases as an economy develops. Joseph Stiglitz attributed the rise of this quantity to the practice of rent-seeking. The Hoover index is a measure of the amount of capital required to make this quantity zero. In Capital in the Twenty-First Century, Thomas Piketty attributed the increase of this statistic to the fact that “r,” the rate of return, is greater than “g,” economic growth. The Lorenz curve can be used to visualize this statistic, which is measured by the Gini coefficient. For 10 points, name this measure of the differences in the distribution of assets among a group of people. ","answer":"ANSWER economic inequality [or income inequality; prompt on poverty] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"1. Among the longest home runs ever recorded at this team’s home stadium was a 540-foot blast by Dave Kingman in a 23-22 loss to the Phillies. In 1964, this team shipped a future Hall of Fame outfielder to a regional rival in return for Ernie Broglio. In the 1900s, this team's infield included a prolific double-play combination immortalized by the phrase “Tinkers to Evers to Chance.” This team's loss to the Marlins in the 2003 NLCS was blamed by fans on Steve Bartman. This team won its first championship in 108 years, breaking the “Curse of the Billy Goat,” by defeating the Indians in the 2016 World Series. For 10 points, name this baseball team that plays at Wrigley Field. ","answer":"ANSWER: Chicago Cubs [prompt on Chicago] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"2. Early feminists from this country include the veil-removing activist Huda Sha’arawi and the author of The Liberation of Women, Qasim Amin. Saad Zaghloul attempted to represent this country at the Versailles Conference. Grand Mufti Muhammad Abduh implemented many reforms at this nation’s Al-Azhar [“ALL UHZ-her”] University. The Wafd Party pushed for this country’s independence, though it was later banned by the regime of this country’s Free Officers Movement. With Soviet support, this country constructed the Aswan High Dam. For 10 points, name this country once led by Gamal Abdel Nasser. ","answer":"ANSWER: Egypt "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"3. A “factor” named for this force is equal to 64 over the Reynolds number for laminar flows and is used to quantify the pressure loss due to this force in the Darcy–Weisbach equation. The area of a body’s surface in contact with a fluid determines the magnitude of the “skin” type of this force. An object’s angle of repose equals the arctangent of two dimensionless properties named for this force. This force, which comes in both static and kinetic varieties, has a magnitude related to the normal force times its namesake coefficient. For 10 points, name this force which opposes the direction of motion and dissipates energy as heat. ","answer":"ANSWER: friction "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"4. A prince of this region named Glaucus had to be resurrected by Polyidus after he drowned in a jar of honey. Heracles caught and set free an animal from this region that later wandered to Marathon. A king of this region was boiled to death in a bathtub by the daughters of King Cocalus. Zeus took the form of a white bull to abduct Europa from this island. Every year, fourteen Athenian youths would be sent to this island to face a task eventually accomplished using a ball of string. In the Underworld, dead souls are judged by a king of this island named Minos. For 10 points, name this Greek island where Daedalus built a labyrinth that contains the Minotaur. ","answer":"ANSWER: Crete [prompt on Greece until “island” is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"5. One of this book’s characters appears in the guise of Danny’s stereotypically Asian cousin “Chin-Kee” in Gene Luen Yang’s graphic novel American Born Chinese. A character in this novel gains notoriety after finding the source of a waterfall behind a bridge, and later waves a plantain fan that causes flames feared by this novel’s Great Sage. A character in this novel writes and urinates on five stone pillars he later realizes are fingers. That character is born from a magical stone egg. This novel’s protagonist is accompanied by Sandy, Pigsy, and the Monkey King on his quest for holy texts. For 10 points, name this classical Chinese novel about Sun Wukong’s trip to India. ","answer":"ANSWER: Journey to the West [accept Xi You Ji; or Hsi-yu chi; or Monkey] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"6. This war was partially sparked by the theft of a silver star from the Church of the Nativity. During this war, a noncombatant used a namesake rose diagram to visualize patient mortality statistics. Roger Fenton photographed this war’s battlefields, and the Victoria Cross was introduced in this war’s aftermath. Colin Campbell and his “Thin Red Line” held off a cavalry charge during a battle in this war where the Earl of Cardigan misinterpreted orders. “The Lady with a Lamp,” Florence Nightingale, nursed men injured during this war’s Battle of Balaclava. For 10 points, the Charge of the Light Brigade occurred during what war fought over a Black Sea peninsula? ","answer":"ANSWER: Crimean War "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"7. The third movement of a piece by this composer opens with a written-out accelerando and ritardando that follows the Fibonacci sequence played by the xylophone. In a piece by this composer, trombone glissandos interrupt a clarinet melody modeled after the Leningrad Symphony’s “march” theme. Two bassoons play the same melody a minor sixth apart in the “Game of Pairs” movement of one of this composer’s works. This composer produced works in the “night music” style like Music for Strings, Percussion and Celesta and a Concerto for Orchestra. For 10 points, name this Hungarian composer of the opera Duke Bluebeard’s Castle. ","answer":"ANSWER: Béla (Viktor János) Bártok "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"8. Bredt’s Rule states that this interaction cannot be located at the bridgehead position of small bridged bicyclic molecules. The number of these interactions in a fatty acid is placed before “delta” in one form of fatty acid nomenclature. A property known as these interactions’ “equivalent” quantifies the level of unsaturation of a compound. Imines contain one of these interactions between carbon and nitrogen atoms. Two carbons that participate in this interaction are modeled by sp 2 (“s p two”) hybridization. These interactions involve one sigma bond and one pi bond. For 10 points, name these covalent bonds in which four electrons are shared. ","answer":"ANSWER: double bond [prompt on bonds or covalent bonds] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"9. In the chapter “Stultifera Navis,” this philosopher links the emergence of the Ship of Fools motif to the decline of leprosy in Europe. A book by this philosopher contrasts a description of a timetable with the public execution of Robert-Francois Damiens. This philosopher coined the term épistéme to refer to the historical forces in which knowledge is embedded as part of his genealogical method for analyzing power in society. This philosopher described the creation of the “medical gaze” in his book The Birth of the Clinic. For 10 points, name this French philosopher of The Order of Things and Discipline and Punish. ","answer":"ANSWER: Michel Foucault [or Paul-Michel Foucault] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"0. This object isn’t blue, but it is taken instead of “gold” or “treasures,” for which a man has “no desire.” Chairs for “gentlemen” cover the hiding place of this object, which induces a “ringing” in one man’s ears. The “hellish tattoo” of this object haunts a man with “over-acuteness of the sense[s].” In a short story, a man commands “villains” to “tear up the planks” that hide this object. This object sounds like a “watch enveloped in cotton” after it is removed from a man with “the eye of a vulture” who is suffocated by the narrator of a short story. For 10 points, name this loudly beating object that titles an Edgar Allan Poe short story. ","answer":"ANSWER: the old man’s heart [or “The Tell-Tale Heart”] Tiebreaker. During this decade, Vogue photographer Lee Miller traveled to Europe, where she photographed herself lying naked in a certain leader’s bathtub. In this decade, portrait photographer Yousuf Karsh captured a British politician stoically grimacing while holding a chair. Magnum Photos was co-founded in this decade by Robert Capa, who also shot the “Magnificent Eleven” photos during it. During this decade, Ansel Adams documented the Manzanar Relocation Center and Alfred Eisenstaedt photographed a sailor kissing a nurse in Times Square. For 10 points, war photographs like Joe Rosenthal’s Raising the Flag on Iwo Jima were taken during what decade? "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this last king of Rome. This despot of Etruscan descent was overthrown after his son raped Lucretia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Tarquin the Proud [or Tarquinius Superbus; do not accept “Tarquinius Priscus”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] A noble with this name led the overthrow of Tarquin and became the new republic’s first consul with Lucretia’s husband. A later Roman figure with this family name committed suicide after losing the Battle of Philippi. ","answer":"ANSWER: Brutus [accept Lucius Junius Brutus; or Marcus Junius Brutus the Younger] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] After his overthrow, Tarquin led a league of city-states from this tribe against Rome at the Battle of Lake Regillus. Romans were descended from this tribe, whose namesake language evolved into the modern family of Romance languages. ","answer":"ANSWER: Latins [or Latin League] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this island whose inhabitants are divided into three groups, representing the stages of life, in the painting Where Do We Come From? What Are We? Where Are We Going? ","answer":"ANSWER: Tahiti "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Paul Gauguin’s depictions of Tahitian life are often described as this kind of art. This term was also used to describe the work of artists who painted without professional training, such as Henri Rousseau. ","answer":"ANSWER: primitive art [or primitivism; or naïve art] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] A primitive artist from this country named Jean Dubuffet produced many works in the art brut style. Henri Rousseau and Paul Gauguin were both artists from this country. ","answer":"ANSWER: France [or the French Republic] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] The residents of Gethen don’t have a fixed version of this concept in Ursula LeGuin’s novel The Left Hand of Darkness. Virginia Woolf’s “A Room of One’s Own” imagines a writer who is similar to Shakespeare except for this characteristic. ","answer":"ANSWER: sex [accept gender] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] In Octavia Butler’s Kindred, Dana is transported from her apartment in California to this American region during the antebellum era, where she is forced into slavery. ","answer":"ANSWER: the American South "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This author of the science fiction series Canopus in Argos is most famous for a novel featuring Anna Wulf’s diary entries. ","answer":"ANSWER: Doris Lessing "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this philosophical text that argues for a distinction between primary and secondary qualities. ","answer":"ANSWER: An Essay Concerning Human Understanding [or An Essay Concerning Humane Understanding] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] An Essay Concerning Human Understanding was written by this British empiricist philosopher. This philosopher’s Two Treatises of Government states that all humans have natural rights to “life, liberty, and property.” ","answer":"ANSWER: John Locke "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Locke’s empiricist ideas were refuted by this philosopher in a chapter-by-chapter rebuttal titled New Essays on Human Understanding. This philosopher stated that we live in “the best of all possible worlds” in his Théodicée. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gottfried Wilhelm (von) Leibniz "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this German physicist. He discovered a namesake series of spectral absorption lines from the Sun. ","answer":"ANSWER: Joseph Fraunhofer "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] The Fraunhofer lines are measured in nanometers, which indicate values of this quantity for light. This quantity is inversely proportional to frequency. ","answer":"ANSWER: wavelength [or lambda] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Diffraction gratings can be used to view the yellow doublet “D line” that is emitted by this alkali metal around 589 and 590 nanometers. Those are the same wavelengths of light produced by this element’s namesake vapor lamp. ","answer":"ANSWER: sodium [or Na] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this French Jewish artillery captain who was scandalously imprisoned on false treason charges. The horrible treatment of this man was lambasted by Émile Zola in the article “J’Accuse!” ","answer":"ANSWER: Alfred Dreyfus [or the Dreyfus affair] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This future Prime Minister of France published Zola’s “J’Accuse” in his newspaper, L’Aurore. Nicknamed “The Tiger,” this politician represented France at the Treaty of Versailles. ","answer":"ANSWER: Georges Clemenceau "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This man covered the Dreyfus Affair as a correspondent for the Neue Freie Presse. Witnessing Dreyfus’ shabby treatment may have inspired this man to found the World Zionist Organization. ","answer":"ANSWER: Theodor Herzl "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this city where Nin and Miller were frequent guests of Gertrude Stein. “Lost Generation” writers like Ernest Hemingway and F. Scott Fitzgerald congregated in this French city. ","answer":"ANSWER: Paris "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] In need of money, Nin wrote many works in this genre that were compiled into the collections Delta of Venus and Little Birds. This genre, which Nin called “as indispensable as poetry,” also includes John Cleland’s Fanny Hill. ","answer":"ANSWER: erotic literature [or erotica; accept pornography or pornographic literature] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Nin published “An Unprofessional Study” of the works of this author, whose own erotic novel about Constance Reid’s affair with the gamekeeper Oliver Mellors led Penguin Books to be tried for obscenity. ","answer":"ANSWER: D. H. Lawrence "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Give the Arabic term for the discipline of interpreting sharia, whose four Sunni branches are Maliki, Shafi’i, Hanbali and Hanafi. ","answer":"ANSWER: fiqh "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Part of fiqh involves interpreting the Sunnah, or the teachings and deeds of this central Islamic prophet who received the Quran from God. ","answer":"ANSWER: Muḥammad ibn ʿAbdullāh "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Fiqh also involves interpreting these texts, which consist of compilations of the sayings and actions of Muhammad. These texts are authenticated by analysis of the chain of narrators who have transmitted them. ","answer":"ANSWER: hadīths [or aḥādīth] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this process, the fusion of two gametes to form an embryo. ","answer":"ANSWER: fertilization [or double fertilization; accept word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Double fertilization has also been observed in two genuses of Gnetophyta, a division of this plant group whose name means “naked seed”. It includes the conifers and cycads. ","answer":"ANSWER: gymnosperms [or Acrogymnospermae] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] During double fertilization, pollen adheres to these structures on the tips of carpels. Pistils typically consist of these structures along with the style and ovary. ","answer":"ANSWER: stigmas "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this state which, according to a 1987 song, is where all of George Strait’s “exes live.” Willie Nelson hosts an annual 4th of July picnic in this state’s city of Austin. ","answer":"ANSWER: Texas [or “Ohio (Come Back to Texas)” or “All My Ex’s Live in Texas”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] According to the aforementioned song, all of George Strait’s exes live in Texas, but he “hangs his hat” in this other state. Elvis Presley's mansion, Graceland, is located in this state. ","answer":"ANSWER: Tennessee "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] In the song, George Strait claims to have an ex-girlfriend of this name who lives in Galveston. A woman with this name is told “I know this world is killing you” and “my aim is true” in an Elvis Costello song. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alisson "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this figure from Greek mythology, who, while hunting in the forest, was turned into a stag and devoured by his own dogs. ","answer":"ANSWER: Actaeon "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Actaeon was killed for incurring this goddess’s wrath after seeing her bathing. This virgin huntress, the twin sister of Apollo, is also known as Cynthia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Artemis "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] At the Temple of Artemis in Brauron, girls would imitate these animals in an initiation ritual. One of Artemis’s followers, Callisto, was turned into one of these animals by a jealous Hera after being seduced by Zeus. ","answer":"ANSWER: bears "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Give this three-word motto of architect Ludwig Mies van der Rohe that espouses a preference for simplicity and functionality. ","answer":"ANSWER: “less is more” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Mies van der Rohe, along with Le Corbusier, was a prominent figure in the “international style” of this general architectural movement. Robert Venturi, who rejected its lack of variety, was described as “post-[this movement].” ","answer":"ANSWER: modernism [accept word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Venturi’s wife and close collaborator, Denise Scott Brown, often designs these institutions. Alvar Aalto’s Baker House and a non-denominational chapel designed by Eero Saarinen are located at one of these institutions. ","answer":"ANSWER: university [or college] (Those buildings are located at MIT.) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this ethnic group that traditionally wore their hair in a single braid known as a “queue” and introduced the qipao [“CHEE-POW”] dress to China. The various tribes of this ethnic group were first united by Nurhaci [“noor-HAWCH-ee”]. ","answer":"ANSWER: Manchu [or Jurchen] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Under Nurhaci, the Manchus formed this dynasty by overthrowing the Ming dynasty. This dynasty reigned from 1644 to 1912, when it was overthrown in the Chinese Revolution. ","answer":"ANSWER: Qing Dynasty "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Nurhaci organized the Manchu army by placing each household into eight groups named for these objects. The Azure Dragon and a red pearl appear in one of these objects that represented the Qing dynasty. ","answer":"ANSWER: banners [or flags] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this element. This element is the central atom in amines, which are derivatives of ammonia. ","answer":"ANSWER: nitrogen [or N] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Diazonium salts are usually produced by treating it with a compound of sodium and this nitrogenous anion. This anion has the formula NO 2- [“N O two minus”]. ","answer":"ANSWER: nitrite [do not accept or prompt on “nitrate”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Aryl diazonium salts can be substituted by an element from this group in the Sandmeyer reaction. Elements in this group are often symbolized by an X when writing reactions in organic chemistry. ","answer":"ANSWER: halogens [or Group 17] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name these fruits. In the first poem in a collection titled for [these fruits] From Thistles, the speaker’s candle gives a “lovely light” even though it “burns at both ends.” ","answer":"ANSWER: figs "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This poet of the collection A Few Figs From Thistles wrote about a woman who dies weaving clothes for her freezing son in “The Ballad of the Harp Weaver.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Edna St. Vincent Millay "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Millay’s poem “Euclid alone has looked upon Beauty bare” is an example of this fourteen-line poetic form written largely in iambic pentameter. ","answer":"ANSWER: sonnets "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this composer who married Cosima, the daughter of Franz Liszt, after she left her previous husband Hans von Bulow. After this composer’s death, Cosima refused to allow his opera Parsifal to be staged outside of Germany. ","answer":"ANSWER: Richard Wagner "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Richard and Cosima Wagner named their son, Siegfried, after the hero of this Wagner tetralogy, which begins with Das Rheingold and ends with Gotterdammerung. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Ring Cycle [or Der Ring des Nibelungens; or The Ring of the Nibelung] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] After Wagner died, Cosima took over management of this theater, which Wagner built to showcase his work. This theater hosts an annual Wagner festival. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bayreuth Festival Spielhaus [or Bayreuth Festival Theater] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this layer of the Earth that contains the asthenosphere. It makes up about 84 percent of the Earth’s volume. ","answer":"ANSWER: mantle "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This “discontinuity” separates the Earth’s crust from the mantle. Its Croatian discoverer identified it by observing the refraction of P-waves and S-waves. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mohorovičić discontinuity [or the Moho discontinuity] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This is the most abundant metal by weight in the Earth’s mantle. It is particularly abundant along with iron in olivine and other mafic rocks. ","answer":"ANSWER: magnesium [or Mg] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this rival of Joseph Pulitzer who owned the New York Journal. This man’s newspapers published damning reviews of Citizen Kane, whose title character was based on him. ","answer":"ANSWER: William Randolph Hearst "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Hearst’s newspapers whipped up public support for the Spanish-American War by publishing exaggerated stories of violence on this Caribbean island, where the USS Maine sunk in Havana Harbor ","answer":"ANSWER: Cuba "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] During the lead-up to the Spanish American War, Hearst’s newspapers published inaccurate articles about Cuba’s governor Valeriano Weyler, whom they gave this nickname. The leader of the Bowery Boys gang, William Poole, also used this nickname. ","answer":"ANSWER: butcher [or “Butcher” Weyland; or Bill the Butcher] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this deceased wife of Maxim de Winter. This resident of Manderley never shared her cancer diagnosis with anyone, even her beloved maid Mrs. Danvers. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rebecca "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This granddaughter of the author of Trilby wrote Rebecca. Nat Hocken finds fifty dead birds on the floor of his children’s bedroom in her short story “The Birds.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Daphne du Maurier "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] George du Maurier’s prejudiced novel Trilby emphasizes that the evil musician Svengali is of this religion. A moneylender of this religion named Shylock asks whether people of this religion have eyes in The Merchant of Venice. ","answer":"ANSWER: Judaism [accept anything indicating being Jewish] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] After drawing yellow 6 times, you are inclined to believe you’re now more likely to draw a blue marble, but since the probability remains constant, you are actually experiencing this fallacy. ","answer":"ANSWER: gambler’s fallacy or Monte Carlo fallacy "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Since the probability of winning is 50%, you could determine your bet using the martingale approach, often used in roulette, which involves doing this to your bet if you lose. ","answer":"ANSWER: doubling your bet [accept equivalents] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Along with asylum judges and loan officers, officials in this sport are often subject to the gambler’s fallacy. Michael Lewis’s Moneyball describes how Billy Beane used sabermetrics to succeed in this sport. ","answer":"ANSWER: baseball Tiebreaker. Tartrazine is a synthetic dye that is commonly found in food coloring of this color. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name this color. Lead chromate makes up a pigment known as the “chrome” type of this color. ","answer":"ANSWER: yellow "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Bromothymol blue, one of these compounds, transitions from magenta to yellow before turning blue. These compounds, which include phenolphthalein, are particularly useful in titrations. ","answer":"ANSWER: pH indicators "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Some paints of this color are made of lead carbonate. Calcium hydroxide and titanium dioxide both naturally occur as powders of this color. ","answer":"ANSWER: white EXTRA To control the population of one of these insects, scientists have engineered a strain of them called OX513A [“OCKS-513-A”] that expresses a lethality trait. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] Name these insects whose examples include the genus Anopheles and the species Aedes aegypti. ","answer":"ANSWER: mosquitoes [or Culicidae] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"5. ","answer":"ANSWER: Zika fever [or Zika virus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"I","question":"[10] This other disease spread by Aedes mosquitoes commonly displays antibody-dependent enhancement, in which the immune system is “tricked” into worsening an infection. Like yellow fever, it may lead to severe hemorrhaging. ","answer":"ANSWER: dengue [“DENG-ee”] fever [or dengue virus]"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"1. In 2012, Amgen announced that it could independently reproduce only six out of fifty-three key papers studying these cells. In an epithelial-mesenchymal transition, these cells lose their anchoring to a solid surface. The region surrounding these cells, or microenvironment, is frequently acidic due to their high rate of anaerobic respiration in the Warburg [“VAR-burg”] effect. Cell culture research has been using these immortalized cells ever since some were unethically harvested from Henrietta Lacks’ cervix. Though these cells’ telomeres shrink, they surpass the Hayflick limit and continue dividing indefinitely. For 10 points, name these cells that form tumors. ","answer":"ANSWER: cancerous cells [or tumor cells; or neoplasms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"2. A soprano air by this composer begins with the ascending notes B – long E, followed by a dotted-eighth-sixteenth rhythm on a descending G-sharp – F-sharp – E. In Act III of one of this composer’s oratorios, the title character’s death is honored with a “Dead March”; earlier in that oratorio, the Witch of Endor raises the ghost of Samuel. The castrato aria “Ombra mai fu” opens this composer’s opera Serse. The air “I know that my Redeemer liveth” is from one of this composer’s oratorios; its librettist, Charles Jennens, penned the words “and he shall reign forever and ever” for its most famous chorus. For 10 points, name this composer who included the “Hallelujah Chorus” in his oratorio Messiah. ","answer":"ANSWER: George Frideric Handel [or Georg Friedrich Händel] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"3. Scientific racist William Ripley authored a plan to consolidate this industry during the Great Depression. A company in this industry clashed with San Joaquin Valley ranchers in the Mussel Slough Tragedy. Workers in Martinsburg, West Virginia initiated a “Great” 1877 strike in this industry. This industry’s black workers were unionized by A. Philip Randolph. Financiers associated with this industry bribed congressmen in the Credit Mobilier scandal. Eugene Debs went to jail for leading this industry’s workers in a strike against the Pullman Company. For 10 points, the Central Pacific and the Union Pacific were companies in what transportation industry that uses locomotives? ","answer":"ANSWER: railroad industry [accept train industry; prompt on transportation] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"4. While traveling in Italy, this author wrote a poem titled “Mignon” that asks “do you know the land where the lemon-trees grow?” The title character of a trilogy by this author joins the Tower Society after starring in a production of Hamlet. This poet of the Roman Elegies wrote a novella whose protagonist recites poems by Ossian to his unrequited love, who is married to Albert. The title character is buried under a linden tree after he commits suicide in that novel by this author, which kickstarted the Sturm und Drang movement. For 10 points, name this author of The Sorrows of Young Werther. ","answer":"ANSWER: Johann Wolfgang von Goethe "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"5. In one of these texts, a large group of people watches as a man illuminates “eighteen thousand lands to the east” and causes the universe to “quake in six ways.” Another of these texts ends with the declaration “gone, gone, gone beyond.” One of these texts uses a parable about a man who promises toys to his children to get them out of a burning house to illustrate the concept of “expedient means.” Subhuti talks to a sage in one of these texts named for its ability to cut through illusions. Many of these texts belong to the “perfection of wisdom” genre. For 10 points, name these Buddhist texts that include ones titled “Diamond,” Heart,” and “Lotus.” ","answer":"ANSWER: sutras [accept Lotus Sutra; accept Heart Sutra; accept Diamond Sutra] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"6. A pirate from this country named Skipper Clement led a peasant rebellion during its Count’s Feud. An enemy army crossed frozen straits to invade this country in the March Across the Belts. Ships that refused to pay this country’s Sound Toll were bombarded by its fortress of Elsinore. This country entered into a 126-year alliance with its (stress this word) northern neighbors after its queen Margaret I married Haakon VI. Questions surrounding the status of ethnic Germans led Austria and Prussia to invade this country’s duchy of Schleswig-Holstein. This country formed the Kalmar Union with Norway and Sweden. For 10 points, name this country ruled from Copenhagen. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kingdom of Denmark "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"7. While visiting this country, President Obama stated “America does not presume to know what is best for everyone” and proposed a “New Beginning” for US-Arab relations. A doctor whose parents immigrated to America from this country ran as a progressive challenger to Gretchen Whitmer in the Michigan gubernatorial Democratic primary. Despite her Indian heritage, Hillary Clinton advisor Huma Abedin is often accused of being a spy for this country’s Muslim Brotherhood. During the Arab Spring, protesters in Tahrir Square demanded the resignation of this country’s dictator Hosni Mubarak. For 10 points, name this country where Obama spoke at Cairo University. ","answer":"ANSWER: Egypt (The Michigan candidate is Abdul El-Sayed) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"8. A scholar from this place uses Cavalieri’s principle that each solid body is made of an infinite number of planes to imagine Letizia Alvarez de Toledo’s “single volume.” People living near circuit 15-94 in this place study the phrase “O Time thy pyramids.” Purifiers living in this place attempt to destroy anything that isn’t one of the Vindications. This place causes mass suicide among readers of The Plaster Cramp and The Combed Thunderclap and is made up of “hexagonal galleries” filled with bookshelves containing all possible 410-page books. For 10 points, name this infinitely large setting of a Jorge Luis Borges short story. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Library of Babel [prompt on partial answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"9. This nation’s Bohol province is home to over a thousand hills that turn brown during the dry season, an attraction known as the Chocolate Hills. The oldest Chinatown in the world is located in the Binondo neighborhood of this country’s capital. Many dishes in this country’s cuisine are served adobo style and make of use of the purple ube root. One of the world’s longest underground rivers runs through this nation’s Palawan Island. Tagalog is spoken in this nation, and its two largest islands are Luzon and Mindanao. For 10 points, name this island country with a presidential palace located in Manila. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Philippines "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"0. This scientist first theorized the tetraoxygen molecule to explain exceptions to Curie’s Law. This scientist used Abegg’s rule to derive his cubical atom theory, which Irving Langmuir built on to posit the octet rule. This scientist used electrolysis to be the first to produce heavy water. A class of compounds named for this scientist catalyzes the Friedel–Crafts alkylation of benzene. Boron trifluoride is a typical example of a group of compounds named for this man. Whether a species accepts or donates electron pairs is central to this scientist’s acid-base definition. For 10 points, name this American chemist who names “dot diagrams” that show bonding between atoms. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gilbert N. Lewis "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"1. An artist made two paintings depicting objects of this color to flank a portrait of Augustine Roulin in a rocking chair titled La Berceuse. That artist supposedly ate paint of this color, and used it liberally due to his consumption of foxglove and absinthe. An 1886 painting uses distorted perspective to depict an artist’s bedroom in a building of this color, where he temporarily lived with Paul Gauguin. That “House” was in Arles [“ARL”]. A Post-Impressionist artist painted crows over a landscape of this color, and made many still-lifes of flowers in this color during a rare period of optimism. For 10 points, which color dominates Vincent van Gogh’s depictions of wheatfields and sunflowers? ","answer":"ANSWER: yellow "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"2. A monarch of this name alienated his son by choosing the Duke of Newcastle as his grandson’s godfather. Citing rumors of an affair involving Bartolomeo Pergami, a king of this name introduced the Pains and Penalties Bill, which would have allowed him to divorce Caroline of Brunswick. At Dettingen, a monarch of this name became the last English king to lead troops into battle. The Jacobite uprising of 1745 was put down by a monarch of this name, whose son of the same name went insane due to undiagnosed porphyria. For 10 points, give this name of four kings from the House of Hanover, including one who ruled England during the American Revolution. ","answer":"ANSWER: George [or George I; or George II; or George III; or George IV] . "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"3. This character is called one of the “hapless, annoying, dumb-bunny girls” by the narrator of a Margaret Atwood story titled for this character. The speaker of a poem chooses “never to stoop” even though this character gives him “much the same smile” she gives anyone else. According to the speaker of that poem, this character’s “looks went everywhere” when she received a “bough of cherries” or a “white mule” from an “officious fool.” The giver of a “nine-hundred-years-old name” claims that this woman’s heart is “too soon made glad.” This woman was married to a nobleman from Ferrara who had her painted by Fra Pandolf. For 10 points, name this title character of a Robert Browning poem. ","answer":"ANSWER: the duchess [accept the duchess of Ferrara, or “My Last Duchess”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"4. The total value of this quantity is equal to the tensor product of its electronic and nuclear types, according to the Born–Oppenheimer approximation. An operator’s expectation value can be calculated by integrating over the operator sandwiched between this quantity and its complex conjugate. Born’s rule states that the square of the magnitude of this quantity gives a particle’s probability density function. Applying the Hamiltonian operator to this quantity gives a corresponding eigen-energy, according to the time-independent Schrödinger equation. For 10 points, name this quantity that has the information about the quantum state of a given particle, symbolized psi. ","answer":"ANSWER: wavefunction [accept psi before mentioned] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"5. A text by this philosopher asserts that the letter “a,” in a certain case, “remains silent, secret, and discreet as a tomb.” This philosopher coined the term “hauntology” in a book that lists ten plagues of the capital system and calls for the creation of a “new international.” This philosopher asserted that all discourse is bricoleur in a lecture at Johns Hopkins University later published as the essay “Structure, Sign, and Play.” This philosopher coined the term dif érance and wrote a book that discusses Saussure’s logocentrism while arguing that speech has been historically privileged over writing. For 10 points, name this deconstructivist philosopher who wrote Specters of Marx and Of Grammatology. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jacques Derrida [or Jackie Élie Derrida] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"6. A filmmaker from this country directed a loose remake of Leo McCarey’s Make Way For Tomorrow that features his trademark motionless “pillow shots.” That film set in this country is about an elderly couple who visit this country’s capital city to see their children, but are ignored by them. George Lucas says his use of wipe cuts is an homage to a director from this country whose film Hidden Fortress inspired the plot of Star Wars. That director from this country cast his recurring collaborator Toshiro Mifune in films like Throne of Blood and Yojimbo. For 10 points, name this home country of Akira Kurosawa, whose films include The Seven Samurai. ","answer":"ANSWER: Japan [or Nippon] (the film described in the first two lines is Yasujiro Ozu’s Tokyo Story) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"7. In the Katha Upanishad, Nachiketa visits a god of this domain, who teaches him about Atman and liberation. A hero who tries to kidnap the wife of a god of this domain becomes forever stuck to a chair with snakes coiled around him. Heracles rescues Alcestis by wrestling the Greek personification of this domain. The god of this domain in Hindu mythology is also the god of righteousness and is the father of Yudhishthira [“you-DHISH-tee-raw”], Yama. The Aztec god of this domain is named Mictlantecuhtli [“MIKT-lawn-TEH-koot-lee”]. The Greek personification of this domain is the twin of Hypnos and is named Thanatos. For 10 points, name this domain ruled by Hades. ","answer":"ANSWER: death [accept word forms like dying or the dead; accept underworld gods] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"8. Frederick Catherwood made detailed illustrations of this civilization’s ruins on an expedition with John Lloyd Stephens. Altar Q lists rulers from this civilization like King “18 Rabbit.” Descendents of this civilization’s inhabitants revolted during the Caste War. The Temple of Inscriptions attests to this civilization’s hieroglyphs and was built by Pacal the Great. Dredging has revealed that this civilization sacrificed humans and objects to the Sacred Cenote. During this civilization’s Classic period, cities like Copán and Palenque flourished. For 10 points, name these people of the Yucatan who built Chichen Itza. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mayan civilization "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"9. The speaker of one of this man’s poems claims that “Earth’s the right place for love” since he doesn’t “know where it’s likely to go better.” That poem describes a boy “whose only play was what he found himself” because he lived “too far from town to play baseball.” In another poem by this man, the speaker commands “stay where you are until our backs are turned,” and notes how one man’s apple orchard will never “get across” to disturb his neighbor’s pines. This poet of “Birches” included the refrain “good fences make good neighbors” in his poem “Mending Wall.” For 10 points, name this poet of “The Road Not Taken.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Robert Frost "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"0. The third largest one of these specific bodies has gained a distinctive “two tone” appearance through the accumulation of dark colored debris on one part of its surface. Another one of these objects has an albedo equal to roughly 1.38, making it the most reflective body in the solar system. The largest of these objects was visited by the Huygens [“HIGH-guns”] probe and features a thick orange atmosphere covering liquid hydrocarbon lakes. One of these objects called Mimas lies in the Cassini Division between its planet’s rings. For 10 points, Iapetus, Enceladus, and Titan are examples of what objects that orbit the sixth planet from the Sun? ","answer":"ANSWER: Saturn’s moons [or moons of Saturn; or natural satellites of Saturn; prompt on moons] Tiebreaker. During this period, seven Taoist sages gathered in a bamboo grove to escape politics and drink heavily. One general in this period staged a coup at the Gaoping Tombs. A different general during this period devised the Longzhen Strategy and may have invented the repeating crossbow. Sima Yi and Zhuge Liang appear in a narrative about this period by Luo Guanzhong that begins with the Yellow Turban Rebellion and fictionalizes Liu Bei’s victory over Cao Cao at the Battle of Red Cliffs. For 10 points, name this period of rivalry between the states of Wei, Shu, and Wu that titles an epic Chinese Romance. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this aria in which the central character wears a blood-stained wedding dress and imagines marrying her dead lover, Edgardo. It is generally regarded as the most famous “mad scene” in opera. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Il dolce suono” [or “The Sweet Sound”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The title character sings “Il dolce suono” in this composer’s opera Lucia di Lammermoor. This man also composed The Elixir of Love. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gaetano Donizetti "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The role of Lucia is played by singers with this voice type, such as Maria Callas and Dame Joan Sutherland. This female voice type has the highest vocal range of all of the classical voice types. ","answer":"ANSWER: soprano [accept coloratura soprano] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this event whose “trauma” titles a 1924 book by psychoanalyst Otto Rank. Rank posited that this event results in the first and most significant instance of “separation anxiety” in a person’s life. ","answer":"ANSWER: birth [accept equivalents such as conception; accept The Psychological Birth of the Human Infant: Symbiosis and Individuation; or The Trauma of Birth] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Both Mahler and Rank’s theories were inspired by this teacher and founder of psychoanalysis, who originated the idea of the Oedipus Complex and wrote The Interpretation of Dreams. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sigmund Freud "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Rank wrote a book titled for The Myth of the Birth of this figure. In Joseph Campbell’s “monomyth” theory, this figure refuses to heed the “Call to Adventure” before “Crossing the First Threshold.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the hero [or The Myth of the Birth of the Hero] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"3. John Keats poems are more thematically similar to contemporary prose than you might think. For 10 points each: 10] Keats dedicated an ode to this season of “mellow fruitfulness,” “gourds,” and “apples.” An Ali Smith novel titled for this season describes how Elisabeth Demand’s friendship with 101-year-old Daniel Gluck changes during Brexit. ","answer":"ANSWER: autumn [or “To Autumn”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Charles Arrowby pursues Hartley in Iris Murdoch’s book titled for this place. Keats described this place’s “eternal whisperings,” and it lulls the speaker into “a quiet sleep” in John Masefield’s most famous poem. ","answer":"ANSWER: the sea [or The Sea, the Sea or “To the Sea” or “Sea-Fever”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] This author read Keats’ letters while writing a novel about Lucy Honeychurch’s affair with George Emerson. His novel about the feuding Wilcox and Schlegel families inspired Zadie Smith’s On Beauty. ","answer":"ANSWER: E.M. (Edward Morgan) Forster (On Beauty was inspired by Forster’s Howards End) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] These observations, whose values differ greatly from the rest of a data set, may cause the means of small samples to be much higher than population means. ","answer":"ANSWER: outliers "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Many statistical hypothesis tests will yield misleading results if the data are not independent; one example is this test devised by Karl Pearson, which uses a sum of squared errors to determine the relationship between categorical variables. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pearson’s chi-squared test "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] In this paradox, a trend that arises in several different groups of data disappears when the data are combined. It may cause incorrect conclusions to be made about the causality between different variables. ","answer":"ANSWER: Simpson’s paradox [or reversal paradox; or amalgamation paradox; or Yule-Simpson effect] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name these frontier horsemen who rebelled against the Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth to form an independent hetmanate under Bogdan Khmelnytsky [“chmel-NIT-skee”]. One of these people named Yemelyan Pugachev led a revolt against Catherine the Great. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cossacks [accept Zaporozhian Cossacks or Don Cossacks] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Khmelnytsky is a national hero in this modern-day country, where many Cossacks settled along the Don River. Some paramilitary pro-Russian Cossacks have joined the separatist insurgency in this country’s Donbass region. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ukraine "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The Khmelnytsky Uprising initiated this historical period, in which Russia and Sweden repeatedly invaded Poland. Its name comes from the title of a Henryk Sienkiewicz [“SHEN-kyay-veech”] novel. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Deluge "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Give this surname of that artist, Orazio, and Orazio’s daughter, who was raped by Agostino Tassi. That woman with this surname alluded to her trauma over the incident in her painting Judith Beheading Holofernes. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gentileschi [accept Orazio Gentileschi; or Artemisia Gentileschi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Gentileschi’s Sleeping Venus was partially inspired by her time in Venice, where she studied the works of Giorgione and this artist of the Venus of Urbino. ","answer":"ANSWER: Titian [or accept either underlined portion of Tiziano Vecellio] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Gentileschi was inspired by an illustration from Cesare Ripa’s Iconologia to produce a self-portrait titled as an Allegory of [this subject]. That same Ripa illustration also inspired a Vermeer work, sometimes titled The Allegory of [this subject], in which a woman holds a trumpet and a book. ","answer":"ANSWER: painting [accept Self-Portrait as the Allegory of Painting; or The Allegory of Painting; or The Art of Painting; prompt on less specific answers like art] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this god who spared the remaining pirates by turning them into dolphins. This Greek god of wine became the twelfth Olympian after Hestia conceded her seat. ","answer":"ANSWER: Dionysus [or Bacchus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Dionysus was the son of Zeus and this mortal woman, the daughter of Cadmus. This woman died when Zeus revealed his true form to her. ","answer":"ANSWER: Semele "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] According to Nonnus, Dionysus invaded this region, where he defeated this region’s King Deriades. Dionysus also fought a battle with a river god from this region named Hydaspes. ","answer":"ANSWER: India "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Before sequencing, DNA is often copied using a “chain reaction” technique named after this enzyme. During replication, it adds nucleotides to the 3’ end of DNA after helicase unwinds the molecule. ","answer":"ANSWER: DNA polymerase [or polymerase chain reaction] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] In 1977, this British biochemist developed a method of sequencing DNA using dideoxynucleotides. He also determined the amino acid sequence of insulin. ","answer":"ANSWER: Frederick Sanger [or Sanger sequencing] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Because Sanger sequencing is only useful with smaller genomes, this method that involves “shredding” DNA into smaller fragments and sequencing them individually was introduced in 1979 for long DNA strands. ","answer":"ANSWER: shotgun sequencing "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this “repellant, almost revolting” decoration that titles a Charlotte Perkins Gilman short story. The narrator is forced to look at this object because her husband John has prescribed her a “rest cure.” ","answer":"ANSWER: “The Yellow Wallpaper” [prompt on partial answer] [10] ] “The Yellow Wallpaper” was published in an 1891 issue of The New England Magazine alongside “The Herons of Elmwood,” a poem by this writer of “The Song of Hiawatha.” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Despite publishing works by Gilman and Longfellow, The New England Magazine never matched the success of this literary periodical, which was edited by William Dean Howells. Julia Ward Howe’s “Battle Hymn of the Republic” was initially published in this magazine. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Atlantic Monthly "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"8. Speke named this place’s location after Queen Victoria. ","answer":"ANSWER: the source of the Nile [accept descriptive answers like the origin of the Nile; prompt on Lake Victoria; do not accept or prompt on Victoria Falls] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Speke was traveling with this explorer, who vigorously disagreed that Lake Victoria was the source of the Nile. In another adventure, this explorer snuck into Mecca disguised as a Pashtun pilgrim. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sir Richard Francis Burton "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Speke’s discovery was confirmed by this Welsh-American explorer, who circumnavigated Lake Victoria. More famously, this man discovered Dr. David Livingstone on the shores of Lake Tanganyika. ","answer":"ANSWER: Henry Morton Stanley "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this type of stress that acts parallel to a material’s cross section. Scissors apply this type of stress to cut paper. ","answer":"ANSWER: shear stress "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Stress and strain are proportional according to this law. This law alternatively says that for elastic materials, restoring force is proportional to displacement. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hooke’s law "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The shear modulus is equal to [read slowly] one-half times Young’s modulus over quantity 1 plus this value. It is found by dividing a material’s lateral strain by its corresponding axial strain. ","answer":"ANSWER: Poisson’s ratio [prompt on partial answer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this ballet, inspired by the stories of E. T. A. Hoffman, in which Franz becomes disillusioned with his love interest Swanhilda. Its score, composed by Leo Delibes, includes a noted “Waltz of the Hours.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Coppélia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The title character of Coppélia is one of these toys that is brought to life by a doctor. The title character of Igor Stravinsky’s Petrushka is one of these toys, as is the protagonist of Jonathan Dove’s opera The Adventures of Pinocchio. ","answer":"ANSWER: dolls [or puppets] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Two infatuated dolls perform this dance in Léonide Massine’s ballet La Boutique. This dance is traditionally performed to the “Infernal Galop” from Jacques Offenbach’s Orpheus in the Underworld. ","answer":"ANSWER: the can-can "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name these German paramilitary groups largely composed of jobless World War I veterans. They launched the Kapp Putsch in support of Erich Ludendorff. ","answer":"ANSWER: Freikorps [or Free Corps] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Friedrich Ebert, the President of this hyperinflation-ridden post-World War I German government, used the Freikorps to quell left-wing rebellions in the Ruhr and Bavaria. ","answer":"ANSWER: Weimar Republic [or Weimar Germany] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Adolf Hitler and his Nazi henchmen were denounced as “Freikorps bands of rowdies” in the aftermath of this failed 1923 putsch. It is named for the large pub where Hitler and his fellow revolutionaries gathered. ","answer":"ANSWER: Beer Hall Putsch [or Bierkeller Putsch; prompt on Munich Putsch] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this play in which Mr. and Mrs. Smith invite the Martins over for dinner. Later in this play, the Fire Chief arrives and recognizes the maid Mary as his first love. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Bald Soprano [or La Cantatrice Chauve] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The Bald Soprano is by this French-Romanian playwright. This author of The Rhinoceros included the recurring character Bérenger in his plays Exit the King and The Chairs. ","answer":"ANSWER: Eugène Ionesco [or Eugen Ionescu] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Ionesco’s fellow absurdist, Tom Stoppard, wrote a pseudo-sequel to this Shakespeare play focusing on its characters Rosencrantz and Guildenstern. Stoppard notably excludes this play’s most famous monologue, “To be, or not to be.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Hamlet [or The Tragedy of Hamlet, Prince of Denmark] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this country, located on the eastern rim of the Ring of Fire, that is home to the stratovolcanoes Chimborazo and Cotopaxi. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ecuador "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Ecuador controls this volcanic archipelago, which is home to an endemic species of giant tortoises. Charles Darwin developed his theory of natural selection while studying this archipelago’s finches. ","answer":"ANSWER: Galapagos Islands "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Since Ecuador’s colonial era, miners called hieleros have extracted this resource from Chimborazo. The 19th century “king” of this resource’s trade, Frederic Tudor, used sawdust to keep this resource insulated during transatlantic voyages. ","answer":"ANSWER: ice [prompt on “water”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this dialogue in which a personification of the Laws of Athens explains that a person cannot reject an individual law without rejecting all of society’s laws. ","answer":"ANSWER: Crito "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] In his namesake dialogue, Crito tries to convince this man to escape his jail cell, but is confused when he refuses. This teacher of Plato was sentenced to death for supposedly corrupting the youth of Athens. ","answer":"ANSWER: Socrates "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Chronologically, Crito follows this dialogue in which Socrates notes his reputation as the gadfly of Athens. In this dialogue, Socrates recounts how the Oracle of Delphi proclaimed him the wisest man. ","answer":"ANSWER: Apology [or The Apology of Socrates] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this man who fulfilled Salome’s [“SAL-oh-may’s”] request for a certain prophet’s head on a dish. ","answer":"ANSWER: Herod [or King Herod; or Herod the Tetrarch; or Herod Antipater; or Herod Antipas] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] King Herod fulfilled Salome’s request by beheading this prophet who baptized Jesus after calling him “the lamb of God.” Gabriel told this man’s father Zachariah that this man’s mother, Elizabeth, would give birth to him in menopause. ","answer":"ANSWER: St. John the Baptist [or John the Forerunner; or John the Baptizer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The Gospels state that John survived in the wilderness by eating locusts and this food. This is the second food mentioned in a common Biblical quote that calls Israel “a land flowing with” two kinds of food. ","answer":"ANSWER: honey "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this poet. Many of his Pythian Odes, like the one calling Hippocleas one of “Sparta’s warlike sons,” are dedicated to winners of athletic competitions. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pindaros "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] This Cavalier poet called his love a “slug-a-bed” in “Corinna’s going a-Maying.” He tells some young women to “gather ye rosebuds while ye may” in the most famous poem from his Hesperides. ","answer":"ANSWER: Robert Herrick "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] The death of the “prince of mimics” inspired this Roman to write a poem “On the Death of Corinna’s Parrot.” His Metamorphoses serves as a collection of mythical transformations. ","answer":"ANSWER: Publius Ovidius Naso "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name this Pennsylvania battlefield where, decades earlier, Abraham Lincoln promised that “government of the people, by the people, for the people, shall not perish from the earth.” Lincoln’s speech at this location begins with the phrase “fourscore and seven years ago.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Gettysburg [or the Gettysburg Address] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"4. ","answer":"ANSWER: “under God” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] This Massachusetts politician delivered a two hour-long keynote speech before Lincoln at Gettysburg. He served as John Bell’s running mate on the Constitutional Union Party ticket in the 1860 presidential election. ","answer":"ANSWER: Edward Everett "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Name these types of catalysts that function even though the reactants and catalyst are in different phases. ","answer":"ANSWER: heterogeneous catalysts "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Heterogeneous catalysts typically consist of a layer of expensive catalyst on a cheaper support, such as this element’s “activated” form. Other forms of this element include charcoal and graphite. ","answer":"ANSWER: carbon [or C] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Another example of heterogeneous catalysis uses these aluminosilicate materials, which are commonly used for fluid catalytic cracking in refineries. Their name means “boiling rock” in Greek. ","answer":"ANSWER: zeolites Tiebreaker. Many herbivores have developed strategies to digest cellulose fibers in plants. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] Although this East Asian animal has the teeth and digestive system of a typical carnivore, scientists are still baffled by its diet, which consists almost exclusively of bamboo. ","answer":"ANSWER: giant panda [or Ailuropoda melanoleuca] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] This term is used for animals such as cattle which regurgitate food as cud and then rechew it, allowing them to break down cellulose with the help of bacteria. ","answer":"ANSWER ruminants [or rumination] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"J","question":"[10] In contrast to rumination, horses and rabbits use this digestive process in which bacteria in the cecum [“SEE-cum”] and large intestine help break down food that has only been chewed once. ","answer":"ANSWER: hindgut fermentation [accept hindgut fermenters; prompt on fermentation]"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"1. In Welsh myth, one of these creatures uses special forks to prop his eyelids open, and refuses to marry his daughter Olwen to the hero Culhwch [“KILL-hwick”]. One of these creatures is killed by Heracles after he steals the cattle of Geryon. According to legend, one of these creatures named Benandonner fought Finn MacCool on a basalt formation in Northern Ireland. A harp that plays itself and a goose that lays golden eggs are stolen from one of these creatures, causing him to shout “fee-fi-fo-fum, I smell the blood of an Englishman!” For 10 points, name these creatures, one of whom is killed in the story “Jack and the Beanstalk.” ","answer":"ANSWER: giants "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"2. Walter Pater described one of this artist’s subjects as a “vampire” who is “older than the rocks among which she sits.” A scroll reading “virtutem forma decorat,” surrounded by a laurel and palm leaf, is painted on the reverse of a portrait by this artist. This artist used red chalk for a work believed to be his only self-portrait. This artist of Ginevra de’ Benci painted Cecilia Gallerani holding a weasel in his Lady With an Ermine. His best-known portrait depicts a winding road behind the subject, who is lacking eyebrows. That portrait, known as La Gioconda, utilizes sfumato to create its subject’s enigmatic smile. For 10 points, name this artist who painted Lisa Gherardini in his Mona Lisa. ","answer":"ANSWER: Leonardo da Vinci [accept either underlined portion] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"3. This novel ends with the protagonist stammering “Me? Me?” in response to her lover’s statement “you your own best thing.” In this novel dedicated to “sixty million and more,” Amy helps the protagonist give birth to a baby on the banks of the Ohio River. A man with a “tobacco tin” heart comes to visit this novel’s protagonist at her “spiteful” home on 124 Bluestone Road. Denver and Paul D try to help the protagonist of this novel come to terms with her memories of Sweet Home plantation. Sethe is haunted by the ghost of her dead slave daughter in, for 10 points, what Toni Morrison novel? ","answer":"ANSWER: Beloved "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"4. This element can form a polyatomic anion solely consisting of 29 atoms of this element. When dissolved in a strong acid, this element turns into a bright blue paramagnetic solution. Sodium thiosulfate is often used in a type of titration that is named for this element’s “-metry,” often used for volumetric analysis. This element’s namesake “clock” reaction involves its interconversion between elemental and negatively charged ionic forms. This element is found in Lugol’s solution, which is used to detect starches in solution. This heaviest diatomic element normally sublimes to form a violet-colored gas. For 10 points, name this heaviest stable halogen. ","answer":"ANSWER: iodine [or I] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"5. An Austro-Hungarian monarch with this name was stabbed to death in Geneva by the Italian anarchist Luigi Lucheni. St. Petersburg’s Winter Palace was built by a monarch of this name who led Russia into the Seven Years War. Another monarch with this name claimed to possess the “heart and stomach of a king,” despite her “weak and feeble body,” in the Tilbury Speech. That monarch with this name employed the spymaster Francis Walsingham, who helped her survive the Ridolfi and Babbington plots. For 10 points, give this name of a “Virgin Queen” whose navy defeated the Spanish Armada. ","answer":"ANSWER: Elizabeth [or Elizabeth I; or Empress Elizabeth of Russia; or Empress Elisabeth of Austria] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"6. In this novel, a woman observes that happiness is “but the occasional episode in a general drama of pain” after she learns that the protagonist asked to be buried in an unconsecrated grave. After Joshua Jopp leaks his love letters, the title character of this novel is subjected to a skimmington ride with his lover Lucetta Le Sueur. When the title character goes bankrupt, he is forced to sell his grain business to his former accountant Donald Farfrae. The title character swears off alcohol after drunkenly selling his wife and child to a sailor for five guineas. For 10 points, Michael Henchard appears in what Thomas Hardy novel about a disgraced town official? ","answer":"ANSWER: The Mayor of Casterbridge "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"7. The tremolo-heavy “glide guitar” style of a musician from this non-US country is featured in a song that begins with the lyrics “when I look at you/ oh, I don’t know what’s real.” “When You Sleep” appears on Loveless, the 1991 masterpiece of a band from this country credited with popularizing shoegaze. A singer from this country describes “broken bottles under children’s feet” and “bodies strewn across the dead-end street” in a song that begins with the statement “I can’t believe the news today.” A band from this country recorded the hit songs “Pride (In The Name of Love)” and “Sunday, Bloody Sunday.” For 10 points, name this country where Bono founded U2 in Dublin. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ireland "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"8. An essay by Jonathan Parry examines the role of these things in Hindu rituals. An essay claims that these things have a personality or spirit described by the Polynesian terms hau and mana. The alliance theory of Claude Lévi-Strauss describes women as the “supreme” of these things. One thinker claimed these things were a “total prestation,” meaning that reciprocity was actually obligatory to their use. The Pacific Northwest tradition of potlatch and the Trobriand islanders’ kula ring are two different customs in which these things are exchanged. For 10 points, Marcel Mauss’ magnum-opus is titled for what type of item that is given without an expected return or payment? ","answer":"ANSWER: gifts [accepts equivalents like presents] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"9. This ruler feuded with Pope Vigilius during the Three-Chapter controversy. Victories at Tricamarum and Ad Decimum helped this ruler depose Gelimer and retake control of North Africa from the Vandals. An angry mob crowned Hypatius as emperor during a riot against this ruler that began as a scuffle between Blues and Greens in the Hippodrome. This ruler, who faced the Nika Revolt, employed Tribonian to write the Corpus Juris Civilis. Procopius’ Secret History chronicles how this ruler jockeyed for power with his general Belisarius and his consort Teodora. For 10 points, name this Byzantine emperor who built the Hagia Sophia and issued a namesake law code. ","answer":"ANSWER: Justinian I [or Justinian the Great; prompt on partial answer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"0. Early work in this technology was spearheaded by Henry Fox Talbot, who introduced a process in which potassium bromide was used to wash paper coated with silver iodide called the calotype. Its inventor is widely considered to be the Frenchman Nicephore Niepce [“nee-say-for NEE-epps”]. Another early form of this technology, which involved a silver-copper plate reacting with mercury vapor, is named for Louis Daguerre. Processes involved in this technology may produce negatives that are printed to reverse coloration. For 10 points, George Eastman popularized the use of what type of technology marketed by Polaroid and Kodak? ","answer":"ANSWER: photography [or photographs; accept any answer referring to cameras; accept photographic film; prompt on pictures or images or film] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"1. A hunchbacked bandleader who played this instrument recorded “A-Tisket, A-Tasket” with Ella Fitzgerald. Chick Webb played this instrument, as did a bandleader known for performing a medley of Leonard Bernstein’s West Side Story. The hard bop album Moanin’ was recorded by a player of this instrument and his “Jazz Messengers.” Dave Brubeck wrote “Take Five” to showcase Joe Morello’s ability on this instrument. With bass, guitar, and piano, this instrument makes up a typical jazz rhythm section. For 10 points, Art Blakey and Buddy Rich played what percussion instrument, which requires sticks? ","answer":"ANSWER: drums [prompt on percussion; prompt on specific kinds of drums, like snare drum or bass drum] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"2. Karl Barth’s book The Epistle to the Romans cites this philosopher’s notion of the “infinite qualitative distinction.” A text by this philosopher uses Mozart’s operas as an example of the musical-erotic and distinguishes between the views of Don Juan and Faust. This philosopher of a Concluding Unscientific Postscript divided life into aesthetic, ethical, and religious stages. He discussed the “teleological suspension of the ethical” in a text that uses the example of Abraham’s willingness to sacrifice Isaac as an example of the “Knight of Faith.” For 10 points, name this Danish philosopher of Either/Or and Fear and Trembling. ","answer":"ANSWER: Søren Kierkegaard [prompt on Johannes de Silentio or Johannes Climacus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"3. This author wrote a novel about Eve Frame’s disintegrating marriage to the radio actor “Iron Rimm” shortly after his own contentious divorce with Claire Bloom. Another novel by this author of I Married a Communist is framed as a conversation between the protagonist and his psychoanalyst Dr. Spielvogel. Many of this author’s works are set in and around his hometown of Newark, New Jersey and are narrated by his recurring character Nathan Zuckerman. The title character of this author’s first major novel recounts his sexual escapades, which feature a woman known as “The Monkey” and a piece of liver. For 10 points, name this author of Portnoy’s Complaint. ","answer":"ANSWER: Philip Roth "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"5. During this presidential election, South Carolina’s Red Shirts implemented the Mississippi Plan to intimidate black voters, leading to the election of Wade Hampton as governor. After this election, Joseph Bradley was controversially appointed to fill Justice David Davis’ spot on a committee. Despite the release of the Mulligan Letters, James G. Blaine was the frontrunner for this election’s Republican nomination until Roscoe Conkling engineered his defeat. The result of this election was confirmed by the Electoral Commission and settled by a compromise that ended Reconstruction in the South. For 10 points, name this election in which Samuel Tilden lost to Rutherford B. Hayes. ","answer":"ANSWER: election of 1876 [prompt on ‘76] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"6. A passage that describes this figure without naming him states that he “stood poised on the higher horizon, drew near and suspended hung, two bow-lengths away.” During one event, this figure took a man to a tree at the end of the seventh layer of heaven, called the Sidrat al-Muntaha, that this figure could not pass. This figure commanded a man to recite, “Read! In the name of your Lord, who has created all that exists” in a cave on Mount Hira. This figure, who brought the horse Buraq to Muhammad during the Night Journey, will blow a trumpet blast when Jesus returns to Earth. For 10 points, name this archangel who revealed the Quran to Muhammad and has a namesake horn. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gabriel [or Jibril; or Jibra’il] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"7. While living in this place, a writer used a cerium alloy to whittle light-flints, an experience that writer recalled in the “Cerium” chapter of his memoir The Periodic Table. In a different book, the narrator describes how the “flames” of this place “consumed [his] faith forever” while repeating the phrase “never shall I forget.” After a man in this place asks “where is God?” that narrator imagines replying that God is “hanging here from this gallows.” In a 1960 memoir, this location’s guards shout “men to the left, women to the right” as they separate Eliezer from his mother and sisters. For 10 points, Elie Wiesel’s Night describes the horrors of what Nazi concentration camp in Poland? ","answer":"ANSWER: Auschwitz-Birkenau [prompt on concentration camps] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"8. A piece by this composer for violin and piano opens with a repeated 16th-note, 32nd-rest, 32nd-note rhythm on a melody that begins with the notes [read slowly] G-flat, A-flat, G-flat, A-flat, B-flat. This composer imitated the call of a scarlet tanager in the third movement scherzo of a string quartet that begins with a pentatonic viola solo. This composer of 8 Humoresques for piano included a notable English horn solo in the Largo second movement of his most famous symphony. This composer’s ninth symphony was influenced by the African-American spirituals he encountered on a trip to Iowa. For 10 points, name this Czech composer of the New World Symphony. ","answer":"ANSWER: Antonín (Leopold) Dvořák "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"9. It’s not Kenya, but Frederick Lugard pioneered indirect rule while administering the colony that became this country. The earliest evidence of ironworking in Africa was discovered in this country’s valley of Taruga, which was occupied by the Nok people. After the abolition of slavery, this country’s port of Bonny became a center of the palm oil trade. Royal Dutch Shell’s treatment of this country was protested by Ken Saro-Wiwa. During the late 1960s, this country’s Igbo people seceded to form the breakaway Republic of Biafra. For 10 points, name this country once administered by the British from Lagos. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nigeria "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"0. The production of this compound in the kidney with the aid of 1-alpha-hydroxylase is stimulated by parathyroid hormone. A precursor of this compound called ergosterol is found in the cell membranes of fungi. One form of this compound called cholecalciferol is converted from 7-dehydrocholesterol during a “cutaneous synthesis.” Intestinal absorption of phosphate is increased by this vitamin, whose deficiency may lead to bowed legs and greater susceptibility to fractures in young children. For 10 points, rickets is caused by a deficiency in what vitamin that works to increase calcium uptake in the body and is produced in the skin with the help of sunlight? ","answer":"ANSWER: vitamin D [accept Vitamins D1, D2, or D3] Tiebreaker. An early holder of this position was selected because a dove miraculously landed on his head. Theodora and Marozia of the Theophylacti family installed numerous lovers in this position during a period known as the Pornocracy. After conquering the Exarchate of Ravenna, Pepin the Short donated the land to the holder of this position. In a controversy over the right of investiture, one holder of this position was the recipient of Henry IV’s Walk to Canossa. The holder of this position resided in Avignon during the 14th century “Babylonian Captivity.” For 10 points, name this position held by the Bishop of Rome, who leads the Catholic Church. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this familial relation that titles a photo of Florence Owens Thompson, who forlornly looks into the distance in a Dorothea Lange photo titled for a Migrant [one of these people]. ","answer":"ANSWER: mother [or Migrant Mother; accept equivalents to “mother” like mom] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Sally Mann, who controversially photographed her own children for the book Immediate Family, depicted the aftermath of this event in What Remains. Matthew Brady’s best-known photographs depict this event. ","answer":"ANSWER: the American Civil War "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This woman photographed a nude, pregnant Demi Moore for the August 1991 Vogue magazine cover. She photographed John Lennon clutching his wife, nude, on the day of Lennon’s death. ","answer":"ANSWER: Annie Leibovitz "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this Christina Rossetti poem in which the sisters Laura and Lizzie are tempted by the fruit-selling title creatures, who chant “come buy, come buy!” ","answer":"ANSWER: “Goblin Market” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This author heavily edited his sister’s novel The Adventures of David Simple after it was first released. He is more famous for writing about Sophia Western’s foundling love in Tom Jones. ","answer":"ANSWER: Henry Fielding "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Love in a Cold Climate and The American Way of Death were written by the sisters Nancy and Jessica, who shared this surname. Nancy and Jessica’s sister Diana, who also had this surname, was married to the British fascist Oswald Mosley. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mitford sisters "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this British Marxist historian who discussed the Invention of Tradition in a book he co-edited with Terence Ranger. He is perhaps best known for a trilogy of works that begins with The Age of Revolution. ","answer":"ANSWER: Eric Hobsbawm "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The Age of Revolution is the first in Hobsbawm’s trilogy about the “long” version of this century, which Hobsbawm claims began with the French Revolution. The unification of Italy occurred during this century. ","answer":"ANSWER: the 19th century [or the 1800s] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Hobsbawm’s Age of Revolution begins in 1789 and ends in this year. Lajos Kossuth’s failed Hungarian Revolution took place during this year. ","answer":"ANSWER: 1848 [prompt on 48] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this mathematical operation. According to the fundamental theorem of calculus, it is the inverse of integration. ","answer":"ANSWER: differentiation [or word forms like differentiating; or taking the derivative; or partial derivative; or similar answers that indicate a derivative] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] At these points, a function’s first partial derivatives are all zero, but it is not a local extremum. They are named for a piece of equipment that curves differently in orthogonal directions. ","answer":"ANSWER: saddle points [prompt on minimax points] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This matrix, named for a German mathematician, contains all of a function’s second-order partial derivatives. It is equal to the transpose of the Jacobian of a function’s gradient. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hessian matrix "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this island, called “the Galapagos of the Indian Ocean” due to its diversity of unique flora. ","answer":"ANSWER: Socotra "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This country officially governs Socotra, although the island has been practically annexed by the UAE following the outbreak of civil war in this country. Houthi forces control its capital city, Sana’a. ","answer":"ANSWER: Yemen "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The UAE’s presence on Socotra could be used to gain power over shipping through this gulf to Socotra’s west, a major route for oil tankers. This gulf separates Yemen from Somalia and is named for a Yemeni city. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gulf of Aden [or Gulf of Berbera] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] An essay by this author characterizes literary heroes as either Don Quixote or Hamlet depending on their decisiveness. A conflicted party guest is nicknamed the “Hamlet of the Shchigrovsky District” in a story from this author’s Sportsman’s Sketches. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ivan Sergeyevich Turgenev "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"5. ","answer":"ANSWER: Miguel de Cervante "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This member of Spain’s Generation of ‘98 attempted to interpret Don Quixote independently of Cervantes’ influence in his essay “Our Lord Don Quixote.” He’s better known for novels like Abel Sanchez and Niebla. ","answer":"ANSWER: Miguel de Unamuno "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Many scientists believe that this monotreme species secretes venom from its hind limbs for the purpose of competing for mates, and not as defense against predators. ","answer":"ANSWER: duck-billed platypus [or Ornithorhynchus anatinus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The slow loris is believed to be only venomous member of this taxonomic order. Other members of this order include lemurs, chimpanzees, and quiz bowl players. ","answer":"ANSWER: primates "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The “northern short-tailed” and “American short-tailed” variety of these mole-like mammals are both venomous. Their “Etruscan” variety is considered the smallest mammal by mass. ","answer":"ANSWER: shrews [or Soricidae; or northern short-tailed shrew; or American short-tailed shrew; or Etruscan shrew] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name these vehicles that were recalled en masse in 2016 due to a glitch that caused their battery packs to overheat and catch on fire. ","answer":"ANSWER: hoverboards [or self-balancing scooters] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Marty McFly rides a hoverboard in the second installment of this film series, whose first film sees Marty and Doc Brown travel to the 1950s in a time-travelling Delorean. ","answer":"ANSWER: Back to the Future "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] In Back to the Future II, this bully travels back in time to give himself a sports almanac, which his past self uses to become a Donald Trump-esque gambling mogul. ","answer":"ANSWER: Biff Tannen [accept either underlined portion] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Give this term for an event in which God reveals himself to a human being. This term with a Greek origin is an alternate name for the feast of Epiphany. ","answer":"ANSWER: theophany "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This apostle converted to Christianity after Jesus spoke to him on the road to Damascus. His attempts to convert Gentiles are the primary subject of the book of Acts. ","answer":"ANSWER: Saint Paul of Tarsus [or Saul of Tarsus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] In Acts, the Holy Spirit descends upon the Apostles on this feast day, causing them to speak in tongues. This holy day occurs seven weeks after Easter. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pentecost [or White Sunday or Whitsunday] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Identify this object used by a KGB agent to fire a poisonous ricin pellet at Georgi Markov in London. ","answer":"ANSWER: an umbrella "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Markov was exiled from this communist country during the rule of dictator Todor Zhivkov. Zhivkov came to prominence as the police chief in its capital city, Sofia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bulgaria "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"1. ","answer":"ANSWER: Turks [or Turkish] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this character who titles a novel narrated by John Wheelwright. He dies while protecting a group of Vietnamese children from a grenade at an airport. ","answer":"ANSWER: Owen Meany [prompt on Meany] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] A Prayer for Owen Meany was written by an author with this surname. A much earlier author with this surname wrote the short stories “The Legend of Sleepy Hollow” and “Rip Van Winkle.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Irving [accept John Irving or Washington Irving] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] In the novel, Owen kills Tabitha while taking part in this activity. An Ernest Thayer poem about this activity notes that “there was no joy in Mudville” after Cooney, Barrows, and Casey failed at this activity. ","answer":"ANSWER: baseball "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this home state of the Regionalist painter John Steuart Curry. Curry’s mural Tragic Prelude, which depicts a giant bearded man clutching a rifle and bible, is housed in this state’s Capitol Building. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kansas [the first Curry painting mentioned is Baptism in Kansas] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This other member of the Regionalist movement depicted his native Iowa in a portrait of his sister and dentist, the latter of whom holds a pitchfork, titled American Gothic. ","answer":"ANSWER: Grant Wood "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Wood’s painting Parson Weem’s Fable shows Weems pulling back a curtain to reveal this person as a child, holding an axe. He is also depicted in Gilbert Stuart’s Lansdowne portrait. ","answer":"ANSWER: George Washington "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this minister to Louis XVI who published France’s first public budget. He attempted to reform France’s economy during the debt crisis caused by Louis’ decision to finance the American Revolution. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jacques Necker "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Summoned to discuss Necker’s proposed reforms in June 1789, the Third Estate found themselves locked out of their chambers; instead, they moved to this location, usually used for athletic events, where they swore an oath to pursue a constitution. ","answer":"ANSWER: a tennis court [or the Tennis Court Oath] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] A month after the Tennis Court Oath, an angry crowd reacted to Necker’s firing by storming this Parisian prison. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Bastille "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name these concepts whose origin is attributed to Empedocles. In the dialogue Timaeus, each of these things is associated with a particular Platonic solid. ","answer":"ANSWER: Classical elements [or the four elements] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Timaeus associates this “ever-living” and unstable element with the tetrahedron. Heraclitus considered this to be the fundamental element, unlike Thales, who favored this element’s counterpart, water. ","answer":"ANSWER: fire "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] In contrast to Ionian philosophers, this thinker from Samos believed numbers created harmony in the world. This philosopher, who abstained from eating meat and beans, theorized the “music of the spheres” and the “transmigration of souls.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Pythagoras of Samos "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this type of reaction. The Diels-Alder is a 4+2 “cyclo-” type of these reactions. ","answer":"ANSWER: addition reaction [accept cycloaddition] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] In the Michael addition, one of these species, such as a carbanion, attacks the carbonyl compound. Organolithium reagents and anions can be examples of these species, which attack positively charged atoms. ","answer":"ANSWER: nucleophiles "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The carbanion in the Michael addition has this charge. Halides also possess a charge of this negative number. ","answer":"ANSWER: -1 [or negative one; do not accept or prompt on “one”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this goddess who emerged from the churning of the ocean sitting in a lotus plant. On the third night of Diwali, people light diyas and offer puja to welcome this goddess into their homes. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lakshmi [or Laxmi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Lakshmi is the consort of Vishnu in this religion, the majority religion in India. Texts from this religion include the Vedas and the Bhagavad Gita. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hinduism "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Lakshmi’s mount Olooka is one of these animals. In Greek myth, Demeter turned Ascalaphus into one of these animals out of anger following Hades’ abduction of Persephone. ","answer":"ANSWER: an owl [prompt on bird] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this piece in which the solo trumpet plays a motif with the notes (read slowly) B-flat, low C-sharp, high E, long E-flat, low C. According to the composer’s program notes, this piece’s strings represent “The Silence of the Druids.” ","answer":"ANSWER: The Unanswered Question "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The Unanswered Question was written by this American composer of the Concord Sonata and Three Places in New England. ","answer":"ANSWER: Charles Ives "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Ives composed a set of Variations on “My Country, ‘Tis of Thee” for this instrument, which Ives played. Players of this large keyboard instrument use a pedalboard to manipulate the sound produced by a set of pipes. ","answer":"ANSWER: pipe organ "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this Native American tribe that was subjected to the largest execution in US history after an uprising led by its chief Little Crow. ","answer":"ANSWER: Dakota [or Sioux; do not accept or prompt on “Lakota” or “Nakota”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This president commuted the death sentences of many of the captured Dakota warriors. This president, who served as a militia captain during Black Hawk’s War, opened up Indian Territory to white settlers by signing the Homestead Act. ","answer":"ANSWER: Abraham Lincoln "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The Dakota War took place in this modern-day US state. Little Crow and his tribe resided on land that is now this state’s capital, St. Paul. ","answer":"ANSWER: Minnesota "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this medieval Japanese text. Written by lady-in-waiting Sei Shonagon, it contains lists of “Irritating Things” and “Pleasant Things.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the Pillow Book [or Makura no Soshi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Authors like Ze’ami Motokiyo pioneered this form of medieval Japanese drama, similar to kabuki, in which short farces called kyogen are interspersed with more serious plays. Its performers typically wear masks. ","answer":"ANSWER: Noh [or Nogaku] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This Lady Murasaki work, written during Japan’s Heian period, is often considered the first modern novel. The title character of this novel is a womanizing prince who falls in love with Lady Fujitsubo. ","answer":"ANSWER: Tale of Genji [or Genji-monogatari] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this law in fluid mechanics. It states that the pressure drop of a fluid is proportional to the product of the pipe length times mu times flow rate, divided by pi times pipe radius to the fourth power. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hagen–Poiseuille [“PWAH-zoo-ee”] equation or law "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The mu term in Poiseuille’s equation represents the dynamic type of this physical quantity. This property quantifies a fluid’s resistance to shear or tensile stress. ","answer":"ANSWER: dynamic viscosity "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Poiseuille’s law is only valid for fluids that are incompressible and have this property. In these fluids, which include water, air, and glycerol, viscosity is independent of shear rates. ","answer":"ANSWER: Newtonian fluids Tiebreaker. This woman says that she has been “a stranger in [her] own land” because of her “father and brother.” For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this character who defies King Creon in order to give her brother Polynices the proper funeral rites. Haemon is devastated when this character hangs herself in a cave at the end of the play she appears in. ","answer":"ANSWER: Antigone [an-TIG-uh-nee] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Antigone is one of this classical Greek playwright’s Theban plays, which also include Oedipus Rex and Oedipus at Colonus. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sophocles "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This twentieth century French playwright adapted Sophocles’ Antigone in a staging designed to parallel the Vichy France regime. In his Antigone, tragedy is defined as “a film without a sound track.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Jean Anouilh [ah-noo-EEL] EXTRA Arthur Anderson and Charles Dibble made the first full English translation of this 12-book work after it was rediscovered by the scholar Angelo Bandini. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this text preserved in the Laurentian library. It was composed by the missionary Bernardino de Sahagun in conjunction with his students in Tlatelolco. ","answer":"ANSWER: Florentine Codex [prompt on partial answer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The Florentine Codex is one of the major sources on this empire’s practices, which included human sacrifices under rulers like Montezuma II. ","answer":"ANSWER: Aztec Empire "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] This interpreter to the conquistador Hernán Cortés appears in many of the Florentine Codex’ illustrations. Her child by Cortés, Martín, is considered one of Mexico’s first mestizos. ","answer":"ANSWER: La Malinche [or Doña Marina] This solid figure is represented by the Schläfli symbol {3,5}, and its volume equals roughly 8.66 times its edge length squared. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this solid whose four-dimensional analog is considered to be the hexacosichoron, or 600-cell. ","answer":"ANSWER: regular icosahedron "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Because the icosahedron is a convex, regular polyhedron, it is one of these five “solids” named for an ancient Greek thinker. ","answer":"ANSWER: Platonic solids "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] The icosahedron is considered a dual to this other Platonic solid, which is made up of pentagonal faces. ","answer":"ANSWER: regular dodecahedron The study introducing this test also asked children for etymologies of words like “blackboard.” “Thanksgiving.” and “Friday.” For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Name this linguistic test introduced by Jean Berko Gleason in which participants asked to provide a plural form to describe a pair of a fictional bird-like creature. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wug test "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Gleason conducted the wug test to examine the ability of these people to learn morphological rules. According to one hypothesis, these individuals are able to acquire language because they haven’t left the “critical period.” ","answer":"ANSWER: children [accept equivalents] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"K","question":"[10] Lydia White has done research on how this concept contributes to second language acquisition. Noam Chomsky put forth the “poverty of the stimulus” argument to argue for this theory, which suggests that certain structures and constraints are innate to all language. ","answer":"ANSWER: universal grammar [or UG]"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"1. This substance is mixed with water in an acidic soil called muskeg, which is commonly found in boreal forests. This substance is capable of storing up to 10 times more carbon dioxide than other ecosystems, leading to it being called the “world’s most efficient carbon sink.” It’s not coal, but the use of this substance as energy in Finland has raised global warming concerns. The genus Sphagnum makes up most of this substance, which dominates fens and quagmires. This substance consists of dead or decaying plant matter, primarily that of mosses. For 10 points, name this substance that accumulates in bogs. ","answer":"ANSWER: peat [or peat moss; accept bogland until “bogs” is read; prompt on organic matter; prompt on moss before “mosses”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"2. Merchants from this city smuggled relics out of Alexandria by covering them in pork to ward off Muslim authorities. This city’s mints produced a large silver coin called the grosso. This city’s Murano glassmakers were prohibited from traveling abroad by its ruling Council of Ten. Every Ascension Day, the ruler of this city dropped a ring into the water as part of a ceremony known as the “Marriage of the Sea.” The rulers of this “Most Serene Republic” resided in a palace overlooking St. Mark’s Square. For 10 points, leaders known as doges [“DOE-jiz”] ruled what maritime republic on the Adriatic Sea famous for its canals? ","answer":"ANSWER: Venice [or Venezia] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"3. The title character of this English-language play asks why some years have more eclipses than others, only to be told that he is “damned.” This play, which exists in “A” and “B” versions, includes a scene in which the phrase “homo, fuge” [“HO-mo FOO-gay”] appears on a man’s arm as he attempts to sign a contract. The title character of this play travels through time to play a prank on Pope Adrian and to visit Helen of Troy, of whom he asks “was this the face that launch’d a thousand ships?” Unlike Goethe’s adaptation of the same legend, this play ends with the title scholar being dragged to hell. For 10 points, name this Christopher Marlowe play about a man who sells his soul to Mephistopheles. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Tragical History of the Life and Death of Doctor Faustus [do not accept or prompt on Faust] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"4. One depiction of this figure may have been inspired by Agnolo Poliziano’s poem “La Giostra.” A wide canvas depicts this figure on the left as satyrs hold a lance and blow a conch into the ear of her sleeping lover. Simonetta Vespucci likely modeled as this figure for a painting in which a hora covers her with a cloak. The Three Graces stand to the left of this figure draped in red at the center of a painting set in an orange grove. A painting depicts Zephyr holding the nymph Chloris while he blows this figure to shore as she covers her nude body with her hair. For 10 points, Sandro Botticelli painted what Roman goddess standing atop a shell in a scene depicting her Birth? ","answer":"ANSWER: Venus [or Aphrodite] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"5. Some members of this phylum go through larval stages called planulae. An organism in this phylum can induce a life-threatening condition called Irukandji [“ee-roo-CON-jee”] syndrome. The presence of a box-shaped or cup-shaped body layout differentiates this phylum’s classes Cubozoa and Scyphozoa [“sigh-foh-ZOH-uh”]. In these organisms, the activation of a hair-like trigger causes the ejection of a venomous cell called a nematocyte. Animals in this phylum may alternate between two body morphologies: a sessile polyp phase and a motile medusa phase. For 10 points, name this aquatic phylum which includes sea anemones, corals, and jellyfish. ","answer":"ANSWER: cnidarians [or Cnidaria] [the “C” is silent] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"6. The founder of this party proposed a return to dual monarchy in the pamphlet The Resurrection of Hungary. This party elected the first female MP to the House of Commons, Constance Markievicz [“mar-kee-EV-itch”], and pursued the Armalite and ballot box strategy after the success of the Anti-H Block candidate Bobby Sands. Arthur Griffith formulated this party’s policy of abstentionism, which eventually led Fianna Fail [FEE-uh-nuh FOYL] to break away from this party under Eamon de Valera. This party’s military wing disarmed following Gerry Adam’s assent to the Good Friday Agreement, which ended the Troubles. For 10 points, name this Irish political party once linked with the Provisional IRA. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sinn Féin [“shin-FAYN”] [prompt on We Ourselves] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"7. Members of this religious sect call Sunday school “First Day School” because this sect uses a traditional calendar with numbered days and months. This sect’s core values are known as “testimonies” and can be memorized with the acronym SPICES. Books of Discipline are issued at this sect’s yearly meetings, some of which practice “waiting worship” instead of “programmed worship.” Early members of this movement did not swear oaths in courtrooms and used “thee” as a common pronoun. This sect’s founder George Fox encouraged individuals to sit in silence in order to hear the “inner light” of God. For 10 points, name this Christian sect that was followed by William Penn. ","answer":"ANSWER: Quakers [or the Religious Society of Friends; or the Friends Church] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"8. The reaction of one of these compounds with carbon monoxide and water was once used to produce acrylic acid. Aldehydes can be converted to these compounds via di-bromo-olefins in the Corey–Fuchs reaction. Treating these compounds with a strong base results in their namesake zipper reaction, which converts one of these compounds to their terminal type. These compounds contain at least one carbon that is sp [“ess pee”] hybridized. Lindlar’s catalyst converts these compounds to alkenes. Acetylene is the simplest one of these compounds. For 10 points, name these compounds that contain carbon-carbon triple bonds. ","answer":"ANSWER: alkynes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"9. In one of this author’s plays, two men sing about a dog named Blue who “treed a possum in Noah’s Ark.” The protagonist of that play by this author recounts how his co-worker, Brownie, was fired for smuggling a watermelon under his coat. This author’s most famous play ends with a mentally handicapped man named Gabriel attempting to blow a trumpet. In that play by this author, the protagonist has an affair with Alberta and refuses to let his son Cory play football. This author’s play about the garbage truck driver Troy Maxson is the sixth work of his Pittsburgh Cycle. For 10 points, name this African-American playwright of Fences. ","answer":"ANSWER: August Wilson "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"0. This man is the dedicatee of Joyce Carol Oates’ “Where Are You Going, Where Have You Been?” An ode to “aretha / jukebox queen of hymn & him” opens his poetry collection Tarantula. This man, who included a photograph of his friend Allen Ginsberg on the back cover of Bringing It All Back Home, may have plagiarized the Moby Dick SparkNotes summary in a speech that he did not actually deliver; instead, he sent Patti Smith to perform “A Hard Rain’s a-Gonna Fall” on his behalf. At that ceremony, this man was recognized for creating “new poetic expressions within the great American song tradition” like “Blowin’ in the Wind.” For 10 points, name this folk musician who won the 2016 Nobel Prize in Literature. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bob Dylan [or Robert Zimmerman] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"1. It isn’t in Oregon, but this peninsula’s “Valley of the Giants” contains many gigantic cactuses. This peninsula was explored by Francisco de Ulloa [“day oo-YO-uh”], who disproved the long-held misconception that this peninsula was actually an island. Japanese immigrants to this peninsula’s city of Ensenada may have invented the fish taco. The mouth of the Colorado River is located on the northeastern base of this peninsula. Many obnoxious American college students visit this peninsula’s resort town of Cabo San Lucas. For 10 points, Tijuana is the largest city in what Mexican-controlled peninsula located to the south of California? ","answer":"ANSWER: Baja California [do not accept or prompt on “Alto California”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"2. A narrator created by this author is writing a manuscript on the Buddha, and becomes distressed when he is called a “bookworm” by a friend who sees him reading the Divine Comedy. In a novel by this author, Manolios acts as Christ in a passion play put on by his village. Translator Kimon Friar declared this author’s 33,333-verse follow-up to Homer’s Odyssey a “Modern Sequel.” This author’s best known character enthusiastically plays the santuri, seduces the aging hotel owner Madame Hortense, and is employed to work in the narrator’s lignite mine. For 10 points, name this modern Greek novelist of The Last Temptation of Christ and Zorba the Greek. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nikos Kazantzakis "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"3. A piece written in this genre uses an eight note motif that begins with the notes (READ SLOWLY): G, G-sharp, high F, E-natural. Stravinsky declared that that piece in this genre would be “contemporary forever.” Pieces nicknamed “Spring” and “Dissonance” are from a group of six pieces in this genre dedicated to Haydn. Pieces in this genre include one nicknamed “The Joke” and another that includes variations on a melody that would become the German national anthem. That set of pieces in this genre is called Erdödy. 68 Haydn pieces and Beethoven’s “Grosse Fuge” [“GROW-suh FYOUG”] were written in, for 10 points, what genre of pieces written for an ensemble of two violins, a viola, and a cello? ","answer":"ANSWER: string quartets [prompt on quartets] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"4. In this city, American diplomat John Allison was slapped after a squadron of planes attacking this city accidentally bombed the USS Panay. John Magee recorded footage during an event in this city that saw the German businessman John Rabe set up a “safety zone.” A contest to kill one hundred people with a sword took place in this city, which was once the site of the Porcelain Tower. This city was renamed Tianjing when it was the capital of the Heavenly Kingdom during the Taiping Rebellion. The first of the “unequal treaties” was signed in, for 10 points, what Chinese city subjected to a 1937 “Rape” by the Japanese army. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nanjing [or Nanking] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"5. According to the Purusha Sukta, this deity and Agni were created from Sukta’s mouth. This deity disguised himself as Gautama Maharishi to sleep with Gautama’s wife Ahalya; in response, Gautama cursed this deity to sprout a thousand vaginas over his body. This figure prevented Hanuman from eating the sun by striking him with a vajra. Most depictions of this deity show him holding a thunderbolt atop his white elephant steed, Airavata. This father of Arjuna used a wave of sea foam to defeat the demon Vritra. For 10 points, name this god of storms, the chief of the devas in Hindu mythology. ","answer":"ANSWER: Indra "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"6. This film’s cinematographer, F. A. Young, used a specially created telephoto lens to capture a wide shot of a black-robed horseman riding through a mirage. A famous “match cut” from this film connects a shot of the protagonist blowing out a match to a shot of a rising sun. Like The Seven Pillars of Wisdom, this film plays up the homoerotic element of the main character’s friendship with Sherif Ali. This David Lean film begins with the title character dying in a motorcycle crash, and ends with him liberating Damascus alongside Prince Faisal. For 10 points, what film stars Peter O’Toole as the British leader of the Arab Revolt? ","answer":"ANSWER: Lawrence of Arabia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"7. A poem about this substance claims that it “levels life and death / and a thousand things obstinately hard to prove.” Du Fu named Li Bai as one of the “eight immortals” of this substance. Mo Yan wrote a satirical novel titled for the Republic of [this substance] as well as Red Sorghum, which is about a family that produces this substance. Eighteen bowls of this substance inspire Wu Song to slay a tiger in Water Margin. A poem about this substance describes how it is consumed by two friends “under the flowering trees” on the “Cloudy River of the sky.” For 10 points, name this alcoholic beverage, the subject of Li Bai’s “Drinking Alone by Moonlight.” ","answer":"ANSWER: wine [or sorghum wine; prompt on alcohol until it is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"8. This brother-in-law of Josephine Goldmark led the creation of the Savings Bank Insurance League in Massachusetts. This lawyer publicized the results of the Pujo Committee in Other People’s Money and How the Bankers Use It. With Samuel Warren, this pioneer of the Erie doctrine authored an article on “The Right to Privacy” and later condemned wiretapping in his dissent in Olmstead. This justice filed a namesake scientific brief on behalf of working women in Muller v. Oregon. A clash with Chaim Weizmann led this justice to resign from the Zionist Organization of America. For 10 points, name this first Jewish Supreme Court Justice. ","answer":"ANSWER: Louis Brandeis "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"9. This philosopher explained his use of the term “principle attribute” by reasoning that extension is the principle attribute of the body. Marin Mersenne accused this philosopher of making a circular argument in a “Second Set of Objections” to one of this man’s texts. This philosopher used the analogy of sorting rotten apples from fresh apples to illustrate the separation of false beliefs from true beliefs. A text by this philosopher discusses clear and distinct perceptions and states that, because the idea of perfection cannot come from a non-perfect being, God exists. For 10 points, name this author of Meditations on First Philosophy who stated “I think, therefore I am.” ","answer":"ANSWER: René Descartes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"0. Scientists have proposed a “firewall” that destroys matter that enters these objects. The first gravitational waves were detected from a merger of two of these objects. The idea that these objects emit blackbody radiation due to mutually entangled particles was proposed by Stephen Hawking. An ergosphere surrounds the rotating type of these objects. These entities are characterized by mass, charge, and angular momentum according to the no-hair theorem. The Schwarzschild radius defines the event horizon of these objects, which contain a gravitational singularity. For 10 points, name these objects that have such a high gravitational pull that not even light can escape them. ","answer":"ANSWER: black holes Tiebreaker. The deformation of regions named for this substance can be described by the Mogi model. This substance may undergo a form of “differentiation” that can be caused by contamination from wall rocks or bulk assimilation. Batholiths, dikes, and sills can be formed when this substance solidifies. Bowen's reaction series describes this substance’s fractional crystallization, which produces minerals such as olivine and pyroxene. Gabbro, granite, and other intrusive rocks can be formed in this substance’s namesake \"chambers\". For 10 points, name this type of molten rock that has not reached the surface of the earth and is contrasted with lava. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this poem from Lewis Carroll’s Through the Looking Glass. It warns the reader to “beware the Jubjub bird” and “shun the frumious Bandersnatch” in addition to the fearsome title creature. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Jabberwocky” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] This protagonist of Through the Looking Glass encounters the Cheshire Cat and the Mad Hatter in a Carroll book about her Adventures in Wonderland. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alice [or Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] This other poem from Through the Looking Glass describes ten crew members, including a Butcher who can only kill beavers and an actual Beaver, on their search for the title Boojum. ","answer":"ANSWER: “The Hunting of the Snark (An Agony in 8 Fits)” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this uprising of Russian soldiers who swore loyalty to the Grand Duke Constantine, who had removed himself from succession. The Northern Society rallied officers in Senate Square in this event’s namesake month. ","answer":"ANSWER: Decembrist Revolt "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Constantin was the elder brother of a Tsar of this name. The second Russian tsar of this name was executed by Bolsheviks in 1918 on the orders of Vladimir Lenin. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nicholas [or Nicholas I; or Nicholas II] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] This son of Nicholas I granted the Decembrists amnesty upon taking the throne. This tsar planned to implement Count Loris-Melikov’s reforms but was assassinated by People’s Will before he could put them into effect. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alexander II [prompt on partial answer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this strong diprotic acid, also known as oil of vitriol. ","answer":"ANSWER: sulfuric acid [or H2SO4 ] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] The Takai reaction uses a reactant containing this metal’s chloride to convert ketones to alkenes. The reagent PCC consists of a pyridinium atom and an anion [“ann-EYE-on”] with this transition metal at its center. ","answer":"ANSWER: chromium [or Cr] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Sulfuric acid, chromium trioxide, and acetone make up the Jones reagent, which acts on the primary and secondary type of these compounds. These compounds contain a hydroxyl functional group. ","answer":"ANSWER: alcohols "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this instrument. This instrument plays the melody after the bassoon in Ravel’s orchestration of “The Old Castle” from Modest Mussorgsky’s Pictures at an Exhibition. ","answer":"ANSWER: saxophone [or alto saxophone; or tenor saxophone; or sax] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] The alto saxophone plays a slow melodic solo in the first of this composer’s Symphonic Dances. This composer wrote a tone poem based on an Arnold Böcklin painting titled Isle of the Dead. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sergei (Vasilyevich) Rachmaninoff "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Both Mussorgsky and Rachmaninoff were composers from this country. This country is the setting of Mussorgsky’s opera Boris Godunov. ","answer":"ANSWER: Russia [or the Russian Empire] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this Chinese philosopher who wrote a text in which he asks a skull “how do you know it’s bad to be dead?” In that text, this man defended a supposedly useless tree by saying one could admire it or nap under it. ","answer":"ANSWER: Zhuangzi [“ZHUANG-zuh”] [or Zhuang Zhou; or Chuang Tzu] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] The Zhuangzi is an important text in this Chinese religion that emphasizes wu-wei, or “non-action.” This religion is typically represented by the yin-yang symbol. ","answer":"ANSWER: Taoism [or Daoism] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Early Taoism was strongly influenced by this other Chinese text, whose 64 hexagrams can be used to perform divination. ","answer":"ANSWER: I Ching [or Classic of Changes; or Book of Changes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this essay that asserts that “existence precedes essence.” This essay defines “abandonment” and “anguish,” and expresses man’s individual responsibilities through the phrase “in fashioning myself, I fashion man.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Existentialism is a Humanism [or L’existentialisme est un humanisme] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] This French philosopher introduced his idea that “existence precedes essence” in Existentialism is a Humanism. The concepts of “being-for-itself” and “being-in-itself” are discussed in his book Being and Nothingness. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jean-Paul (Charles Aymard) Sartre "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] This Sartre concept refers to when individuals deny their innate freedom and accept inauthentic values as a result. To illustrate this concept, Sartre used the examples of a woman on a first date and a waiter in a cafe. ","answer":"ANSWER: bad faith [or mauvaise foi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this curve that demonstrates the effects of tradeoffs. Introductory economics classes often use this curve to plot the relationship between guns and butter. ","answer":"ANSWER: production possibility frontier [or production possibility curve; or PPC; or PPF] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Points located along the PPF are considered to have the productive form of this condition. Vilfredo Pareto generalized it to a state in which any reallocation of goods will make an individual worse off. ","answer":"ANSWER: efficiency [or productive efficiency; or Pareto efficiency; or Pareto optimality; accept word forms such as efficient] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Two answers required. The Heckscher-Ohlin model uses PPFs to determine the intensity of goods relative to these two quantities, which determines what countries export and import. ","answer":"ANSWER: labor and capital [accept in either order] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this diagram in which each number is equal to the sum of the two numbers above it. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pascal’s triangle [prompt on partial answer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] The numbers found in Pascal's triangle are also called these numbers, which are the coefficients of a two-term polynomial raised to an exponent n. ","answer":"ANSWER: binomial coefficients [or binomial numbers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] The sum of the nth binomial coefficients, or equivalently the sum of the nth row of Pascal's triangle, is this function of n. ","answer":"ANSWER: 2 to the n [or 2 to the power of n] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this proponent of “brinkmanship” and “massive retaliation” who served as Secretary of State under Eisenhower. His younger brother Allen was CIA Director in the 1950s and early 1960s. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Foster Dulles "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] The Dulles brothers supported Operation PBSUCCESS, a CIA-led plot to overthrow this democratically elected president of Guatemala. His land reform policies antagonized the United Fruit Company, which owned the majority of Guatemala’s banana plantations. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jacobo Árbenz Guzman "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] The Dulles brothers also orchestrated a 1953 coup in this country, which strengthened Shah Mohammad Reza Pahlavi’s grip on this country’s throne. In 1979, an angry mob captured the US embassy in this country’s capital city of Tehran. ","answer":"ANSWER: Iran "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this type of animal. The final section of a 1984 novel is titled for the dying “Smile” of a female one of these animals that Tereza gives the masculine name “Karenin.” ","answer":"ANSWER: dogs "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Both of the aforementioned novels were written in this European language, which was also used by playwright and president Václav Havel [“VAWT-slahv HUH-VELL”]. Ludvik Vaculik [“VAWT-soo-leek”] used this language to write the “Two Thousand Words” manifesto during the Prague Spring. ","answer":"ANSWER: Czech "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Tomas, Tereza, and their puppy Karenin escape the Soviet invasion of Prague in this Czech author’s novel The Unbearable Lightness of Being. ","answer":"ANSWER: Milan Kundera "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this 1957 album by John Coltrane, featuring trumpeter Lee Morgan and bassist Paul Chambers, which includes the tracks “Moment’s Notice” and “Lazy Bird.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Blue Train "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] This trumpeter pioneered modal jazz on an album featuring the songs “Blues in Green” and “All Blues,” Kind of Blue. ","answer":"ANSWER: Miles Davis "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Hard bop saxophonist Joe Henderson premiered a Kenny Dorham composition titled for the “blue” form of this genre. This Brazilian jazz genre, which is distinct from samba music, was popularized in the United States by Stan Getz and Astrud Gilberto’s recording of “The Girl from Ipanema.” ","answer":"ANSWER: bossa nova [prompt on “Blue Bossa”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this property. The relativistic interaction of this property with a particle’s orbit contributes to atomic fine structure. ","answer":"ANSWER: spin [prompt on intrinsic angular momentum; do not accept or prompt on “angular momentum” alone] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] The existence of spin was confirmed in this experiment named for two German scientists, who fired a beam of silver atoms into an inhomogeneous magnetic field. ","answer":"ANSWER: Stern–Gerlach experiment "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] This scientist lends his name to a set of commutative spin matrices. He also names an exclusion principle that states that two or more fermions cannot occupy the same quantum state in a system. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wolfgang Pauli "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this friar who preached against luxury and corruption and orchestrated the Bonfire of the Vanities. ","answer":"ANSWER: Girolamo Savonarola "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Savonarola preached in this Tuscan city, where he became the de facto ruler after its ruling Medici family was expelled. ","answer":"ANSWER: Florence [or Firenze] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] This pope unsuccessfully tried to silence Savonarola with a cardinalate, then had him excommunicated. According to legend, this pope invited prostitutes to the Vatican for a debauched “Banquet of the Chestnuts.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Pope Alexander VI [or Rodrigo Borgia; prompt on Borgia or Alexander alone] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this author of The Spy Who Came in from the Cold. George Smiley works for a British intelligence group known as the Circus in his Tinker Tailor Soldier Spy. ","answer":"ANSWER: John le Carré [accept David John Moore Cromwell] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"6. ","answer":"ANSWER: Our Man in Havana "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] This fictional British spy appears in several novels by Ian Fleming, including Casino Royale and From Russia with Love. ","answer":"ANSWER: James Bond [accept either underlined name; or 007 [“double-oh seven”]] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this country that implemented mandatory capital punishment for drug offenses under its longtime ruler Lee Kuan Yew. ","answer":"ANSWER: Singapore "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Like Singapore, this other Southeast Asian country uses the death penalty for most drug smuggling cases. Its capital city is Jakarta. ","answer":"ANSWER: Indonesia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] In 2015, Australia cut its foreign aid to Indonesia after this Indonesian president refused to pardon two Australian citizens accused of drug smuggling. ","answer":"ANSWER: Joko Widodo [or Jokowi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Identify this rustic god associated with beekeeping and honey. This god is the son of Apollo and Cyrene. ","answer":"ANSWER: Aristaeus "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] After Aristaeus caused the death of Eurydice, this son of Apollo and Calliope went to the underworld in a failed journey to retrieve her. This man was torn to pieces by Maenads while playing songs on his lyre. ","answer":"ANSWER: Orpheus "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] This son of Apollo and Coronis was a god of medicine who brought back Hippolytus from the dead. People would sleep in temples of this god in order to be healed. ","answer":"ANSWER: Asclepius "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this general who allied with Cassander and Lysimachus to defeat Antigonus the One-Eyed at the Battle of Ipsus. This member of the Diadochi bore the epithet “Nicator” and founded the city of Antioch. ","answer":"ANSWER: Seleucus I Nicator "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"2. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alexander the Great [or Alexander III of Macedon; prompt on Alexander] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Seleucus married his daughter to this Indian emperor, who supplied the elephants that Seleucus deployed at the Battle of Ipsus. This grandfather of Ashoka founded the Mauryan dynasty. ","answer":"ANSWER: Chandragupta Maurya "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Friedrich Wöhler’s accidental synthesis of what compound from inorganic substances helped refute the idea of vitalism? ","answer":"ANSWER: urea [or carbamide; do not accept or prompt on uric acid or urine] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] The fumarate produced during the urea cycle is also an intermediate in this other cycle that occurs in the mitochondrial matrix. This cycle follows glycolysis during cellular respiration. ","answer":"ANSWER: Krebs cycle [or citric acid cycle; or CAC; or tricarboxylic acid cycle; or TCA] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] At one step of the urea cycle, CPS1 catalyzes a reaction between this ion, ammonia, and two molecules of ATP. Levels of this ion are abnormally high during respiratory alkalosis. ","answer":"ANSWER: bicarbonate ion [or HCO3 - ] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this title character of a 1936 short story who is accidentally shot by his wife, Margot, during a safari in Africa. ","answer":"ANSWER: Francis Macomber [accept either underlined part; or “The Short Happy Life of Francis Macomber”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] This author of “The Short Happy Life of Francis Macomber” included his recurring character Nick Adams in stories like “Big Two-Hearted River” and “Indian Camp.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Ernest Hemingway "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] In this Hemingway novella, the elderly fisherman Santiago muses about Joe DiMaggio as he attempts to catch a marlin. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Old Man and the Sea "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this sculptor who depicted a naked couple dancing in The Waltz. Her sculpture The Mature Age is often interpreted as an allegory for her relationship with her lover, who abandoned her to live with his mistress Rose Beuret. ","answer":"ANSWER: Camille Claudel "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Claudel was a collaborator and lover of this French sculptor, who signed his name on some of Claudel’s works. He sculpted The Thinker for his never-completed project The Gates of Hell. ","answer":"ANSWER: François Auguste René Rodin "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Claudel may have assisted in the creation of this Rodin sculpture, which depicts Paolo and Francesca from Dante’s Inferno. It was removed from Gates of Hell because of its controversial eroticism. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Kiss [or Le Baiser] Tiebreaker. Two answers required. In 2002, these two countries engaged in a brief bloodless “war” over control of the Perejil [“peh-ruh-HEEL”] Island. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name these two countries that dispute control over the enclaves Ceuta and Melilla [meh-LEE-yah”]. ","answer":"ANSWER: Spain and Morocco "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"[10] Although Spain refuses to cede control of Ceuta [“see-OOT-ah”] and Melilla back to Morocco, it has frequently protested Britain’s ownership of this strategically important strait. It connects the Atlantic Ocean to the Mediterranean Sea. ","answer":"ANSWER: Strait of Gibraltar "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"L","question":"7. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Rif [or the Rif War]"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"1. People of this ethnicity were granted a monopoly on trade with Venezuela by the Bourbon Reforms. This ethnic group’s whalers spoke an Algonquian pidgin language and were subjected to a 1615 massacre in Iceland. Terrorists of this ethnicity participated in 1973’s Operation Ogre, which resulted in the carbombing of Luis Carrero Blanco. The Song of Roland records how an army of this ethnicity ambushed Charlemagne at Roncevaux Pass. The 2004 Madrid train bombings were initially blamed on this ethnicity’s ETA terrorist group. For 10 points, name this Iberian ethnic minority whose namesake “country” straddles France and Spain. ","answer":"ANSWER: Basques [or Vascos; or Euskaldunak] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"2. This author’s name is used in place of the phrase “excuse me” in Derek Walcott’s Ti-Jean and his Brothers. This writer isn’t American, but his work inspired a play broken into the sections The Homecoming, The Hunted, and The Haunted. Christine poisons her Civil War general husband Ezra Mannon in that Eugene O’Neill work based on one of this author’s plays. Prometheus Bound is a sequel to one of his plays, and his work inspired the modern adaptations Mourning Becomes Electra and Jean Paul Sartre’s The Flies. During a fictional poetry contest in Aristophanes’s The Frogs, this playwright beats Euripides. For 10 points, name this Greek tragedian and playwright of the Oresteia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Aeschylus "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"3. These functional groups are synthesized from nitriles using tin(II) [tin two] chloride in the Stephen synthesis. The simplest aromatic example of these functional groups is the active flavorant in almond extract. In hydrogen NMR, compounds with these functional groups show a peak from 9-10 ppm. PCC can convert primary alcohols to these functional groups. These functional groups, which cause a magenta color change in the Schiff test, form a characteristic “silver mirror” when using Tollens’ reagent. For ten points, name these functional groups that contain a terminal carbon double bonded to an oxygen, unlike ketones. ","answer":"ANSWER: aldehydes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"4. Parashurama killed Kartavirya Arjuna after Arjuna stole one of these animals from Parashurama’s father, the sage Jamadagni. Prithu received vegetation and grain from one of these animals named Prithvi. According to the Mahabharata, the Saptarishi received one of these animals named Kamadhenu that emerged from the churning of the ocean. Shiva’s mount, Nandi, is one of these animals. The final abode of Krishna is sometimes referred to as the “heaven” of these animals, which Krishna herded as a boy. For 10 points, name these animals which Hindus consider sacred and avoid eating. ","answer":"ANSWER: cows [or cattle; or bulls] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"5. A philosophical text written in this language argues against the belief that fire burns cotton, instead declaring that cotton is burned by God. Followers of a philosopher who wrote in this language argued for the possible coexistence of differing philosophical and religious truths, a doctrine referred to as “double truth.” A text in this language denounces 20 heretic views stated by other philosophers, such as the pre-eternity of the world and ordinary causality. The Incoherence of the Philosophers and The Incoherence of the Incoherence were written in this language, which was also used to write commentaries on Aristotle by Averroes. For 10 points, name this language used by the Muslim philosopher al-Ghazali. ","answer":"ANSWER: Arabic "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"6. A member of this minority group attempted to kidnap the royal family in the Surprise of Meaux. Poorly-disciplined dragoons were forcibly billeted in this group’s homes under the Dragonnades policy. Members of this group put posters on the door of the king’s bedchamber in the Affair of the Placards. The Duke of Buckingham helped defend these people at the Siege of La Rochelle. This group’s admiral Gaspard de Coligny was murdered during a massacre ordered by Catherine de’ Medici on St. Bartholomew’s Day. For 10 points, the Edict of Nantes granted religious freedom to what group of French Protestants? ","answer":"ANSWER: Huguenots [or French Protestants until it is read; prompt on Protestants or Calvinists] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"7. At the end of one of this author’s plays, the Mayor turns to the audience to say “What are you laughing about? You are laughing about yourselves!” In that play by this author, Khlestakov cons a village into believing he is an incognito government official. One of this author’s novels ends mid-sentence as a prince lambasts Chichikov for purchasing the property of dead peasants. The Person of Importance is robbed by a ghost at the end of this author’s story about the copy clerk Akaky Akakievich. For 10 points, name this Russian author of Dead Souls and “The Overcoat.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Nikolai Gogol "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"8. This effect can cause spacecraft to build up a positive charge on the side facing the Sun through surface charging. This effect was first observed by Heinrich Hertz when using a coil and a spark gap. Robert Millikan confirmed this effect in an experiment in which he verified the value of Planck’s constant. Maxwell’s electromagnetism incorrectly predicted that in this effect, the electron energy would be proportional to the intensity of the incoming radiation. A 1905 paper explaining how this effect is due to quantized light won Albert Einstein won a Nobel Prize. For 10 points, name this effect, the emission of electrons when light shines on a material. ","answer":"ANSWER: photoelectric effect [prompt on surface charging until it is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"9. The second movement of this composition opens with a solo horn playing the slow notes (read slowly) long F, G, A-flat, long B-flat. At the beginning of this suite, col legno strings play a unison G in a rhythm consisting of triplet eighth-notes, two quarter notes, two eighth notes, and a quarter note. This suite’s final movement creates a “fade-out” effect by closing the door on an offstage women’s chorus. The hymn “I Vow to Thee, My Country” was set to the melody of one of this suite’s movements, which is subtitled “the Bringer of Jollity.” For 10 points, name this Gustav Holst suite with movements named “Mars” and “Jupiter.” ","answer":"ANSWER: The Planets "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"0. Greater government spending does not increase demand because consumers expect an increase in this variable, according to the Ricardian equivalence model. Frank Ramsey inspired Peter Diamond and James Mirrlees to research the “optimal” value for this variable to maximize social welfare. The price elasticity of demand can help determine the “incidence” of these things, which are supported by the “benefit principle.” Externalities can be internalized using a policy of this type designed by Arthur Pigou. Examples of these things include excises and tariffs. For 10 points, name these economic policies that governments use to raise revenue. ","answer":"ANSWER: taxation [or tax rate; or tax revenue; or word forms; prompt on specific types of taxes like tariff or excise] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"1. This event began in response to the issue of sixty subpoenas by William Rawle, which was argued to be a deliberate provocation by Congressman William Findley. The anonymous “Tom the Tinker” and the Mingo Creek Association threatened enemies of this event like John Neville, whose house at Bower Hill was the focus of its first shots. “Light-Horse Harry” Lee led the troops that put down this uprising. The derisively nicknamed “Watermelon Army” participated in this rebellion to protest a financial measure implemented by Alexander Hamilton. For 10 points, name this Pennsylvania frontier revolt caused by a tax an alcohol. ","answer":"ANSWER: Whiskey Rebellion [or the Whiskey Revolt; or the Whiskey Uprising] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"2. The first sentence of this novel describes a woman whose beauty “seems to be thrown into relief by poor dress.” A landlord in this novel asks Mary Garth to destroy his will in order to deprive Joshua Rigg of his inheritance. One of this novel’s characters spends his honeymoon studying books in the Vatican library. That character in this novel is treated by Rosamond Vincy’s husband, Tertius Lydgate, and dies without finishing his book The Key to All Mythologies. In this novel, Edward Casaubon leaves a will stipulating that Will Ladislaw cannot marry Dorothea Brooke. For 10 points, name this “study of provincial life” by George Eliot. ","answer":"ANSWER: Middlemarch: A Study of Provincial Life "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"3. This pathway shares intermediates like sedulose-1,7-bisphosphate and xylulose-5-phosphate with the pentose phosphate pathway. An exciton forms at the special pair in the first phase of this process before the lone electron is shuttled from pheophytin to plastoquinone. To make up for how inefficiently it turns over, an enzyme in this pathway is the most common protein on Earth. NADP carries electrons in this pathway away from the P680 and P700 complexes. The thylakoid lumen develops a pH gradient during the light-dependent phase of this process. For 10 points, name this pathway that fixes carbon in the Calvin cycle and is used by plants to harvest solar energy. ","answer":"ANSWER: photosynthesis [or light-dependent reactions or LDR until it is read; or Calvin cycle until it is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"4. In 1845, John Snare allegedly found a lost painting by this artist depicting Charles I. This artist assisted Peter Paul Rubens in making a copy of Titian’s Rape of Europa, a painting he later featured as a tapestry in the background of a work depicting The Fable of Arachne. This artist’s still-life of a woman frying eggs is in the bodegón (bow-de-GON) genre. He made a portrait of the freed slave Juan de Pareja. This artist stands behind an easel wearing the red cross of the Order of Santiago in his most famous painting, which depicts two dwarves and a dog around the Infanta Margaret Theresa. For 10 points, name this Spanish Golden Age painter of Las Meninas. ","answer":"ANSWER: Diego Velázquez "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"5. Lanterns called fanous are often hung during this time period. According to one text, a night that takes place during this period is “better than a thousand months.” Because that night during this period can take place on any of five days, many adherents choose to practice i’tikah for ten days. During this period, daybreak is defined as the moment when a white thread appears distinct from a black thread. Extra prayers called tarawih are said during this period, during which adherents of a certain religion observe sawm. This month ends with the feast of Eid al-Fitr. For 10 points, name this month of the Islamic calendar in which Muslims fast from dawn to dusk. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ramadan [prompt on specific parts of Ramadan like Laylat al-Qadr and Eid al-Fitr] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"6. This leader wrote the Greek phrase “ginesthoi,” or “make it happen!” at the bottom of a document granting tax exemptions to Quintus Caecilius. Blaise Pascal claimed that “the world would have been changed” if this leader had a shorter nose. Despite a grant of sanctuary, this leader had her sister Arsinoe killed on the steps of the Temple of Artemis. The Donations of Alexandria distributed royal titles to this leader’s children, including her son Caesarion. After the Battle of Actium, this member of the Ptolemaic dynasty committed suicide with an asp. For 10 points, name this lover of Mark Antony and Julius Caesar who ruled as Queen of Egypt. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cleopatra VII Philopator "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"7. A newspaper based in this state won a Pulitzer Prize for its “Seven Days of Heroin” project. Macedonian immigrants to this state developed a type of chili that is poured over spaghetti noodles and garnished with oyster crackers. In 2011, 56 exotic animals escaped from a private zoo in this state’s town of Zanesville. Goodyear Tires is based in this state in a city that is nicknamed the “Rubber Capital of the World.” The Cuyahoga River flows through this state, where the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame is located on the shores of Lake Erie. For 10 points, name this US state, home to cities like Akron, Cincinnati, and Cleveland. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ohio "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"8. The speaker of a jazz standard set in this city owns a “cozy little flat,” in which she’ll “settle down / right here in town.” A bandleader from this city invited audiences to sing “hi-dee-hi-dee-hi-dee-hi” in the scat chorus of his song “Minnie the Moocher.” Paul Whiteman pioneered symphonic jazz in this city, which is where Cab Calloway led the house band of a whites-only nightclub. Billy Strayhorn composed “Take the ‘A’ Train” for a bandleader associated with this city’s Cotton Club, Duke Ellington. For 10 points, name this city where jazz flourished during the Harlem Renaissance. ","answer":"ANSWER: New York City [or NYC; prompt on Manhattan; prompt on Harlem until mentioned] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"9. One mathematician from this country lends his name to a theorem stating that every group G is isomorphic to a subgroup of the symmetric group acting on G. A mathematician from this country used his proof of the Taniyama-Shimura conjecture for semistable elliptic curves to find a proof for Fermat’s last theorem. This country was also home to a mathematician who developed a namesake “method” to approximate the roots of a function by repeatedly taking derivatives. That mathematician argued with Gottlieb Leibniz over who developed calculus. For 10 points, name this country home to Arthur Cayley, Andrew Wiles, and Isaac Newton. ","answer":"ANSWER: United Kingdom [or Britain; or England] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"0. A poem set in this city describes “parking spaces” that “luxuriate like civic sandpiles.” One of this city’s characteristic “marriages” is exemplified by Olive Chancellor’s relationship with Verena Tarrant in an 1886 novel. Another novel notes that the “forefathers” of this city chose to build a cemetery and a prison before anything else. A “savage servility slides by on grease” through this city, which “stands in a Sahara of snow” according to Robert Lowell’s poem “For the Union Dead.” This city, whose residents title a Henry James novel, is largely the setting of The Scarlet Letter. For 10 points, name this city, whose literary “Brahmins” often lectured at Harvard College. ","answer":"ANSWER: Boston [accept The Bostonians; prompt on Cambridge] Tiebreaker. The carbon in pulp process describes the recovery of this element. The Elsner equation describes the dissolution of this element through a cyanide solution. The relativistic contraction of this element’s 5s orbitals give it its characteristic color, and that of its 6s orbitals contribute to its resistance to corrosion. Complexes of this element can exhibit aurophilicity. The scattering of alpha particles on this element’s nuclei was observed by Geiger and Marsden, who used a foil made of this element. Aqua regia can dissolve both this element and platinum. Pyrite is sometimes nicknamed the “fool’s” type of this element. For 10 points, name this precious metal with a yellowish color. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Fine’s book Shared Fantasy discusses this leisure activity, which Philip Zimbardo linked to the “failure” of boys in his book Man, Interrupted. It doesn’t involve movies or music, but many studies have examined the relation between this leisure activity and males’ desensitization to violence. ","answer":"ANSWER: playing video games [or gaming; accept any descriptive or specific answers that involve video games] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Fine defines “naturework” as the way we give meaning to our surroundings in a book about people who collect these organisms. This organism appears in the title of an Anna Tsing book about “the Possibility of Life in Capitalist Ruins.” ","answer":"ANSWER: mushrooms [or Morel Tales: The Culture of Mushrooming; or The Mushroom at the End of the World: On the Possibility of Life in Capitalist Ruins; prompt on fungi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Fine’s book Sticky Reputations examines the influence of the “collective” form of this concept advanced by Maurice Halbwachs. This term refers to our ability to store and retrieve information. ","answer":"ANSWER: memory "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this law, which states that “2 d sine theta equals n lambda” to give the scattering angles of light diffraction in a crystal lattice. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bragg’s law "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Bragg’s law describes the diffraction of light rays in this region of the electromagnetic spectrum. These rays, first discovered by William Röntgen, are commonly used to image bones. ","answer":"ANSWER: X-rays [or X-radiation] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This German scientist received the 1914 Nobel Prize in Physics for discovering X-ray diffraction, predating the work of the Braggs. X-ray diffraction is sometimes known as a type of diffraction named for this man. ","answer":"ANSWER: Max von Laue "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this snake-like giant who, along with Echidna, is the father of many of Greece’s most famous monsters. ","answer":"ANSWER: Typhon [or Typhos] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This offspring of Typhon had poisonous breath and blood so toxic that even smelling it could kill you. Heracles had to burn this monster’s necks in order to stop its many heads from regenerating. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lernaean Hydra [or Hydra of Lerna] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This two-headed dog was the first child of Typhon and Echidna. He was charged with guarding Geryon’s cattle and was eventually killed by Heracles. ","answer":"ANSWER: Orthrus [or Orthus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this algorithm extended by the Bellman-Ford algorithm, which allows for negative edge weights. ","answer":"ANSWER: Dijkstra’s algorithm "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Dijkstra’s algorithm is used to find shortest paths in these mathematical collections of vertices and edges. The Seven Bridges of Königsberg problem laid the foundation for the “theory” of these structures. ","answer":"ANSWER: graphs [or graph theory] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] The priority queues often used to store edges in Dijkstra’s algorithm can be implemented with the “min” variety of this tree-based data structure, in which each node’s leaves are less than or equal to the node itself. ","answer":"ANSWER: heap [or min heap; or binary heap] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this Holy Roman Emperor who called the Diet of Roncaglia after subduing Milan. This red-bearded commander drowned fording the Saleph River during the Third Crusade. ","answer":"ANSWER: Frederick Barbarossa [or Frederick I] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Frederick’s authority in Italy was opposed by this alliance of cities backed by Pope Alexander III. This alliance shared its name with a people once ruled by Desiderius. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lombard League "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] The Lombard League shattered Frederick’s army at this 1176 battle, ending his dream of direct imperial rule in Italy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Battle of Legnano "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this First Lady whose chic greatly influenced the trends of Western fashion in the 1960s and 70s. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jacqueline “Jackie” Kennedy [or Jacqueline Bouvier; or Jacqueline Onassis] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Kennedy often wore a strapless gown of this color designed by Christian Dior. On the day of her husband’s assassination, Kennedy was wearing an iconic Chanel wool suit of this color that became stained with blood. ","answer":"ANSWER: pink [or strawberry pink] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Ann Lowe, one of the first prominent African-American fashion designers, designed a famed one of these clothing items for Kennedy using ivory silk taffeta. In 2011, Sarah Burton designed one of these clothing items for Kate Middleton. ","answer":"ANSWER: wedding dress [or bridal gown; accept equivalents; prompt on dress] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this poetic title character who lived in a “pretty how town.” “Women and men” both “little and small” don’t care for this character, whose life is the subject of a poem with the refrain “sun moon stars rain.” ","answer":"ANSWER: anyone [or “anyone lived in a pretty how town”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This capitalization-adverse poet wrote “anyone lived in a pretty how town.” A “conscientious object-or” whose “warmest heart recoiled at war” appears in his poem “i sing of Olaf glad and big.” ","answer":"ANSWER: e. e. cummings [or Edward Estlin Cummings] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This Imagist writer bet mutual friend Scofield Thayer that cummings would not be a successful poet. The speaker of her poem “Patterns” observes “squills and daffodils” before exclaiming “Christ! What are patterns for?” ","answer":"ANSWER: Amy Lowell [prompt on Lowell] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this country where Ronald Reagan and Mikhail Gorbachev met for a 1986 summit. In 1949, protesters attacked this country’s parliament, the Althing, after it voted to join NATO. ","answer":"ANSWER: Iceland "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] During the Cold War, NATO used Iceland as a base to monitor the activity of these Soviet warships, which could be used to store missiles. The “nuclear” variety of these submersible vessels is powered by a nuclear reactor. ","answer":"ANSWER: Soviet nuclear submarines [or ballistic missile submarines; prompt on subs] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] The Althing repeatedly threatened to leave NATO during this series of informal conflicts between Iceland and the United Kingdom. This “war” ended when Britain agreed to stop harassing Icelandic fishing ships. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Cod Wars "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Plasma and memory cells are both involved in the “adaptive” form of what system, which is contrasted with its “innate” form? ","answer":"ANSWER: immune system [or innate immune system; or adaptive immune system] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Plasma cells are examples of these white blood cells that secrete antibodies. These lymphocytes are contrasted with natural killer cells and T cells. ","answer":"ANSWER: B cells [or B lymphocytes; accept plasma B cells; prompt on lymphocytes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] B cells are activated by the type 1 and 2 of these immune system signaling molecules. These cytokines were once thought to be exclusively used as communication between white blood cells. ","answer":"ANSWER: interleukins [or ILs; or IL-1; or IL-2] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this composer of a piece for an indefinite amount of performers consisting of 53 short numbered musical phrases, each intended to be repeated an arbitrary number of times independently by each musician. That piece by this composer is called In C. ","answer":"ANSWER: Terry Riley "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Terry Riley is a composer from this musical movement. Other composers associated with this movement include the composer of Dif erent Trains, Steve Reich, and Nixon and China composer John Adams. ","answer":"ANSWER: minimalism [accept word forms; prompt on modernism] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Terry Riley, Steve Reich, and John Adams are all minimalist composers from this country. ","answer":"ANSWER: United States of America [or America] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Identify this concept which, according to that text, is a “blind striving.” A posthumous text by a different philosopher declares that the world is this thing “and nothing besides!” ","answer":"ANSWER: will [accept Will-to-Life or Will-to-Live or Wille zum Leben; accept Will to Power or Wille zur Macht] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This German pessimist used the philosophy of the Upanishads to state that human life should focus on opposing the Will-to-Life via asceticism in his book The World as Will and Representation. ","answer":"ANSWER: Arthur Schopenhauer "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This German nihilist philosopher declared that “the world is the will to power – and nothing besides!” This author of Beyond Good and Evil coined the term “will to power” in Thus Spoke Zarathustra. ","answer":"ANSWER: Friedrich (Wilhelm) Nietzsche "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"4. After World War II, Niemoller apologized for his previous support of this leader’s anti-Semitic policies. ","answer":"ANSWER: Adolf Hitler "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Anti-Nazi theologians like Dietrich Bonhoeffer and Karl Barth formed this Christian movement after the Nazi Party officially absorbed Germany’s Protestant church. This movement’s views were expressed in the Barmen Declaration. ","answer":"ANSWER” the Confessing Church [or Bekennende Kirche] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s The Cost of Discipleship is an extended analysis of this Biblical event. This New Testament event is the source of the expressions “salt of the earth” and “turn the other cheek.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the Sermon on the Mount [prompt on the Beatitudes; prompt on the Gospel of Matthew] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this member of the Angry Young Men. The medieval history professor Jim Dixon is fired at the end of his campus novel Lucky Jim. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kingsley Amis [prompt on just Amis] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Alan Sillitoe, another member of the Angry Young Men, is most famous for this short story, in which Smith loses a race on purpose to spite his school. ","answer":"ANSWER: “The Loneliness of the Long Distance Runner” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] In Lucky Jim, Jim Dixon gives a drunken lecture about this “merrie” place. Amis, Sillitoe, and other members of the Angry Young Men set much of their work in this country.. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Merrie England” [accept Great Britain or the United Kingdom] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this empire known to the Han as “Daqin.” Emperor Huan of Han received ambassadors from this empire who claimed to have been sent by Marcus Aurelius. ","answer":"ANSWER: Roman Empire [or Rome] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] The Han were more successful in taking control of this modern-day country, which briefly secured independence from China during the Trung Sisters’ rebellion. This country’s last emperor, Bao Dai, ruled from the imperial city of Hue (he-WAY). ","answer":"ANSWER: Vietnam "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Emperor Wu of Han fought to acquire “heavenly” horses from the Dayuan of the Ferghana Valley in order to deploy them against these northern barbarians, whose incursions led to the construction of the Great Wall. ","answer":"ANSWER: Xiongnu [prompt on Huns] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this molecule, the simplest ketone. It is used in nail polish remover. ","answer":"ANSWER: acetone "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Most acetone is often industrially produced along with phenol in this process. This process, which was discovered by Heinrich Hock, is named for an aromatic intermediate. ","answer":"ANSWER: cumene-phenol process "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Cumene is produced by substituting a hydrogen on this molecule with an isopropyl group. Phenol is made by adding a hydroxyl group to this aromatic molecule, which has formula C6H6 . ","answer":"ANSWER: benzene "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this profession. In “The Albatross,” this profession is compared to a “prince of cloud and sky” whose “giant wings prevent him from walking.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the poet [prompt on writer or author] [10] “Benediction” and “The Albatross” appear in The Flowers of Evil alongside “The Swan,” which reflects on this city’s modernization. The second section of The Flowers of Evil is titled for this city’s “scenes.” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This writer reflected on the role of the poet, as well as the modernization of Paris, throughout his Symbolist masterpiece The Flowers of Evil. ","answer":"ANSWER: Charles Baudelaire "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name these works that were traditionally printed on vellum, a prepared animal skin. The Book of Kells is a well-known example of this type of work. ","answer":"ANSWER: illuminated manuscripts [prompt on partial answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Prehistoric artists often preserved animal skins using a variety of the pigment ochre that was this color. Vermillion was another popular pigment of this color. ","answer":"ANSWER: red "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Native American artists began creating “ledger art” after it became difficult to obtain the hides of these animals, which were the most common hides used by Plains Indians to make teepees. One of these ungulates appears in the Wyoming state flag. ","answer":"ANSWER: American bison [or buffalo; accept buffalo hides; or bison hides] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this deliverer of the “Solitude of Self” speech who lost much of her influence after the publication of The Women’s Bible. ","answer":"ANSWER: Elizabeth Cady Stanton "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Stanton added a resolution advancing this cause to the Declaration of Sentiments at the Seneca Falls Convention. The aim of this cause was achieved with the passage of the 19th Amendment. ","answer":"ANSWER: women’s suffrage [accept women receiving the vote or equivalents; prompt on suffrage] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Stanton’s shift on Black civil rights was criticised by this man, who argued that Black men deserved the vote before White women. Earlier, this man was the only African American attendee at the Seneca Falls Conference. ","answer":"ANSWER: Frederick Douglass "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"2. ","answer":"ANSWER: Whitney Houston "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Houston’s family criticized Pusha T for using a photograph of Houston’s bathroom after her death as the cover art for this 2018 album. Its tracks include “If You Know You Know” and an epic takedown of Meek Mill, “What Would Meek Do?” ","answer":"ANSWER: Daytona "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This rapper, who produced Pusha T’s Daytona, personally shelled out $85,000 to acquire the rights to the photograph of Houston’s bathroom. This husband of Kim Kardashian recently visited President Trump at the White House. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kanye West [accept either underlined portion; also accept Yeezy or Ye] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Name this capital city. Palace Walk is the first work in a trilogy of novels set in this city by the author of Midaq Alley. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cairo [accept the Cairo Trilogy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] Egyptian author Naguib Mahfouz, who wrote the Cairo Trilogy, is the only author to have received the Nobel Prize in Literature for writing primarily in this language. ","answer":"ANSWER: Arabic "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This British novelist wrote a Quartet of novels set in Egypt’s city of Alexandria. His brother Gerald wrote My Family and Other Animals, which chronicles this author’s eccentric upbringing in Corfu. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lawrence Durrell Tiebreaker. The Taft-Katsura memorandum acknowledged Japan’s stake in Korea and disinterest in this country. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"6. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Philippines "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This leader of the Philippine Senate led a 1934 delegation to Washington, D.C. to secure independence. It’s not Manila, but the Philippines’ largest city is named for this first president of the Commonwealth of the Philippines. ","answer":"ANSWER: Manuel Quezon [or Quezon City] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"M","question":"[10] This earlier leader of the Filipino independence movement led a guerilla campaign against Spain towards the end of its occupation of the Philippines. Once the Spanish left, he continued his war against the United States until he was captured by Frederick Funston. ","answer":"ANSWER: Emilio Aguinaldo"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"1. People of this ethnicity were granted a monopoly on trade with Venezuela by the Bourbon Reforms. This ethnic group’s whalers spoke an Algonquian pidgin language and were subjected to a 1615 massacre in Iceland. Terrorists of this ethnicity participated in 1973’s Operation Ogre, which resulted in the carbombing of Luis Carrero Blanco. The Song of Roland records how an army of this ethnicity ambushed Charlemagne at Roncevaux Pass. The 2004 Madrid train bombings were initially blamed on this ethnicity’s ETA terrorist group. For 10 points, name this Iberian ethnic minority whose namesake “country” straddles France and Spain. ","answer":"ANSWER: Basques [or Vascos; or Euskaldunak] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"2. This author’s name is used in place of the phrase “excuse me” in Derek Walcott’s Ti-Jean and his Brothers. This writer isn’t American, but his work inspired a play broken into the sections The Homecoming, The Hunted, and The Haunted. Christine poisons her Civil War general husband Ezra Mannon in that Eugene O’Neill work based on one of this author’s plays. Prometheus Bound is a sequel to one of his plays, and his work inspired the modern adaptations Mourning Becomes Electra and Jean Paul Sartre’s The Flies. During a fictional poetry contest in Aristophanes’s The Frogs, this playwright beats Euripides. For 10 points, name this Greek tragedian and playwright of the Oresteia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Aeschylus "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"3. These functional groups are synthesized from nitriles using tin(II) [tin two] chloride in the Stephen synthesis. The simplest aromatic example of these functional groups is the active flavorant in almond extract. In hydrogen NMR, compounds with these functional groups show a peak from 9-10 ppm. PCC can convert primary alcohols to these functional groups. These functional groups, which cause a magenta color change in the Schiff test, form a characteristic “silver mirror” when using Tollens’ reagent. For ten points, name these functional groups that contain a terminal carbon double bonded to an oxygen, unlike ketones. ","answer":"ANSWER: aldehydes "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"4. Parashurama killed Kartavirya Arjuna after Arjuna stole one of these animals from Parashurama’s father, the sage Jamadagni. Prithu received vegetation and grain from one of these animals named Prithvi. According to the Mahabharata, the Saptarishi received one of these animals named Kamadhenu that emerged from the churning of the ocean. Shiva’s mount, Nandi, is one of these animals. The final abode of Krishna is sometimes referred to as the “heaven” of these animals, which Krishna herded as a boy. For 10 points, name these animals which Hindus consider sacred and avoid eating. ","answer":"ANSWER: cows [or cattle; or bulls] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"5. A philosophical text written in this language argues against the belief that fire burns cotton, instead declaring that cotton is burned by God. Followers of a philosopher who wrote in this language argued for the possible coexistence of differing philosophical and religious truths, a doctrine referred to as “double truth.” A text in this language denounces 20 heretic views stated by other philosophers, such as the pre-eternity of the world and ordinary causality. The Incoherence of the Philosophers and The Incoherence of the Incoherence were written in this language, which was also used to write commentaries on Aristotle by Averroes. For 10 points, name this language used by the Muslim philosopher al-Ghazali. ","answer":"ANSWER: Arabic "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"6. A member of this minority group attempted to kidnap the royal family in the Surprise of Meaux. Poorly-disciplined dragoons were forcibly billeted in this group’s homes under the Dragonnades policy. Members of this group put posters on the door of the king’s bedchamber in the Affair of the Placards. The Duke of Buckingham helped defend these people at the Siege of La Rochelle. This group’s admiral Gaspard de Coligny was murdered during a massacre ordered by Catherine de’ Medici on St. Bartholomew’s Day. For 10 points, the Edict of Nantes granted religious freedom to what group of French Protestants? ","answer":"ANSWER: Huguenots [or French Protestants until it is read; prompt on Protestants or Calvinists] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"7. At the end of one of this author’s plays, the Mayor turns to the audience to say “What are you laughing about? You are laughing about yourselves!” In that play by this author, Khlestakov cons a village into believing he is an incognito government official. One of this author’s novels ends mid-sentence as a prince lambasts Chichikov for purchasing the property of dead peasants. The Person of Importance is robbed by a ghost at the end of this author’s story about the copy clerk Akaky Akakievich. For 10 points, name this Russian author of Dead Souls and “The Overcoat.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Nikolai Gogol "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"8. This effect can cause spacecraft to build up a positive charge on the side facing the Sun through surface charging. This effect was first observed by Heinrich Hertz when using a coil and a spark gap. Robert Millikan confirmed this effect in an experiment in which he verified the value of Planck’s constant. Maxwell’s electromagnetism incorrectly predicted that in this effect, the electron energy would be proportional to the intensity of the incoming radiation. A 1905 paper explaining how this effect is due to quantized light won Albert Einstein won a Nobel Prize. For 10 points, name this effect, the emission of electrons when light shines on a material. ","answer":"ANSWER: photoelectric effect [prompt on surface charging until it is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"9. The second movement of this composition opens with a solo horn playing the slow notes (read slowly) long F, G, A-flat, long B-flat. At the beginning of this suite, col legno strings play a unison G in a rhythm consisting of triplet eighth-notes, two quarter notes, two eighth notes, and a quarter note. This suite’s final movement creates a “fade-out” effect by closing the door on an offstage women’s chorus. The hymn “I Vow to Thee, My Country” was set to the melody of one of this suite’s movements, which is subtitled “the Bringer of Jollity.” For 10 points, name this Gustav Holst suite with movements named “Mars” and “Jupiter.” ","answer":"ANSWER: The Planets "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"0. Greater government spending does not increase demand because consumers expect an increase in this variable, according to the Ricardian equivalence model. Frank Ramsey inspired Peter Diamond and James Mirrlees to research the “optimal” value for this variable to maximize social welfare. The price elasticity of demand can help determine the “incidence” of these things, which are supported by the “benefit principle.” Externalities can be internalized using a policy of this type designed by Arthur Pigou. Examples of these things include excises and tariffs. For 10 points, name these economic policies that governments use to raise revenue. ","answer":"ANSWER: taxation [or tax rate; or tax revenue; or word forms; prompt on specific types of taxes like tariff or excise] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"1. This event began in response to the issue of sixty subpoenas by William Rawle, which was argued to be a deliberate provocation by Congressman William Findley. The anonymous “Tom the Tinker” and the Mingo Creek Association threatened enemies of this event like John Neville, whose house at Bower Hill was the focus of its first shots. “Light-Horse Harry” Lee led the troops that put down this uprising. The derisively nicknamed “Watermelon Army” participated in this rebellion to protest a financial measure implemented by Alexander Hamilton. For 10 points, name this Pennsylvania frontier revolt caused by a tax an alcohol. ","answer":"ANSWER: Whiskey Rebellion [or the Whiskey Revolt; or the Whiskey Uprising] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"2. The first sentence of this novel describes a woman whose beauty “seems to be thrown into relief by poor dress.” A landlord in this novel asks Mary Garth to destroy his will in order to deprive Joshua Rigg of his inheritance. One of this novel’s characters spends his honeymoon studying books in the Vatican library. That character in this novel is treated by Rosamond Vincy’s husband, Tertius Lydgate, and dies without finishing his book The Key to All Mythologies. In this novel, Edward Casaubon leaves a will stipulating that Will Ladislaw cannot marry Dorothea Brooke. For 10 points, name this “study of provincial life” by George Eliot. ","answer":"ANSWER: Middlemarch: A Study of Provincial Life "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"3. This pathway shares intermediates like sedulose-1,7-bisphosphate and xylulose-5-phosphate with the pentose phosphate pathway. An exciton forms at the special pair in the first phase of this process before the lone electron is shuttled from pheophytin to plastoquinone. To make up for how inefficiently it turns over, an enzyme in this pathway is the most common protein on Earth. NADP carries electrons in this pathway away from the P680 and P700 complexes. The thylakoid lumen develops a pH gradient during the light-dependent phase of this process. For 10 points, name this pathway that fixes carbon in the Calvin cycle and is used by plants to harvest solar energy. ","answer":"ANSWER: photosynthesis [or light-dependent reactions or LDR until it is read; or Calvin cycle until it is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"4. In 1845, John Snare allegedly found a lost painting by this artist depicting Charles I. This artist assisted Peter Paul Rubens in making a copy of Titian’s Rape of Europa, a painting he later featured as a tapestry in the background of a work depicting The Fable of Arachne. This artist’s still-life of a woman frying eggs is in the bodegón (bow-de-GON) genre. He made a portrait of the freed slave Juan de Pareja. This artist stands behind an easel wearing the red cross of the Order of Santiago in his most famous painting, which depicts two dwarves and a dog around the Infanta Margaret Theresa. For 10 points, name this Spanish Golden Age painter of Las Meninas. ","answer":"ANSWER: Diego Velázquez "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"5. Lanterns called fanous are often hung during this time period. According to one text, a night that takes place during this period is “better than a thousand months.” Because that night during this period can take place on any of five days, many adherents choose to practice i’tikah for ten days. During this period, daybreak is defined as the moment when a white thread appears distinct from a black thread. Extra prayers called tarawih are said during this period, during which adherents of a certain religion observe sawm. This month ends with the feast of Eid al-Fitr. For 10 points, name this month of the Islamic calendar in which Muslims fast from dawn to dusk. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ramadan [prompt on specific parts of Ramadan like Laylat al-Qadr and Eid al-Fitr] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"6. This leader wrote the Greek phrase “ginesthoi,” or “make it happen!” at the bottom of a document granting tax exemptions to Quintus Caecilius. Blaise Pascal claimed that “the world would have been changed” if this leader had a shorter nose. Despite a grant of sanctuary, this leader had her sister Arsinoe killed on the steps of the Temple of Artemis. The Donations of Alexandria distributed royal titles to this leader’s children, including her son Caesarion. After the Battle of Actium, this member of the Ptolemaic dynasty committed suicide with an asp. For 10 points, name this lover of Mark Antony and Julius Caesar who ruled as Queen of Egypt. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cleopatra VII Philopator "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"7. A newspaper based in this state won a Pulitzer Prize for its “Seven Days of Heroin” project. Macedonian immigrants to this state developed a type of chili that is poured over spaghetti noodles and garnished with oyster crackers. In 2011, 56 exotic animals escaped from a private zoo in this state’s town of Zanesville. Goodyear Tires is based in this state in a city that is nicknamed the “Rubber Capital of the World.” The Cuyahoga River flows through this state, where the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame is located on the shores of Lake Erie. For 10 points, name this US state, home to cities like Akron, Cincinnati, and Cleveland. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ohio "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"8. The speaker of a jazz standard set in this city owns a “cozy little flat,” in which she’ll “settle down / right here in town.” A bandleader from this city invited audiences to sing “hi-dee-hi-dee-hi-dee-hi” in the scat chorus of his song “Minnie the Moocher.” Paul Whiteman pioneered symphonic jazz in this city, which is where Cab Calloway led the house band of a whites-only nightclub. Billy Strayhorn composed “Take the ‘A’ Train” for a bandleader associated with this city’s Cotton Club, Duke Ellington. For 10 points, name this city where jazz flourished during the Harlem Renaissance. ","answer":"ANSWER: New York City [or NYC; prompt on Manhattan; prompt on Harlem until mentioned] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"9. One mathematician from this country lends his name to a theorem stating that every group G is isomorphic to a subgroup of the symmetric group acting on G. A mathematician from this country used his proof of the Taniyama-Shimura conjecture for semistable elliptic curves to find a proof for Fermat’s last theorem. This country was also home to a mathematician who developed a namesake “method” to approximate the roots of a function by repeatedly taking derivatives. That mathematician argued with Gottlieb Leibniz over who developed calculus. For 10 points, name this country home to Arthur Cayley, Andrew Wiles, and Isaac Newton. ","answer":"ANSWER: United Kingdom [or Britain; or England] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"0. A poem set in this city describes “parking spaces” that “luxuriate like civic sandpiles.” One of this city’s characteristic “marriages” is exemplified by Olive Chancellor’s relationship with Verena Tarrant in an 1886 novel. Another novel notes that the “forefathers” of this city chose to build a cemetery and a prison before anything else. A “savage servility slides by on grease” through this city, which “stands in a Sahara of snow” according to Robert Lowell’s poem “For the Union Dead.” This city, whose residents title a Henry James novel, is largely the setting of The Scarlet Letter. For 10 points, name this city, whose literary “Brahmins” often lectured at Harvard College. ","answer":"ANSWER: Boston [accept The Bostonians; prompt on Cambridge] Tiebreaker. The carbon in pulp process describes the recovery of this element. The Elsner equation describes the dissolution of this element through a cyanide solution. The relativistic contraction of this element’s 5s orbitals give it its characteristic color, and that of its 6s orbitals contribute to its resistance to corrosion. Complexes of this element can exhibit aurophilicity. The scattering of alpha particles on this element’s nuclei was observed by Geiger and Marsden, who used a foil made of this element. Aqua regia can dissolve both this element and platinum. Pyrite is sometimes nicknamed the “fool’s” type of this element. For 10 points, name this precious metal with a yellowish color. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Fine’s book Shared Fantasy discusses this leisure activity, which Philip Zimbardo linked to the “failure” of boys in his book Man, Interrupted. It doesn’t involve movies or music, but many studies have examined the relation between this leisure activity and males’ desensitization to violence. ","answer":"ANSWER: playing video games [or gaming; accept any descriptive or specific answers that involve video games] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Fine defines “naturework” as the way we give meaning to our surroundings in a book about people who collect these organisms. This organism appears in the title of an Anna Tsing book about “the Possibility of Life in Capitalist Ruins.” ","answer":"ANSWER: mushrooms [or Morel Tales: The Culture of Mushrooming; or The Mushroom at the End of the World: On the Possibility of Life in Capitalist Ruins; prompt on fungi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Fine’s book Sticky Reputations examines the influence of the “collective” form of this concept advanced by Maurice Halbwachs. This term refers to our ability to store and retrieve information. ","answer":"ANSWER: memory "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this law, which states that “2 d sine theta equals n lambda” to give the scattering angles of light diffraction in a crystal lattice. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bragg’s law "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Bragg’s law describes the diffraction of light rays in this region of the electromagnetic spectrum. These rays, first discovered by William Röntgen, are commonly used to image bones. ","answer":"ANSWER: X-rays [or X-radiation] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] This German scientist received the 1914 Nobel Prize in Physics for discovering X-ray diffraction, predating the work of the Braggs. X-ray diffraction is sometimes known as a type of diffraction named for this man. ","answer":"ANSWER: Max von Laue "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this snake-like giant who, along with Echidna, is the father of many of Greece’s most famous monsters. ","answer":"ANSWER: Typhon [or Typhos] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] This offspring of Typhon had poisonous breath and blood so toxic that even smelling it could kill you. Heracles had to burn this monster’s necks in order to stop its many heads from regenerating. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lernaean Hydra [or Hydra of Lerna] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] This two-headed dog was the first child of Typhon and Echidna. He was charged with guarding Geryon’s cattle and was eventually killed by Heracles. ","answer":"ANSWER: Orthrus [or Orthus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this algorithm extended by the Bellman-Ford algorithm, which allows for negative edge weights. ","answer":"ANSWER: Dijkstra’s algorithm "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Dijkstra’s algorithm is used to find shortest paths in these mathematical collections of vertices and edges. The Seven Bridges of Königsberg problem laid the foundation for the “theory” of these structures. ","answer":"ANSWER: graphs [or graph theory] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] The priority queues often used to store edges in Dijkstra’s algorithm can be implemented with the “min” variety of this tree-based data structure, in which each node’s leaves are less than or equal to the node itself. ","answer":"ANSWER: heap [or min heap; or binary heap] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this Holy Roman Emperor who called the Diet of Roncaglia after subduing Milan. This red-bearded commander drowned fording the Saleph River during the Third Crusade. ","answer":"ANSWER: Frederick Barbarossa [or Frederick I] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Frederick’s authority in Italy was opposed by this alliance of cities backed by Pope Alexander III. This alliance shared its name with a people once ruled by Desiderius. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lombard League "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] The Lombard League shattered Frederick’s army at this 1176 battle, ending his dream of direct imperial rule in Italy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Battle of Legnano "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this First Lady whose chic greatly influenced the trends of Western fashion in the 1960s and 70s. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jacqueline “Jackie” Kennedy [or Jacqueline Bouvier; or Jacqueline Onassis] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Kennedy often wore a strapless gown of this color designed by Christian Dior. On the day of her husband’s assassination, Kennedy was wearing an iconic Chanel wool suit of this color that became stained with blood. ","answer":"ANSWER: pink [or strawberry pink] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Ann Lowe, one of the first prominent African-American fashion designers, designed a famed one of these clothing items for Kennedy using ivory silk taffeta. In 2011, Sarah Burton designed one of these clothing items for Kate Middleton. ","answer":"ANSWER: wedding dress [or bridal gown; accept equivalents; prompt on dress] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this poetic title character who lived in a “pretty how town.” “Women and men” both “little and small” don’t care for this character, whose life is the subject of a poem with the refrain “sun moon stars rain.” ","answer":"ANSWER: anyone [or “anyone lived in a pretty how town”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] This capitalization-adverse poet wrote “anyone lived in a pretty how town.” A “conscientious object-or” whose “warmest heart recoiled at war” appears in his poem “i sing of Olaf glad and big.” ","answer":"ANSWER: e. e. cummings [or Edward Estlin Cummings] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] This Imagist writer bet mutual friend Scofield Thayer that cummings would not be a successful poet. The speaker of her poem “Patterns” observes “squills and daffodils” before exclaiming “Christ! What are patterns for?” ","answer":"ANSWER: Amy Lowell [prompt on Lowell] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this country where Ronald Reagan and Mikhail Gorbachev met for a 1986 summit. In 1949, protesters attacked this country’s parliament, the Althing, after it voted to join NATO. ","answer":"ANSWER: Iceland "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] During the Cold War, NATO used Iceland as a base to monitor the activity of these Soviet warships, which could be used to store missiles. The “nuclear” variety of these submersible vessels is powered by a nuclear reactor. ","answer":"ANSWER: Soviet nuclear submarines [or ballistic missile submarines; prompt on subs] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] The Althing repeatedly threatened to leave NATO during this series of informal conflicts between Iceland and the United Kingdom. This “war” ended when Britain agreed to stop harassing Icelandic fishing ships. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Cod Wars "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Plasma and memory cells are both involved in the “adaptive” form of what system, which is contrasted with its “innate” form? ","answer":"ANSWER: immune system [or innate immune system; or adaptive immune system] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Plasma cells are examples of these white blood cells that secrete antibodies. These lymphocytes are contrasted with natural killer cells and T cells. ","answer":"ANSWER: B cells [or B lymphocytes; accept plasma B cells; prompt on lymphocytes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] B cells are activated by the type 1 and 2 of these immune system signaling molecules. These cytokines were once thought to be exclusively used as communication between white blood cells. ","answer":"ANSWER: interleukins [or ILs; or IL-1; or IL-2] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this composer of a piece for an indefinite amount of performers consisting of 53 short numbered musical phrases, each intended to be repeated an arbitrary number of times independently by each musician. That piece by this composer is called In C. ","answer":"ANSWER: Terry Riley "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Terry Riley is a composer from this musical movement. Other composers associated with this movement include the composer of Dif erent Trains, Steve Reich, and Nixon and China composer John Adams. ","answer":"ANSWER: minimalism [accept word forms; prompt on modernism] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Terry Riley, Steve Reich, and John Adams are all minimalist composers from this country. ","answer":"ANSWER: United States of America [or America] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Identify this concept which, according to that text, is a “blind striving.” A posthumous text by a different philosopher declares that the world is this thing “and nothing besides!” ","answer":"ANSWER: will [accept Will-to-Life or Will-to-Live or Wille zum Leben; accept Will to Power or Wille zur Macht] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] This German pessimist used the philosophy of the Upanishads to state that human life should focus on opposing the Will-to-Life via asceticism in his book The World as Will and Representation. ","answer":"ANSWER: Arthur Schopenhauer "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] This German nihilist philosopher declared that “the world is the will to power – and nothing besides!” This author of Beyond Good and Evil coined the term “will to power” in Thus Spoke Zarathustra. ","answer":"ANSWER: Friedrich (Wilhelm) Nietzsche "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"4. After World War II, Niemoller apologized for his previous support of this leader’s anti-Semitic policies. ","answer":"ANSWER: Adolf Hitler "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Anti-Nazi theologians like Dietrich Bonhoeffer and Karl Barth formed this Christian movement after the Nazi Party officially absorbed Germany’s Protestant church. This movement’s views were expressed in the Barmen Declaration. ","answer":"ANSWER” the Confessing Church [or Bekennende Kirche] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Dietrich Bonhoeffer’s The Cost of Discipleship is an extended analysis of this Biblical event. This New Testament event is the source of the expressions “salt of the earth” and “turn the other cheek.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the Sermon on the Mount [prompt on the Beatitudes; prompt on the Gospel of Matthew] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this member of the Angry Young Men. The medieval history professor Jim Dixon is fired at the end of his campus novel Lucky Jim. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kingsley Amis [prompt on just Amis] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Alan Sillitoe, another member of the Angry Young Men, is most famous for this short story, in which Smith loses a race on purpose to spite his school. ","answer":"ANSWER: “The Loneliness of the Long Distance Runner” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] In Lucky Jim, Jim Dixon gives a drunken lecture about this “merrie” place. Amis, Sillitoe, and other members of the Angry Young Men set much of their work in this country.. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Merrie England” [accept Great Britain or the United Kingdom] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this empire known to the Han as “Daqin.” Emperor Huan of Han received ambassadors from this empire who claimed to have been sent by Marcus Aurelius. ","answer":"ANSWER: Roman Empire [or Rome] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] The Han were more successful in taking control of this modern-day country, which briefly secured independence from China during the Trung Sisters’ rebellion. This country’s last emperor, Bao Dai, ruled from the imperial city of Hue (he-WAY). ","answer":"ANSWER: Vietnam "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Emperor Wu of Han fought to acquire “heavenly” horses from the Dayuan of the Ferghana Valley in order to deploy them against these northern barbarians, whose incursions led to the construction of the Great Wall. ","answer":"ANSWER: Xiongnu [prompt on Huns] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this molecule, the simplest ketone. It is used in nail polish remover. ","answer":"ANSWER: acetone "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Most acetone is often industrially produced along with phenol in this process. This process, which was discovered by Heinrich Hock, is named for an aromatic intermediate. ","answer":"ANSWER: cumene-phenol process "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Cumene is produced by substituting a hydrogen on this molecule with an isopropyl group. Phenol is made by adding a hydroxyl group to this aromatic molecule, which has formula C6H6 . ","answer":"ANSWER: benzene "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this profession. In “The Albatross,” this profession is compared to a “prince of cloud and sky” whose “giant wings prevent him from walking.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the poet [prompt on writer or author] [10] “Benediction” and “The Albatross” appear in The Flowers of Evil alongside “The Swan,” which reflects on this city’s modernization. The second section of The Flowers of Evil is titled for this city’s “scenes.” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] This writer reflected on the role of the poet, as well as the modernization of Paris, throughout his Symbolist masterpiece The Flowers of Evil. ","answer":"ANSWER: Charles Baudelaire "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name these works that were traditionally printed on vellum, a prepared animal skin. The Book of Kells is a well-known example of this type of work. ","answer":"ANSWER: illuminated manuscripts [prompt on partial answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Prehistoric artists often preserved animal skins using a variety of the pigment ochre that was this color. Vermillion was another popular pigment of this color. ","answer":"ANSWER: red "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Native American artists began creating “ledger art” after it became difficult to obtain the hides of these animals, which were the most common hides used by Plains Indians to make teepees. One of these ungulates appears in the Wyoming state flag. ","answer":"ANSWER: American bison [or buffalo; accept buffalo hides; or bison hides] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this deliverer of the “Solitude of Self” speech who lost much of her influence after the publication of The Women’s Bible. ","answer":"ANSWER: Elizabeth Cady Stanton "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Stanton added a resolution advancing this cause to the Declaration of Sentiments at the Seneca Falls Convention. The aim of this cause was achieved with the passage of the 19th Amendment. ","answer":"ANSWER: women’s suffrage [accept women receiving the vote or equivalents; prompt on suffrage] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Stanton’s shift on Black civil rights was criticised by this man, who argued that Black men deserved the vote before White women. Earlier, this man was the only African American attendee at the Seneca Falls Conference. ","answer":"ANSWER: Frederick Douglass "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"2. ","answer":"ANSWER: Whitney Houston "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Houston’s family criticized Pusha T for using a photograph of Houston’s bathroom after her death as the cover art for this 2018 album. Its tracks include “If You Know You Know” and an epic takedown of Meek Mill, “What Would Meek Do?” ","answer":"ANSWER: Daytona "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] This rapper, who produced Pusha T’s Daytona, personally shelled out $85,000 to acquire the rights to the photograph of Houston’s bathroom. This husband of Kim Kardashian recently visited President Trump at the White House. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kanye West [accept either underlined portion; also accept Yeezy or Ye] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Name this capital city. Palace Walk is the first work in a trilogy of novels set in this city by the author of Midaq Alley. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cairo [accept the Cairo Trilogy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] Egyptian author Naguib Mahfouz, who wrote the Cairo Trilogy, is the only author to have received the Nobel Prize in Literature for writing primarily in this language. ","answer":"ANSWER: Arabic "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] This British novelist wrote a Quartet of novels set in Egypt’s city of Alexandria. His brother Gerald wrote My Family and Other Animals, which chronicles this author’s eccentric upbringing in Corfu. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lawrence Durrell Tiebreaker. The Taft-Katsura memorandum acknowledged Japan’s stake in Korea and disinterest in this country. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"6. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Philippines "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] This leader of the Philippine Senate led a 1934 delegation to Washington, D.C. to secure independence. It’s not Manila, but the Philippines’ largest city is named for this first president of the Commonwealth of the Philippines. ","answer":"ANSWER: Manuel Quezon [or Quezon City] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"N","question":"[10] This earlier leader of the Filipino independence movement led a guerilla campaign against Spain towards the end of its occupation of the Philippines. Once the Spanish left, he continued his war against the United States until he was captured by Frederick Funston. ","answer":"ANSWER: Emilio Aguinaldo"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"1. Two answers required. These two countries debated the course of a shifting riverbed in the Chamizal dispute. An incident between these two countries began when the Dolphin refused to give a 21-gun salute. Citizens from one of these countries migrated to work as farmhands in the other under the Bracero program. The Tampico affair increased tensions between these two countries, one of which launched a “Punitive Expedition” into the other’s territory after a raid on the town of Columbus. The Zimmerman Telegram offered one of these countries a chance to regain the land it lost to the other in the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo. For 10 points, name these two countries that share a border along the Rio Grande. ","answer":"ANSWER: United States of America AND Mexico "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"2. John Burton analogized differing views of these entities as either billiard balls or cobwebs. The Fund for Peace publishes an index indicating the fragility, or failure, of these entities. These entities comprise the second “image of analysis” according to a book by Kenneth Waltz pairing them with Man and War. Friedrich Engels postulated that, with the rise of a socialist society, this entity would “wither away.” These entities are the primary actors in IR theory. Max Weber defined this entity as having a “monopoly on the legitimate use of force,” and they are sometimes defined as having sovereignty over a region. For 10 points, name these political entities often paired with nations. ","answer":"ANSWER: states [do not accept or prompt on “nations” or “countries”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"3. Two of the oldest texts in this genre are written in Arabic and titled Kitab al-Tabikh. A famous book in this genre is dedicated to the “peasants, fishermen, housewives, and princes” of La Belle France. A book in this genre is all that remains after a ranch burns down in the wake of Pedro and Tita de la Garza’s wedding in Laura Esquivel’s Like Water for Chocolate. It’s not a diary, but Alice B. Toklas wrote a book in this genre from which “hashish fudge” originates. A more contemporary book in this genre by Nathan Myhrvold explores modernism through molecular gastronomy. For 10 points, name this genre that includes books written by Julia Child. ","answer":"ANSWER: cookbooks [or recipe books] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"4. A museum in this European country features Louise Bourgeois’ sculpture of a spider, Maman, and a giant Puppy made out of flowers by Jeff Koons. One of this country’s cities names an “effect” in which cultural tourism revitalizes a post-industrial city. Along with glass and limestone, a museum in this country makes extensive use of its architect’s trademark thin metal shells, which resemble a ship with fish scales when seen from across the Nervión River. Frank Gehry designed a Guggenheim Museum for this country’s city of Bilbao. For 10 points, name this country home to the Prado Museum in Madrid. ","answer":"ANSWER: Spain [or España] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"5. In molecular biology, the term “densitometry” refers to quantifying band intensity in this technique with software like ImageJ. The buffer for this process contains Tris, EDTA, and either acetate or borate. The “native” form of this procedure is done without sodium dodecyl [DOH-duh-sil] sulfate. This technique is the most common way to determine the efficiency of a restriction digest. “Run to red” is a mnemonic for orienting this procedure, which is done vertically for proteins and horizontally for DNA, but almost always uses a ladder to estimate molecular weights. For 10 points, name this procedure in which an electric field drives macromolecules through a polyacrylamide or agarose matrix. ","answer":"ANSWER: gel electrophoresis [or SDS-PAGE; or a gel; accept Western blot until “Tris” is read and prompt on it afterwards] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"6. This figure’s only weakness is a spot on his back where a leaf once landed. This son of Hjördís uses a sword belonging to his father that was previously shattered in two by Odin. With the help of the blacksmith Regin, this figure is able to bring together the two halves of the sword Gram. This figure, who was killed by Guthorm, could understand the speech of birds after killing and tasting the blood of the dwarf-turned-dragon Fafnir. In the Volsung Saga, this hero rides through a ring of fire to rescue the Valkyrie Brunhilde. For 10 points, name this son of Sigmund from Norse mythology. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sigurd [or Siegfried] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"7. This politician was manipulated by a group of industrialists known as the “seven bankers.” He resigned from office after a scandal involving the Swiss Mabetex construction firm. This politician issued vouchers to citizens as part of a “shock therapy” program designed by his prime minister Yegor Gaidar. This politician gave a defiant speech atop a tank during the August Coup. Oligarchs like Boris Berezovsky benefited from the privatization policies implemented by this president, who gained prominence after resigning from Mikhail Gorbachev’s cabinet. For 10 points, name this first president of post-Soviet Russia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Boris Yeltsin "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"1. This element, which was first isolated from salt water as an orange brown liquid, was named for its foul smell. For 10 points, name this halogen that is liquid at standard temperature. ","answer":"ANSWER: bromine [or Br] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"9. At the climax of The League of Extraordinary Gentlemen: Century, a thinly-veiled parody of this character morphs into an eye-covered giant and is stopped from destroying London by Mary Poppins. This character asks Ebony Dark’ness Dementia Raven Way to call him “Vampire” in the online novel My Immortal. In a Neil Cicierega video, this character and his namesake “Puppet Pals” search for the source of a “Mysterious Ticking Noise.” This character’s son, Albus Severus, uses a time-turner to prevent Cedric Diggory’s death in a play titled for this man and the Cursed Child. For 10 points, name this wizard protagonist of a J. K. Rowling series. ","answer":"ANSWER: Harry Potter [accept either] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"0. This character’s fate is the subject of a Lu Xun [SHOON] speech whose title asks “what happens after [this character] leaves home?” This character responds “the most wonderful thing of all would have to happen” to a question posed by a man who often calls her “little squirrel” and “little skylark.” This character, who lies about not eating macaroons, is blackmailed by Krogstad for taking a bank loan under her father’s name to fund a trip to Italy. At the end of a play, this friend of Christine Linde realizes she’s been living with a “stranger” for “eight whole years.” For 10 points, what woman slams the door on her husband Torvald at the end of Henrik Ibsen’s play A Doll’s House? ","answer":"ANSWER: Nora Helmer [accept either underlined portion] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"1. This minor planet is the only dwarf planet within the orbit of Neptune. For 10 points, name this largest object in the asteroid belt, which is named for the Roman goddess of agriculture. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ceres "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"2. This city’s Catholic government was bloodlessly overtaken by Protestants in the 1578 Alteratie. A Charles Mackay book discusses how a trend in this city began due to a mosaic virus that caused an object to change colors. The statues of this city’s Oude Kerk were destroyed by an iconoclastic mob during the Beeldenstorm. This city, which was gripped by “Tulip mania” in 1637, was the site of the world’s first central bank, as well as the world’s first stock exchange. Like Utrecht and Antwerp, this capital city would be underwater if not for an elaborate system of dikes. For 10 points, name this capital city that was the European headquarters of the Dutch East India Company. ","answer":"ANSWER: Amsterdam "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"3. One section of this text notes that “everything is foreseen, yet free will is given.” An influential commentary on one section of this text includes a list of thirteen “principles of faith.” A passage in this text questions “if I am not for myself, who will be for me?” and asks “if not now, when?” The two versions of this text are named for Babylon and Jerusalem. The Pirkei Avot is found in the first section of this text, which was organized into six orders by Hillel. This text consists of the Mishnah and the Gemara. For 10 points, name this key text of Rabbinic Judaism that consists of oral commentaries on Jewish law. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Talmud [prompt on Mishnah or Gemara before mention by asking, “what larger text is that a part of?”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"4. This historical figure examines a tapestry manufactory in a work depicting him “Visiting the Gobelins Factory.” Gian Lorenzo Bernini created a bust of this man, as well as a poorly received equestrian statue depicting him. A couple watch a portrait of this man being packed away in the painting Gersaint’s Shop Sign. Nicolas Poussin influenced the namesake style of this person, who employed Charles Le Brun as a court painter. This person holds a sceptre and flaunts his muscular legs in a portrait by Hyacinthe Rigaud. For 10 points, name this patron of 17th-century French art who commissioned the Palace of Versailles, nicknamed the “Sun King.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Louis XIV [prompt on partial answer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"5. Edward Bulwer-Lytton criticized a scene in which this character reconnects with his widowed and remarried childhood crush. Jack Maggs searches for a re-imagined version of this character in a Peter Carey novel. In that novel, Maggs represents this character’s benefactor, who became rich after working as a sheep farmer in Australia, the convict Abel Magwitch. This character’s love Estella is raised in Satis House, which is filled with stopped clocks to commemorate the failed wedding of Miss Havisham. For 10 points, name this orphaned protagonist of Charles Dickens’ Great Expectations. ","answer":"ANSWER: Philip “Pip” Pirrip [accept any underlined part] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"6. In a 1964 referendum, citizens of this country voted to return the “lost counties” to the Kingdom of Bunyoro. The Common Man’s Charter codified the nationalization policies of this country’s “Move to the Left.” A leader of this country was exiled to Saudi Arabia after he attempted to annex a neighboring country’s Kagera region. Thousands of Asians were expelled from this country by a dictator who welcomed a hijacked plane full of Jewish hostages to this country’s Entebbe airport. That dictator of this country declared himself the “Last King of Scotland.” For 10 points, name this country once ruled by Idi Amin from Kampala. ","answer":"ANSWER: Republic of Uganda "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"7. Wires are often “coupled” with respect to this phenomenon in order to limit power loss along the line. This process causes eddy currents which transform energy into heat because they resist the direction of change, as described by Lenz’s law. Transformers often use a coil named for this phenomenon in order to step up voltage. Solenoids cause this phenomenon within themselves. The electromotive force is proportional to the negative of the derivative of the magnetic flux with respect to time, according to Faraday’s law of this phenomenon. For 10 points, name this phenomenon in which a voltage is produced across a conductor due to a change in the magnetic field. ","answer":"ANSWER: electromagnetic induction "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"8. A character in this novel states “I seed de beginnin, en now I sees de endin” after she is moved to tears by a sermon. A woman in this novel who smells like honeysuckle scolds her brother for kissing the “dirty girl” Natalie, even though she herself has “muddied her drawers.” While watching golfers on his thirty-third birthday, a character in this novel is told to stop “moaning” by his caretaker Luster. On June 2, 1910, a Harvard student in this novel jumps off a bridge while thinking about his sister Caddy. For 10 points, name this novel narrated by Jason. Benjy and Quentin Compson, written by William Faulkner. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Sound and the Fury "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"9. Towards the end of this piece, the orchestra pauses, then blasts a dissonant, mostly whole-tone chord topped with an A for two bars; the orchestra then builds into its final reprisal of this piece’s “Stride” theme. It’s not by Copland, but in a 1942 recording of this composition, the opening “Ritornello” theme is played by Benny Goodman. Originally scored for two pianos, this piece is mostly performed as orchestrated by Ferde Grofé [“ferd gro-FE”]. This jazz-inspired piece opens with a trill followed by a long glissando in the solo clarinet. For 10 points, name this colorfully-named piece by George Gershwin. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rhapsody in Blue "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"0. A text by this philosopher organizes various “instances agreeing in the form of heat” into a “table of presentation.” Denis Diderot’s taxonomy of knowledge was inspired by this philosopher’s division of the human mind into memory, imagination, and reason. An allegorical book by this philosopher is set at an ideal school on the island of Bensalem. This philosopher theorized four fallacies called the “idols” of the cave, the tribe, the theater, and the marketplace in a text proposing his namesake method. For 10 points, name this British philosopher of The New Atlantis and Novum Organum who emphasized an empiricist and inductive scientific method. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sir Francis Bacon Tiebreaker. Along with pH, this quantity is one of the axes on a diagram that maps the equilibrium phases of an aqueous system, named for Marcel Pourbaix. A formula for calculating this quantity may include the number 0.059 if a common logarithm is involved, and most often contains the term “RT over nF ln Q”. This quantity’s value is defined as zero for the production of hydrogen gas from the H+ ion. The Nernst equation calculates this quantity, which is symbolized by a script E. For 10 points, name this “potential” that represents the tendency of a species to gain electrons. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this feminine alter-ego of a male artist whose name puns on the phrase “such is life.” This alias partially titles a sculpture consisting of a birdcage filled with marble cubes and cuttlefish bones. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rrose Sélavy [accept either underline portion; or Why Not Sneeze, Rose Sélavy?; prompt on Marcel Duchamp] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Rrose Sélavy was the feminine alter-ego of Marcel Duchamp, who promoted the “anti-art” of this avant-garde European movement. Its name, allegedly chosen from a dictionary at random, translates to “hobbyhorse.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Dadaism "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Duchamp stirred controversy by attempting to submit one of these objects, which he had reoriented 90 degrees and signed “R. Mutt 1917,” to New York’s Society of Independent Artists exhibit. ","answer":"ANSWER: a urinal [or toilet; do not accept or prompt on Fountain] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this novel in which Bamford drives a yellow baakie. It ends with Maureen running towards a helicopter. ","answer":"ANSWER: July’s People "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This Nobel laureate wrote July’s People. Jacobus finds a corpse on his farm in this author’s novel The Conservationist. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nadine Gordimer "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Nadine Gordimer hailed from this country, which banned July’s People after Gordimer spoke out against this country’s apartheid policy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Republic of South Africa "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name these bonds that link together two amino acids. ","answer":"ANSWER: peptide bonds [or peptides; or eupeptide bonds] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Trypsin’s active site contains a catalytic triad that uses this amino acid as a nucleophile. Protein kinase A belongs to a group of kinase enzymes that recognize either this amino acid or threonine. ","answer":"ANSWER: serine [or Ser or S; or serine protease; or serine-threonine kinase] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Unlike trypsin, papain [“pah-PAY-en”] belongs to a class of proteases named after this amino acid. The toughness of keratin is partly due to the disulfide bonds formed by this amino acid. ","answer":"ANSWER: cysteine [or Cys; or C; or cysteine protease] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this Roman general who described his conquest of Gaul in Commentaries on the Gallic Wars. He was later stabbed to death on the Ides of March. ","answer":"ANSWER: Julius Caesar "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Caesar finally subdued Vercingetorix at this battle. At this battle, Caesar built two sets of walls, one facing inwards to attack this battle’s namesake city and an outward wall to ward off Vercingetorix’s reinforcements. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alesia "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Caesar quipped “alea iacta est,” or “the die is cast,” as he marched his army over this Italian river. Caesar’s crossing of this river initiated the Great Roman Civil War. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Rubicon [or the Rubico] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name these people who may recall events inaccurately due to suggestibility and the misinformation effect. Loftus and Palmer demonstrated the unreliability of these people in an experiment that had patients describe the severity of a car crash. ","answer":"ANSWER: eyewitnesses [or On the Witness Stand: Essays on Psychology and Crime; accept court witnesses;] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Aside from creating Wonder Woman, Münsterberg’s student William Marston is known for championing the use of this device. Modern studies largely reject evidence provided by these devices, which determine the validity of eyewitnesses by measuring factors like blood pressure and heartbeat. ","answer":"ANSWER: lie detectors [or polygraph tests] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Münsterberg wrote a book pairing psychology with this sort of efficiency. This term is paired with the word “organizational” in the name of a branch of psychology that studies workplaces. ","answer":"ANSWER: industrial [or industrial efficiency; or industrial and organizational psychology] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this region of the body where a colored dot known as a bindi is often worn by Hindu and Jain women, traditionally to represent concealed wisdom or the “third eye.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the forehead [prompt on the face or head] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Hindu women receive the sindoor, a streak of vermillion across the forehead and hair, following one of these events. During this event, Hindus traditionally take seven steps around a holy fire as part of the ritual of Saptapadi. ","answer":"ANSWER: marriage [or wedding] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] In preparation for weddings, Hindu women will often host gatherings to be adorned in an ornate form of body art known by this name, that utilizes a brown dye obtained from the dried leaves of a certain plant. ","answer":"ANSWER: mehndi [or mehendi; or henna] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this head of the Second Bank of the United States who deliberately raised interest rates to cause a recession in an attempt to stop Andrew Jackson from shuttering the Second Bank. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nicholas Biddle "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Citing the Necessary and Proper Clause, this 1819 Supreme Court case affirmed the constitutionality of the Second Bank of the United States. This case’s majority opinion states “the power to tax is the power to destroy.” ","answer":"ANSWER: McCulloch v. Maryland "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This longest-serving Chief Justice of the Supreme Court authored the majority opinion in McCulloch. His majority opinion in Marbury v. Madison established the principle of judicial review. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Marshall "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this type of dance performed by Bojangles and Shirley Temple on a staircase in the film The Littlest Colonel. Most of Fred Astaire’s solo dances were performed in this style of dancing. ","answer":"ANSWER: tap dance [or tap dancing] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] After she was denied service at a hotel in this South American country, Dunham helped pass a bill forbidding racial discrimination in its cities. This country is the origin of the samba and jongo dance styles. ","answer":"ANSWER: Brazil "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This student of Dunham paid tribute to her in a performance titled The Magic of Katherine Dunham. He’s better known for founding a New York-based dance company and channeling spirituals and blues in his ballet Revelations. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alvin Ailey "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This Millennium Prize Problem concerns the equivalence of two complexity classes; it asks whether a problem that can be “quickly” verified can also be solved “quickly”. ","answer":"ANSWER: P versus NP problem [or Does P=NP?; or other answers that specify both P and NP; do not accept or prompt on just “P” or “NP”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] If P is in fact equivalent to NP, this technique of translating readable data to apparent nonsense for secure communication purposes would break. Its “public key” variant may use the RSA system. ","answer":"ANSWER: cryptography [or cryptology; or encryption; or cryptosystems; or public-key cryptography; accept word forms] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] A problem C belongs to this complexity class if C is in NP and every NP problem can be reduced to C in polynomial time. Finding a Hamiltonian path for a graph is a classic problem in this complexity class. ","answer":"ANSWER: NP-completeness "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this Dutch physicist who introduced a and b parameters in his namesake equation of state for gases. ","answer":"ANSWER: Johannes Diderik van der Waals "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Van der Waals’ equation of state treats real gases, as opposed to this type of gas, which is represented as point particles that have perfectly elastic collisions. This kind of gas names a “law” that states PV equals nRT. ","answer":"ANSWER: ideal gases "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] The law of corresponding states says that all gases have roughly the same value for this quantity at the same reduced pressure and temperature. This quantity, symbolized Z, describes the deviation of a gas from ideal behavior. ","answer":"ANSWER: compressibility factor [or compression factor; prompt on gas deviation factor] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this sculptor from Greek myth who fell in love with one of his own statues, Galatea. ","answer":"ANSWER: Pygmalion "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Pygmalion hailed from this island, which was also the birthplace of Adonis and Teucer. According to legend, this island’s city of Paphos was founded by Pygmalion’s son. ","answer":"ANSWER: Cyprus "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This Greek goddess of love had a cult center at Paphos. When Pygmalion fell in love with his own statue, he prayed to this wife of Hephaestus, who agreed to bring the statue to life. ","answer":"ANSWER: Aphrodite "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] A descriptivist theory of names was put forth by this thinker in his book A System of Logic. He’s better known for advancing the “greatest-happiness principle” in his Utilitarianism. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Stuart Mill "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This philosopher rebuked Mill’s theory by proposing a distinction between “sense” and “reference.” He illustrated the former with the example of how both Hesperus and Phosphorus refer to the planet Venus. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gottlob Frege [or Friedrich Ludwig Gottlob Frege] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Later philosophers described “fixing” and “borrowing” in a theory of reference described by this process. Mill’s five methods of induction illustrate this process, which Aristotle divided into material, formal, efficient, and final types. ","answer":"ANSWER: causation [or causal reference; or causes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this realm that was elevated to an empire by its Habsburg archdukes after they dissolved the Holy Roman Empire. It was ruled in a dual monarchy with Hungary. ","answer":"ANSWER: Austria [or Austrian Empire; accept Austro-Hungarian Empire] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] At the Congress of Vienna, this reactionary Austrian statesman formed the German Confederation to ensure Austria’s continued domination of the former Holy Roman Empire. ","answer":"ANSWER: Klemens von Metternich "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Under Metternich, Austria did not join this economic union, founded by Prussia in 1834, that limited tariffs on trade between German-speaking states. ","answer":"ANSWER: Zollverein "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this color. This color reminds Celie of her romantic partner Shug Avery, which inspires her to decorate her home entirely in red and this color. ","answer":"ANSWER: purple [or The Color Purple; do not accept or prompt on shades of purple like “violet”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] The Color Purple was written by this woman. She dedicated that novel’s sequel, Possessing the Secret of Joy, to the “blameless vulva.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Alice Walker "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] In the 1970s, Alice Walker edited and contributed content to this feminist magazine, which was co-founded by Gloria Steinem. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ms. magazine "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name these theoretical subatomic particles that are believed to move faster than the speed of light. ","answer":"ANSWER: tachyons "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Tachyons have an imaginary value for this quantity. According to Newton’s second law, force is equal to this quantity times acceleration. ","answer":"ANSWER: mass "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Tachyons violate this principle, which describes how phenomena cannot be created from things that happen outside the light cone before them. ","answer":"ANSWER: causality [or causation; or cause; accept word forms "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this opera, based on a Nikolai Leskov novel, that was attacked in the article “Muddle Instead of Music.” In this opera, Katerina feeds her husband Zinovy poison mushrooms so she can marry the merchant Boris. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lady Macbeth of the Mtsensk District [or Lady Macbeth of Mtsensk] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This Soviet composer described his 5th Symphony as a reply to the “justified criticism” received by his Lady Macbeth of the Mtsensk District. He also composed the Leningrad Symphony. ","answer":"ANSWER: Dmitri (Dmitriyevich) Shostakovich "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] The ostinato “invasion theme” of Shostakovich’s Leningrad Symphony is accompanied by this percussion instrument. This instrument maintains a constant ostinato throughout Ravel’s Bolero. ","answer":"ANSWER: snare drum [prompt on drum] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this short story in which Gabriel Conroy learns of his wife Mary’s youthful love affair with Michael Furey. It is the last and longest story collected in Dubliners. ","answer":"ANSWER: “The Dead” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This author included “The Dead” alongside “Araby” and “Ivy Day in the Committee Room” in his short story collection Dubliners. ","answer":"ANSWER: James Joyce "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] At the end of “The Dead,” Gabriel Conroy notes that this substance is “general all over Ireland.” In the story’s last sentence, this substance is described “faintly falling” over “all the living and the dead.” ","answer":"ANSWER: snow [or snowflakes] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this community of American-based Mennonites who avoid using modern technology and wear 18th century clothing. Their largest settlement is in Lancaster County, Pennsylvania. ","answer":"ANSWER: Amish [or Pennsylvania Dutch] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Some Amish communities have begun using modern power tools to construct these buildings, which are sometimes built in under an hour by Amish during a communal ceremony known as their “raising.” ","answer":"ANSWER: barns "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Most Amish teenagers experiment with modern technology as part of this Amish coming-of-age period, during which they are separated from their families and allowed to explore the outside world. ","answer":"ANSWER: rumpsringa "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this cult leader who moved his organization, the People’s Temple, from the United States to a compound in Guyana. He and his followers drank flavor aid laced with cyanide in a 1978 mass suicide. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jim Jones "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Before they moved to Guyana, Jones and his followers were based in this Northern California city, where they helped elect Harvey Milk as this city’s first gay elected official. ","answer":"ANSWER: San Francisco, California "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] The Jonestown massacre occurred shortly after the People’s Temple ambushed this congressman, who had inspected Jonestown a day prior. He is the only congressman to have been killed in the line of duty. ","answer":"ANSWER: Leo Ryan "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this home country of the Andalusian-born Juan Ramón Jiménez. This country’s Baroque authors included the rival poets Luis de Góngora and Francisco de Quevedo. ","answer":"ANSWER: Spain [or España] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Jiménez moved from Seville to Madrid at the behest of this Nicaraguan poet, who pioneered modernismo with his collection Azul… . ","answer":"ANSWER: Rubén Darío "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Dario was first championed by the critic Juan Valera, an author whose novel Pepita Jiménez is associated with the Spanish branch of this movement that depicted everyday life. French writers in this style, which is not Naturalism, included Stendhal and Honoré de Balzac. ","answer":"ANSWER: realism [or realist literature] Tiebreaker. As part of a failed coup d’etat, planes bombed the Plaza de Mayo during one of this man’s rallies. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this husband of Evita whose presidency was built on the support of working-class descamisados, or “shirtless ones.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Juan Domingo Peron "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Peron’s death ushered in a military takeover of this South American country, whose leaders murdered dissidents in the Dirty War. ","answer":"ANSWER: Argentina "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] During the Dirty War, a group of these people named for the Plaza de Mayo wore white scarves to protest the abduction and murder their “disappeared” relatives. ","answer":"ANSWER: mothers [or grandmothers; accept equivalents to “mother” like madre or mom; prompt on women or girls] EXTRA For 10 points each, answer the following about South American natives: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Yanomami tribes live deep in this country’s Amazon rainforest, where they have been encroached upon by garimpeiro gold miners. Through the practice of cunhadismo, this country’s coastal Tupi people intermarried with Portuguese settlers, but largely died out due to disease. ","answer":"ANSWER: Brazil "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] The indigenous Guarani language is the most widely spoken language in this country. During the rule of Alfredo Stroessner, this country’s Aché people were openly massacred and enslaved. ","answer":"ANSWER: Paraguay "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] These natives under Lautaro resisted Pedro de Valdivia in the 16th century and remained largely independent until the 19th-century occupation of Araucanía. These natives name an ongoing conflict against Chile’s government. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mapuche The Aborigine Bungaree accompanied this captain on his journeys as a guide and interpreter. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] Name this explorer who first circumnavigated Australia and identified it as a continent. His suggestion to name the continent “Australia” was formally adopted by Governor Lachlan Macquarie. ","answer":"ANSWER: Matthew Flinders "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"[10] This captain of the HMS Endeavor christened Botany Bay and made the first circumnavigation of New Zealand. This explorer died in a scuffle in Hawaii after abducting King Kalaniʻōpuʻu. ","answer":"ANSWER: James Cook "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"O","question":"6. He named the new land for this country’s province of Zeeland, though it didn’t stick. ","answer":"ANSWER: Netherlands"},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"1. The third book of this text describes a city in which men are separated based on whether they originate from silver, iron, brass, or gold. A character in this text imagines a line and cuts it into two unequal sections; the shorter section represents the visual world, while the longer section represents the intelligible world. This text argues that education in gymnastics is essential for the guardian class. This dialogue opens with Glaucon accompanying a character to a celebration where Polemarchus and Thrasymachus define justice. The “Allegory of the Cave” appears in, for 10 points, what Socratic dialogue that defines an ideal city-state? ","answer":"ANSWER: The Republic [or Res Publica] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"2. A female engineer from this country invented a device used to solve engine stall in planes called “Miss Shilling’s Orifice.” Specially built “bouncing bombs” were used by a squadron of this country's air force known as the Dam Busters. This country was the planned target of Operation Sea Lion. The leader of this country remarked “never in the field of human conflict was so much owed by so many to so few” to commend the service of its Hurricane and Spitfire pilots. For fifty-seven consecutive nights, the Luftwaffe [“LOOFT-vah-fuh”] bombed this country’s capital during the Blitz. For 10 points, name this country led through World War II by Winston Churchill. ","answer":"ANSWER: United Kingdom [or Great Britain; prompt on England] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"3. Little Walter was one of the first musicians to play this instrument with an amplifier. It’s not the guitar, but musicians playing this instrument often use “bending” to adjust the pitch of their notes. Benjamin Franklin is credited with inventing a supposedly-dangerous instrument of this name used in the “Aquarium” section of the Carnival of the Animals. This instrument plays solos near the beginning of Neil Young’s “Heart of Gold” and Billy Joel’s “Piano Man.” A comb and reed plates form the chambers of this instrument, which is alternatively known as a French harp. For 10 points, name this handheld instrument popular in blues music, sometimes called a mouth organ. ","answer":"ANSWER: harmonica [or glass harmonica; accept French harp until mentioned; accept mouth organ until mentioned] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"4. The posterior part of this bone is bent to form the gonial angles. This bone’s namesake “arch” is formed from segments known as Meckel’s cartilages, and is also known as the first pharyngeal arch. The hyoid bone sits at the base of this bone, which is separated by the zygomatic arch from the temporal bone. The muscles of mastication are inserted into this bone, which lies below the maxilla and, apart from the inner ear bones, is the only movable bone in the skull. For 10 points, the lower teeth are held in place by what bone used for chewing food? ","answer":"ANSWER: mandible [or lower jaw; or jawbone; prompt on skull] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"5. A drama major in one of this man’s novels is warned not to fall into the cold, dark “field well” by a woman who is grieving her boyfriend’s suicide. Philip Gabriel translated a novel by this author whose characters include a cat murderer named Johnnie Walker. That novel uses alternating bold and normal type to represent the “boy named Crow,” who lives in Miss Saeki’s library. This author’s most recent novel is Killing Commendatore. The map-obsessed Storm Trooper rooms with Toru Watanabe as he dates Naoko in one of this man’s novels, which takes its name from a Beatles song. For 10 points, name this Japanese author of Kafka on the Shore and Norwegian Wood. ","answer":"ANSWER: Haruki Murakami [accept either underlined part] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"6. In a region of this country, children celebrate Christmas Eve by feeding snacks to anthropomorphic “Christmas logs,” which “release” presents as excrement on Christmas morning. Roughly three-quarters of this country’s population participates in its annual Christmas lottery, which is the biggest lottery in the world. Revellers wearing white clothes and red scarves pray to Saint Fermin before participating in the encierno portion of a festival held in this country. Many pilgrims walk this country’s Way of St. James to visit the Cathedral of Santiago de Compostela. For 10 points, name this country where Pamplona hosts an annual “running of the bulls.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Kingdom of Spain [or Reino de España] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"7. This empire lost a naval squadron to a cyclone during a standoff with the United States in Apia Harbor. This empire poisoned desert wells and built the Shark Island prison camp during a military campaign sparked by Hendrik Witbooi’s rebellion. The “place in the sun” speech was delivered by this empire’s ruler, who initiated the Agadir crisis by sending the Panther gunboat to French-controlled Morocco. Africa was partitioned into European colonies at an 1884 conference hosted in this empire’s capital. This empire, which committed the Herero genocide, lost all of its African colonies in the Treaty of Versailles. For 10 points, name this empire ruled by Kaiser Wilhelm II. ","answer":"ANSWER: Germany [or Deutschland or the German Empire] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"8. This book’s 27th chapter outlines the “redemption of votive gifts,” or the redemption of vowed offerings. 1 Peter 1:16 cites this book’s repeated admonition to “be holy, because I am holy.” In this book, Nadab and Abihu are punished for using a “strange fire” to offer a sacrifice. This book’s description of casting a goat into the desert to drive away sin is the origin of the term “scapegoat.” Chapters 17 through 26 of this book are called the Holiness Code and lists rules for sacrifices and punishments for blasphemy. This book details instructions from God to the Israelites after they reached Mount Sinai. For 10 points, name this book that follows Exodus, the third book of the Old Testament. ","answer":"ANSWER: Book of Leviticus [or Vayikra] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"9. The hexahydrate of this compound, which generally forms very spiky or steep crystals, is called ikaite [eye-kay-ATE]. Parts of concrete can react with carbon dioxide to form this compound, which can cause corrosion. The depth after which this compound is no longer found in the ocean is its namesake compensation depth. Polymorphs of this compound include vaterite and aragonite. The Mohs scale of mineral hardness defines 3 as this compound’s most stable polymorph, calcite. Heating the solid form of this substance forms quicklime. For 10 points, name this chemical compound found in limestone with chemical formula CaCO3 . ","answer":"ANSWER: calcium carbonate [or CaCO3 until it is read] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"0. In a poem by this writer, the speaker hopes that “dunghill mists away may fly” if they can “raise up thoughts above the sky.” This writer is said to have “moved, restless, waiting for the Governor” in an “homage” to this poet written by John Berryman. She describes a love “prized more than whole mines of gold” that “rivers cannot quench” in a poem that ends with the declaration “if ever two were one, then surely we.” This author of a poem dedicated to her “Dear and Loving Husband” remarks that her “hope and treasure lie above” in some “Verses upon the Burning of our House.” For 10 points, name this colonial era poet of The Tenth Muse Lately Sprung Up in America. ","answer":"ANSWER: Anne Bradstreet "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"1. A King of Naples who married into this family ordered his executioners to shoot “straight to the heart but spare the face!” This family included a king who was ridiculed as the “Rabbit of Holland” for his poor Dutch, Louis I. The first modern German constitution was authored by a ruler from this family, King Jerome of Westphalia. The best known member of this family may have removed the “u” from its surname in order to conceal his origins as a minor Corsican nobleman. That member of this family came to power in the coup of 18 Brumaire but lost his empire at the Battle of Waterloo. For 10 points, name this family that produced Napoleon. ","answer":"ANSWER: Bonaparte family [or Buonaparte; the first clue refers to Joachim Murat] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"2. This artist used the term croqueton [“cro-kay-TAWN”] for the studies he made in preparation for paintings. Years after finishing a work, this artist restretched its canvas to add a border of red, orange, and blue. This painter of Circus Sideshow was promoted by the critic Félix Fénéon, who praised his use of chromoluminarism. This artist’s best-known painting features a man in red smoking a pipe in the bottom left. In that painting, an umbrella-holding woman with a monkey on a leash is one of a crowd of Parisians lounging along the River Seine. For 10 points, name this pointillist painter of A Sunday Afternoon on the Island of La Grande Jatte. ","answer":"ANSWER: Georges Seurat "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"3. They’re not electromagnetic waves, but the namesake impedance of these things is measured in rayls [“rails”] per square meter and is equal to their namesake pressure divided by their namesake density. A-weighting can be used to quantify these things in relation to humans’ sensitivity to them. The deep scattering layer was discovered by probing with these things, which detected a “false bottom” in the ocean. The speed of these waves is equal to the square root of bulk modulus over density. The propagation of these waves are used by sonar to navigate underwater, and their namesake pressure is measured with decibels. For 10 points, name these waves that can reflect to form echoes. ","answer":"ANSWER: sound waves [or acoustic waves] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"4. A novel written in this language concerns Bartlebooth’s attempts to produce and solve 500 watercolor jigsaw puzzles. Experimental novels like Life: A User’s Guide and A Void were written in this language by members of the Oulipo [OOH-lee-poh] group. It isn’t English, but most of Samuel Beckett’s later works were written in this language. The protagonist of a novel written in this language travels to the Home for Aged Persons to attend the funeral of his mother, who died “today. Or, maybe yesterday.” Later, the protagonist of that novel inexplicably shoots an Arab on the beach. For 10 points, The Stranger was written in what language used by the writers Georges Perec and Albert Camus? ","answer":"ANSWER: French [or Francais] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"5. A piece by this composer begins with a three chord motif with the syllables“Le-be-wohl” written across each chord. The opening Grave [GRAH-vay] movement of one of this composer’s sonatas begins with a long C minor fortepiano chord. This composer wrote pieces named Les Adieux [LAY ah-DYOO] and Waldstein during his “middle period.” A work by this composer instructs the performer to hold the sustain pedal throughout the entire piece and opens with slow right hand C-sharp minor triplets. That piece by this composer was inspired by Lake Lucerne and is subtitled Quasi una fantasia. For 10 points, name this composer of the Moonlight Sonata. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ludwig van Beethoven "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"6. Robert Bellah used President Kennedy’s inaugural address to illustrate the “civil” form of this phenomenon in America. Emile Durkheim claimed this phenomenon arose out of “collective effervescence.” In a lecture on this phenomenon “as a Cultural System,” Clifford Geertz defined it as a “system of symbols [that formulates] conceptions of a general order of existence.” Edward Taylor and E. Evans Pritchard were among those who studied the “primitive” form of this phenomenon, seen in systems like totemism and animism. For 10 points, anthropologists often study the relationship between mythology and what belief systems, which can be polytheistic or monotheistic? ","answer":"ANSWER: religion [or civil religion; or primitive religion] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"7. In this US state, a fort commanded by William Moultrie withstood a British siege because its soft wooden walls literally absorbed the cannonballs fired at it. The British occupation of this state was led by a general nicknamed “Butcher” due to his alleged participation in the Waxhaws massacre, Banastre Tarleton. Guerilla forces led by Francis Marion harassed redcoats in this state, which was the site of the Battle of Kings Mountain. British troops withdrew from this state after the Battle of Cowpens. Members of this state’s militia were sometimes called “gamecocks.” For 10 points, name this state where the British Army besieged Charleston. ","answer":"ANSWER: South Carolina "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"8. A quantity named for this man is squared in the denominator of the density parameter omega. In October 2018, a law originally named for this man was renamed in honor of its earliest formulator Georges Lemaître [luh-MET-ruh]. He developed a classification system which separates objects labelled ‘S’ and ‘SB’ on the prongs of a so-called “tuning fork.” A constant first estimated as 500 kilometres per second per megaparsec appears in a law co-named for this man, which states that a galaxy’s recession speed is proportional to its distance from Earth. For 10 points, many deep field photos of galaxies have been taken by what astronomer’s namesake “space telescope”? ","answer":"ANSWER: Edwin Hubble [or Hubble parameter; or Hubble tuning fork; or Hubble constant; or Hubble-Lemaitre law; or Hubble Space Telescope] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"9. A participant in this event uses a thick shoe made from pieces of discarded leather to hold a wolf’s jaws open. The giant herdsman Eggthér plays his harp while the rooster Fjalar [FYAWL-ar] crows to announce this event. One participant in this event takes nine steps before collapsing from poison after killing a serpent that encircles the world. The giant Surtr [SURT] leads an army from Muspelheim to battle against the gods in this event, which is announced when Heimdall blows the Gjallarhorn [GYAWL-ar-horn]. Vidarr avenges his father Odin during this event by killing the wolf Fenrir. For 10 points, name this apocalyptic battle of Norse myth. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ragnarök [prompt on apocalypse, end of the world or equivalents] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"0. This poet likens “crowds upon the pavement” to “fields of harvest wheat” in a poem describing his walk “down Bristol Street.” Though mostly known for his poems, this author collaborated on plays like The Ascent of F6 with his companion Christopher Isherwood. One of this man’s poems claims that “accurate scholarship can unearth” what “huge imago made a psychopathic god,” although even “schoolchildren know” that “those to whom is evil is done / do evil in return.” This poet of “As I Walked Out One Evening” sits in a dive bar on 52nd Street at the beginning of a poem which proclaims “we must love one another or die.” For 10 points, name this poet of “September 1, 1939.” ","answer":"ANSWER: W. H. (Wystan Hugh) Auden Tiebreaker. An extended form of this function is defined as the integral from zero to infinity of “x to the z minus 1 times e to the negative x”. The “hyper” form of this operation gives the number 27,648 for an input of "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"4. The Taylor series of the exponential function has denominators involving this function, which is extended to all real numbers by the gamma function. The sum from “n equals zero” to infinity of 1 over this function of n gives the number e. This function is applied to give the number of permutations of n objects. For 10 points, name this function that, for n, gives the product of the natural numbers from 1 to n. ","answer":"ANSWER: factorial function [or n factorial] Bonuses "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this performance artist who gained prominence through her collaborations with Ulay. She invited museum visitors to sit across a table from her in her performance The Artist Is Present. ","answer":"ANSWER: Marina Abramovic "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] The Artist is Present was performed at the Museum of Modern Art in this city. A 1989 poster by the Guerrilla Girls notes that “less than 5% of the artists are women, but 85% of the nudes are female” in the Modern Art section of this city’s Met Museum. ","answer":"ANSWER: New York City [or NYC] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] This Japanese performance artist allowed audience members to cut pieces of her dress in Cut Piece. Along with her husband, John Lennon, she protested the Vietnam War by lying in a hotel bed for two weeks. ","answer":"ANSWER: Yoko Ono "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this poet whose “Fair Youth” sonnets may be about a male lover, although he also wrote poems dedicated to a “Dark Lady.” Willie Hughes is named as his lover in the short story “The Portrait of W.H.” ","answer":"ANSWER: William Shakespeare "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] This author of the aforementioned “Portrait of W.H.” was imprisoned in Reading Gaol [RED-ing JAIL] for pursuing sexual relationships with other men, including Alfred Douglas. He wrote The Importance of Being Earnest. ","answer":"ANSWER: Oscar Wilde "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Biographer Rene Weis suggested that Shakespeare had an affair with this playwright. The title English king lusts after his male attendant Piers Gaveston in this man’s play Edward II. ","answer":"ANSWER: Christopher Marlowe "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Give this name shared by that historian and his ancestor, a king of the Saxons who resisted Charlemagne’s attempts to conquer and Christianize his people. ","answer":"ANSWER: Widukind "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"2. ","answer":"ANSWER: Otto the Great [or Otto I] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] At Lechfeld, Otto put an end to the westward invasions of this Carpathian tribe. This ethnic group was unified by Stephen I, who is venerated by this ethnicity’s modern descendents at a namesake basilica in Budapest. ","answer":"ANSWER: Magyars [or Hungarians] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this property of galvanic cells, which is measured in volts. This quantity is positive if current can flow from the anode to the cathode. ","answer":"ANSWER: electrode potential difference [or voltage; or electromotive force; or redox potential; prompt on “reduction potential”; prompt on “oxidation potential”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] This equation gives the electrochemical potential of a galvanic cell as a function of concentrations and temperature. It is named for a German chemist who formulated the third law of thermodynamics. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nernst equation "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Electrochemical cells use many kinds of standard electrodes. A very common one is the saturated calomel electrode, which contains this element and its chloride. ","answer":"ANSWER: mercury [or Hg] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this civilization whose creation myth, known as the Popol Vuh, tells of how the Hero Twins journeyed to Xibalba [chi-BAWL-bah] to defeat the Lords of the Underworld. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mayan civilization "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] After the Hero Twins defeated the Xibalbans in the ball game, they were burnt in a great oven before being regenerated in the form of these animals. In Japanese mythology, one of these animals named Namazu causes earthquakes. ","answer":"ANSWER: catfish [prompt on fish] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] In Mayan mythology, it is believed that humans were created from this crop. The Maya would wash and hull this crop through nixtamalization to make food such as tortillas and tamales. ","answer":"ANSWER: maize [or corn] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Give this surname of Amos Bronson, who founded the Fruitlands commune. Amos’ daughter, who shares this surname, satirized her father in Transcendental Wild Oats and wrote three novels about the students of Professor Bhaer’s Plumfield Estate School. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alcott [accept Amos Bronson Alcott or Louisa May Alcott] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Elsewhere in A Fable for Critics, Lowell claims that feeling emotional in the presence of this poet is akin to “being stirred up with the very North Pole.” This poet wrote “To a Waterfowl” and “Thanatopsis.” ","answer":"ANSWER: William Cullen Bryant "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Lowell also feuded with this author, who he accused of creating unrealistic female characters. A Mark Twain essay titled for this author’s “Literary Offenses” mocks a scene from one of his novels in which Natty Bumppo shoots a nailhead from a thousand yards. ","answer":"ANSWER: James Fenimore Cooper "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this octagonal building in Houston, Texas whose entrance features Barnett Newman’s Broken Obelisk over a reflecting pool designed by Philip Johnson. It houses 14 black-hued canvases created by an artist who also painted the Seagram Murals. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rothko Chapel [prompt on partial answer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Mark Rothko’s large canvases of flat, solid colors are considered part of the “color-field” branch of this art movement, which critic Clement Greenberg contrasted with so-called “action painting.” ","answer":"ANSWER: abstract expressionism [prompt on partial answer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] This action painter’s extensive use of “drip painting” in works like Lavender Mist and Autumn Rhythm inspired his nickname “Jack the Dripper.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Jackson Pollock "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this proto-anarchist group led by Gerrard Winstanley that opposed the enclosure of British land in the 17th century. Members of this group practiced communal farming on St. George’s Hill in Surrey. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Diggers [or the True Levellers; do not accept or prompt on “Levellers”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] The Diggers agitated during the reign of this Lord Protector of England. He commanded the New Model Army during the English Civil War. ","answer":"ANSWER: Oliver Cromwell "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Like the Diggers, these 19th century English dissenters are often described as articulating an early form of Marxism. These disgruntled textile workers, who opposed the industrialization of their jobs, often destroyed factory machinery at their protests. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Luddites "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this species of mollusk that was originally native to southern Russian and Ukrainian lakes. ","answer":"ANSWER: zebra mussel [or Dreissena polymorpha; prompt on partial answer] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Zebra mussels are commonly classified as one of these organisms, which are introduced to a non-native area and often outcompete other local species for resources. Kudzu is one of these organisms. ","answer":"ANSWER: invasive species "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] An invasive species that feeds on marsh plants in Louisiana, the nutria, is a member of this largest mammalian order. Members of this order such as the capybara often gnaw on objects with their large incisors. ","answer":"ANSWER: rodents [or Rodentia] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this philosopher who illustrated his claim that “meaning just ain’t in the head” with a thought experiment about an alternate version of earth where the chemical symbol for water is “XYZ.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Hilary (Whitehall) Putnam "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Putnam’s “Twin Earth” thought experiment argues for the externalist view of this concept, which, broadly speaking, is the study of meaning in language. In linguistics, this concept is typically contrasted with syntax. ","answer":"ANSWER: semantics "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Hilary Putnam is also known for his functionalist theory of this entity. Dualists believe that this entity is fundamentally different than the body. ","answer":"ANSWER: the mind "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this New York senator whose namesake legislation, passed in 1935, created the National Labor Relations Board and guaranteed collective bargaining rights to unions. ","answer":"ANSWER: Robert F. Wagner "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] The Wagner Act was signed into law by this president, who sought to win labor union support for his New Deal policies. ","answer":"ANSWER: Franklin Delano Roosevelt [or FDR; prompt on Roosevelt] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Before he was a senator, Wagner chaired New York’s investigation of this clothes company. A 1911 fire in this company’s Manhattan factory killed 146 of its mostly female garment workers. ","answer":"ANSWER: Triangle Shirtwaist Company [or Triangle Shirtwaist Factory fire] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name these frameworks popularized in the studies of British psychologist Frederic Bartlett. Responsible for processing and categorizing information, they can be utilized through assimilation and accommodation. ","answer":"ANSWER: schemas [or schemata] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] This Swiss psychologist was inspired by Immanuel Kant to introduce the psychological schema. He is better known for proposing four stages of cognitive development. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jean Piaget "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] The “internalization of schemas,” along with the development of skills like language and object permanence, conclude this first of Piaget’s four stages. It is followed by the preoperational stage. ","answer":"ANSWER: sensorimotor stage "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this Edwin Abbott novella whose protagonist, A Square, is arrested after suggesting a third dimension can be reached by traveling “upward, not northward.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Flatland: A Romance of Many Dimensions "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] The Time Traveller characterizes the four dimensions as “length, breadth, thickness, and duration” in this author’s The Time Machine. Smoke and heat rays rain down on Earth in his The War of the Worlds. ","answer":"ANSWER: H. G. (Herbert George) Wells "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] A group of power hungry Fourth Dimensionists attempt to colonize Earth in this author’s The Inheritors. This author of Nostromo wrote about Legatt hiding aboard a captain’s ship in his short story “The Secret Sharer.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Joseph Conrad [or Jozef Teodor Konrad Korzeniowski] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this religious text written in the Gurmukhi script. This text is divided into 31 ragas and contains 1,430 angs, or “limbs.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Adi Granth [or Adi Sri Granth Sahib Ji; or Guru Granth Sahib; or Granth Sahib] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] The Adi Granth is the living Guru of this religious faith that originated in Punjab. Many adherents of this religion do not cut their hair and wear turbans. ","answer":"ANSWER: Sikhism "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Kesh, uncut hair covered by a turban, is one of this many Ks of Sikhism, another of which is kirpan, a small dagger. This many men made up the Panj Pyare, the first group of people to be baptized into Sikhism. ","answer":"ANSWER: five "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Galois introduced his namesake theory to study the roots of these expressions. The zeroes of these expressions with degree two can be found using the quadratic formula. ","answer":"ANSWER: polynomials [or quadratic polynomials] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Galois laid the foundations for the “theory” of these structures that consist of a set of elements along with an operation on those elements. The set of integers together with addition constitutes one of these structures. ","answer":"ANSWER: groups [or group theory] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] This French mathematician declared Galois’ work on the theory of equations to be “incomprehensible.” In his namesake discrete probability distribution, the variance and expected value are equal. ","answer":"ANSWER: Siméon Denis Poisson [or Poisson distribution] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this genre of polyphonic sacred choral pieces exemplified by Josquin des Prez’s [“jo-SCAN de pray’s”] “Ave Maria … Virgo Serena.” Medieval era pieces in this genre were traditionally constructed as a discant over a cantus firmus. ","answer":"ANSWER: motets "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] This composer wrote a set of motets that include his pieces “Jesu, meine Freude” and “Der Geist hilft unser Schwachheit auf.” [“SCHVOCK-hite OFF”] This composer also wrote the St. Matthew’s Passion and the Goldberg Variations. ","answer":"ANSWER: Johann Sebastian Bach [prompt on Bach] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Bach’s other choral works include various pieces in this genre, such as one named for its key signature, B minor, and one written “for the Dresden court.” Pieces in this genre typically include a section titled “Kyrie” [KEER-ee-ay]. ","answer":"ANSWER: masses "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this state in which “butterfly ballots” and “hanging chads” caused widespread confusion during the 2000 presidential election. ","answer":"ANSWER: Florida "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Florida’s electoral votes were eventually awarded to this then-Governor of Texas, giving him the presidency over his democratic rival Al Gore. ","answer":"ANSWER: George Walker Bush [or George Bush, Jr.; prompt on partial answer; prompt on Dubya; do not accept or prompt on “George HW Bush” or “George Bush, Sr.”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Some blame Gore’s Florida loss on the scandal surrounding this Cuban boy, who was forcibly removed from Florida to be returned to his father’s custody in Cuba. ","answer":"ANSWER: Elián González [prompt on Elián] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this non-European country whose verse play The Chalk Circle inspired Brecht to write The Caucasian Chalk Circle. Another Brecht play set in this country is about a prostitute who cross-dresses as her fictional cousin to maintain a tobacco shop. ","answer":"ANSWER: China [the other Brecht play is The Good Woman of Szechuan] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Brecht’s Caucasian Chalk Circle takes place on a collective farm in this country. This country’s leader Joseph Stalin urged writers to think of themselves as “engineers of the human soul.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Soviet Union [or Union of Soviet Socialist Republics; prompt on Russia] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Brecht’s theory of “epic theatre” rejects this man’s belief that a tragic play should provoke catharsis in its audience. In his Poetics, this man argues that a play should take place over 24 hours in a confined location, a theory referred to as this philosopher’s “unities.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Aristotle [or Aristotelian unities] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this thing. It is the only noun in the title of a song by the same band with the lyrics “little darling / it’s been a long cold lonely winter.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the sun [also accept “Here Comes the Sun” or “Sun King”] [10] “Here Comes the Sun” and “Sun King” were performed by this British band, whose “Fab Four” consisted of Paul, George, John and Ringo. "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] This Beatles’ song describes a “limitless undying love that shines around me like a million suns.” Its chorus notes “nothing’s going to change my world,” and repeats the mantra “Jai Guru Deva.” ","answer":"ANSWER: “Across the Universe” "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this base SI unit for measuring length. It was initially standardized with a bar made of platinum and iridium. ","answer":"ANSWER: meter "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"6. Discovered by William Ramsay, this noble gas is often produced in the fission of uranium. ","answer":"ANSWER: krypton [or Kr] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] In 2002, the CIPM declared that the meter should only be used on small length scales due to this theory’s effects. This theory, developed by Einstein, describes how gravity arises due to spacetime curvature. ","answer":"ANSWER: general relativity [or GR; prompt on relativity; do not accept or prompt on “special relativity”] Tiebreaker. Semyon Dezhnev discovered this man’s namesake body of water eighty years before he did. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this Danish-born Russian navigator who led the Great Northern Expedition into Alaska. He also led to expeditions to explore Kamchatka. ","answer":"ANSWER: Vitus Bering "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Explorers for the Russian-American Company established Fort Ross in this modern U.S. state in 1812 to supply their Alaskan settlements with food. ","answer":"ANSWER: California "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] This Russian explorer was the first human to reach the final frontier: space. This cosmonaut left the atmosphere in the Vostok 1 capsule in 1961, kicking off the Space Race with the U.S. ","answer":"ANSWER: Yuri Gagarin EXTRAS Name these characters used in Java syntax, for 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] In Java, comments are indicated using two instances of this symbol. In HTML, closing tags contain this symbol along with one or more letters inside angle brackets. ","answer":"ANSWER: forward slash [or oblique; or virgule] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] This symbol, which is used to indicate “printf” [“print eff”] format specifiers in C, denotes the modulus operator in Java. ","answer":"ANSWER: percent sign "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] This symbol denotes the ternary operator in Java. In many C-like languages, it is used to declare nullable types. ","answer":"ANSWER: question mark One of this author’s novels begins with vultures entering the presidential palace. For 10 points each: "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Name this author of The Autumn of the Patriarch. Although his best-known novel, One Hundred Years of Solitude, is most closely associated with magical realism, he is also considered a part of the Latin American Boom. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gabriel García Márquez [prompt on partial surname] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] This Peruvian Boom author depicted a fictionalised Rafael Trujillo in his book The Feast of the Goat. He also wrote a radio play-filled novel about the relationship between Aunt Julia and the Scriptwriter. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mario Vargas Llosa [prompt on partial surname] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2018","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"P","question":"[10] Both The Autumn of the Patriarch and The Feast of the Goat belong to this genre of Latin American literature, in which the main antagonist is always a caudillo [caw-DEE-yo]. Other novels written in this genre include Facundo and Yo el supremo. ","answer":"ANSWER: the dictator novel [or la novela del dictador; prompt on partial answer]"}]
